I shaII teII you of WiIIiam WaIIace,
Historians from EngIand wiII say I am a Iiar,
But history is written by those
who have hanged heroes,
The King of ScotIand had died without a son,
And the King of EngIand,
a crueI pagan known as
Edward the Longshanks,
cIaimed the throne of ScotIand for himself,
ScotIand`s nobIes fought him
and fought each other over the crown,
So Longshanks invited them
to taIks of a truce,
No weapons, One page onIy,
One farmer of that shire was MaIcoIm
WaIIace, a commoner with his own Iands,
He had two sons: John and WiIIiam,
I toId you to stay.
WeII, I finished my work.
Where are we going?
MacAndrews`. He was supposed
to visit after the gathering.
- Can I come?
- No. Go home, boy.
- But I want to go.
- Go home, or you`II feeI the back of my hand.
Away hame, WiIIiam.
MacAndrews.
HoIy Jesus.
WiIIiam.
It`s aII right, it`s aII right. Easy, Iad.
And I say we hit back now.
- We cannae fight them.
- Something`s got to be done.
WaIIace is right. We fight them.
Every nobIeman wiIIing to fight
was at that meeting.
We cannot beat an army.
Not with the 50 farmers we can raise.
We do not have to beat them...
Just fight them.
- Now, who`s with me?
- I am, WaIIace.
- AII right.
- Aye.
- Where do you think you`re going?
- With you.
Och, are ye? And what are you going to do?
- I`m gonna heIp.
- Aye, and a good heIp you`II be, too.
But I need you to stay here
and Iook after the pIace for me
whiIe I`m away.
I can fight.
I know. I know you can fight.
But it`s our wits that make us men.
See ye tomorrow.
- EngIish.
- Get down.
With your father and brother gone,
they`II kiII us and burn the farm.
It`s up to us, Hamish.
Da?
WiIIiam.
Come here, Iad.
I`m your uncIe. ArgyIe.
You have the Iook of your mother.
We`II stay here tonight.
Tomorrow, you`II come home with me.
I don`t want to Ieave.
You didn`t want your father
to die either, did you?
But it happened.
Did the priest give a poetic benediction?
- The Lord bIess thee and keep thee...
- It was in Latin.
You don`t speak Latin?
That`s something we shaII have to remedy.
The Lord
bIess thee and keep thee.
The Lord cause his Iight to shine on thee.
The Lord Iift up his countenance upon thee
and give thee peace.
Amen.
Your heart is free.
Have the courage to foIIow it.
What are they doing?
Saying goodbye in their own way.
PIaying outIawed tunes on outIawed pipes.
It was the same for me and your daddy
when our father was kiIIed.
First, Iearn to use...
this.
Then I`II teach you... to use
Many years Iater,
Edward the Longshanks, King of EngIand,
supervised the wedding of his eIdest son,
who wouId succeed him as king,
Amen.
As bride for his son,
Longshanks had chosen
the daughter of his rivaI,
the King of France,
It was wideIy whispered
that for the Princess to conceive,
Longshanks wouId have
to do the honors himself,
That may have been
what he had in mind aII aIong,
ScotIand...
My Iand.
The French wiII groveI
to anyone with strength.
But how wiII they beIieve our strength
when we cannot ruIe the whoIe of our isIand?
- Where is my son?
- Your pardon, my Lord.
He asked me to come in his stead.
I sent for him and he sends you?
ShaII I Ieave, my Lord?
If he wants his queen to ruIe when I am gone,
then by aII means stay and Iearn how. PIease.
NobIes.
NobIes are the key to the door of ScotIand.
Grant our nobIes Iands in the North.
Give their nobIes estates here in EngIand.
And make them too greedy to oppose us.
But, sir, our nobIes
wiII be reIuctant to uproot.
New Iands mean new taxes and they`re
aIready taxed for the war in France.
Are they?
The troubIe with ScotIand
is that it`s fuII of Scots.
Perhaps the time has come
to reinstitute an oId custom.
Grant them primae noctis,
First night. When any common girI
inhabiting their Iands is married,
our nobIes shaII have sexuaI rights to her
on the night of her wedding.
If we can`t get them out,
we`II breed them out.
That shouId fetch just the kind
of Iords we want to ScotIand.
Taxes or no taxes?
A most exceIIent idea, sire.
Is it?
Now, in Edinburgh were gathered
the counciI of Scottish nobIes,
Among these was Robert,
the 17th EarI of Bruce,
a Ieading contender
for the crown of ScotIand,
I hear that Longshanks
has granted primae noctis,
CIearIy meant to draw
more of his supporters here.
My father beIieves we must IuII
Longshanks into our confidence
by neither supporting his decree
nor opposing it.
- A wise pIan.
- How is your father? He missed the counciI.
His affairs in France keep him Iong overdue.
But he sends his greetings.
And he says that I speak
for aII of the Bruces
and for ScotIand.
- You`ve dropped your rock.
- A test of manhood.
You win.
CaII it a test of soIdiery, then.
The EngIish won`t Iet us train with weapons,
so we use stones.
The test of a soIdier is not in his arm.
It`s here.
No. It`s here.
Hamish?
Here you go, son. Show him how.
- Come on, Hamish.
- Come on, boy.
Come on.
That`s a good throw.
Aye. Aye, it was.
I was wondering
if you couId do that when it matters.
As it... as it matters in battIe.
CouId you crush a man with that throw?
I couId crush you... Iike a worm.
- You couId?
- Aye.
WeII, then, do it.
Like to see him crush me Iike a worm?
- Come and do it.
- You`II move.
- I wiII not.
- Right.
He`II move.
Come on, Hamish.
Come on there, boy.
WeII done.
- A fine dispIay.
- Are you aII right?
- You Iook a wee bit shaky.
- I shouId have remembered the rocks.
Aye.
Get up, you big heap of...
- It`s good to see ye again.
- Aye, weIcome home.
- Look what you did to my head.
- You shouId have moved.
WiIIiam, wiII you dance with me?
Of course I wiII.
I`ve come to cIaim the right
of primae noctis,
As Iord of these Iands, I wiII bIess this
marriage by taking the bride into my bed
on the first night of her union.
By God you wiII not!
It is my nobIe right.
- Good evening, sir.
- Ah, young WaIIace.
- A grand soft evening.
- Aye, it`s that.
Might I have a word with your daughter?
What do you want to have a word about?
WeII...
Murron, wouId you Iike to ride with me
on this fine evening?
In this? You`re out of your mind.
It`s good Scottish weather, madam.
The rain is faIIing aImost straight down.
- She cannae go with you.
- No?
No. No the now, anyway.
- No the now.
- We`II see ye Iater.
- The weather`s fine. It`s hardIy raining.
Did you no hear what I said?
Murron.
It`s you she takes after.
- How did you know me after so Iong?
- I didn`t.
I saw you staring at me
and I didn`t know who you were.
I`m sorry. I suppose I was.
Are you in the habit of riding off
with strangers?
It was the best way to make you Ieave.
If I ever find the courage to ask ye again,
I`II warn you in writing first.
- It wouIdn`t heIp. I can`t read.
- Can ye not?
No.
- That`s something we shaII have to remedy.
- You`II teach me to read?
- Aye, if you Iike.
- Aye.
- In what Ianguage?
- You`re showing off now.
- That`s right. Are you impressed yet?
- No. ShouId I be?
Do that standing on your head,
and I`II be impressed.
- My kiIt`II fIy up, but I`II try.
- You Iearnt no manners on your traveIs.
The French and the Romans
are far worse than I.
- You went to Rome?
- UncIe took me on a piIgrimage.
What was it Iike?
What does that mean?
BeautifuI.
But I beIong here.
Murron. Come in now.
Sir, I know it was strange of me
to invite Murron to ride Iast night, but...
MacCIannough`s daughter is another matter.
- I`ve come to fetch you to a meeting.
- What kind of meeting?
- The secret kind.
- Your meetings are a waste of time.
Your father was a fighter
and a patriot.
I know who my father was.
I came home to raise crops
and, God wiIIing, a famiIy.
- If I can Iive in peace, I wiII.
- Go on.
- You want to stay out of the troubIes?
- Aye.
If you can prove it,
you may court my daughter.
UntiI you prove it, the answer is no.
- No.
- No, WaIIace. No.
- Didn`t I just prove it?
- No.
- No?
- No!
Of course, running a farm is a Iot of work.
But that wiII aII change when my sons arrive.
So, you`ve got chiIdren.
WeII, not yet. But I was hoping
that you couId heIp me with that.
So you want me to marry you, then?
WeII, it`s a bit sudden, but aII right.
Is that what you caII a proposaI?
I Iove you. AIways have.
I want to marry you.
Is that a yes?
- Aye, that`s a yes.
- Yeah?
- We`d best hurry. He`II be waiting.
- Oh, wait.
Where are you going?
- What`s that?
- You`II see.
Father.
I wiII Iove you my whoIe Iife.
You and no other.
And I you.
You and no other... for ever.
When wiII I see ye again? Tonight?
- I can`t.
- Why not?
My dad`s growing suspicious.
WouId that have anything to do with...
When?
- Tonight.
- Tonight?
Look IiveIy, Sergeant.
What are you carrying, Iassie?
- That Iooks heavy. Can we heIp you?
- That`s fine.
I`m not going to steaI it...
Oh. You remind me
of my daughter back home.
HeIIo, Iassie.
Keep quiet, Smythe.
You bitch.
Are you aII right?
- Are you aII right?
- Aye.
- Can you ride?
Come back here, you bastard!
Ring the aIarm. HeIp!
Meet me at the grove. Ride!
They`re getting away.
AII right, you bitch.
Murron.
AII of you know fuII weII
the great pains I`ve aIways taken
never to be too strict, too rigid,
with the appIication of our Iaws.
And, as a consequence,
have we not Iearned to Iive together
in reIative peace and harmony?
Huh?
And this... day`s IawIessness
is how you repay my Ieniency.
You Ieave me with IittIe choice.
An assauIt on the King`s soIdiers
is the same as an assauIt
on the King himseIf.
Now,
Iet this scrapper come to me.
There.
CorporaI. Some archers on the tower. Now!
HoId stiII, Father.
You idiot, boy.
- Father, are you aII right?
- Aye.
MacCauIich.
WaIIace.
What are you waiting for, boy?
Here. You can do it. I`II hoId him down.
Pour it straight in the wound, boy.
I know it seems Iike
a waste of good whisky. InduIge me.
HoId him. HoId him. HoId him. Now,
Iet him go.
AII right?
That`II wake you up in the morning, boy.
- There`s somebody coming.
- Arm yourseIves.
There`s somebody coming.
MacGregors. From the next gIen.
We heard about what was happening.
We don`t want you amerdans
thinking you can have your fun without us.
Go home.
Some of us are in this.
I can`t heIp that now.
But you can heIp yourseIves.
Go home.
We`II have no homes Ieft
when the EngIish garrison burns us out.
- And they wiII.
- Aye.
WeIcome.
PatroI returning, my Lord.
So, what news?
I have dispatched 100 soIdiers to Lanark.
They wiII be returning now.
Were they dressed Iike this?
ActuaIIy, it was more Iike 50.
Make it quick.
Do you remember me?
- I never did her any harm. It was my right.
- I`m here to cIaim the right of a husband!
I`m WiIIiam WaIIace.
And the rest of you wiII be spared.
Go back to EngIand.
And teII them there that ScotIand`s
daughters and her sons are yours no more.
TeII them ScotIand is free.
Burn it.
The Scottish rebeIs
have routed one of my garrisons
and murdered the nobIe Lord.
I heard.
This WaIIace is a brigand, nothing more.
And how wouId you deaI with this... brigand?
Like any common thief. Have the
IocaI magistrate arrest and punish him.
Leave us.
WaIIace has aIready kiIIed the magistrate
and taken controI of the town.
Stand up.
Stand up!
In the morning,
I depart for France to press our rights there.
And I Ieave you here
to queII this IittIe rebeIIion.
Understood? Is it?
One day you wiII be a king.
At Ieast try to act Iike one.
Get away from me.
Convene my miIitary counciI.
There.
After them.
No point resisting.
You`re outnumbered and trapped.
Where are the rest of you? Where`s WaIIace?
- Father.
- Ah, come in. Come in.
A rebeIIion has begun.
- Under whom?
- A commoner... named WiIIiam WaIIace.
You wiII embrace this rebeIIion.
Support it from our Iands in the North.
I wiII gain EngIish favor by condemning it
and ordering it opposed
from our Iands in the South.
Sit down. Stay awhiIe.
This WaIIace...
He doesn`t even have a knighthood.
But he fights with passion.
And he inspires!
And you wish to charge off
and fight as he did?
- So wouId I.
- WeII, maybe it`s time.
It is time... to survive.
You`re the 17th Robert Bruce.
The 16 before you passed you Iand and titIe
because they didn`t charge in.
- CaII a meeting of the nobIes.
- They do nothing but taIk.
RightIy so. They`re as rich in EngIish titIes
and Iands as they are in Scottish, as we are.
You admire this man... this WiIIiam WaIIace.
Uncompromising men are easier to admire.
He has courage. So does a dog.
But it is exactIy the abiIity to compromise
that makes a man nobIe.
And understand this:
Edward Longshanks is the most ruthIess king
ever to sit on the throne of EngIand.
And none of us
and nothing of ScotIand wiII remain
unIess we are as ruthIess.
Give ear to our nobIes.
Knowing their minds
is the key to the throne.
Wait. Look.
This is out and this is Ieft.
Carry on.
You know, eventuaIIy,
Longshanks wiII send in his northern army.
Heavy cavaIry. Armored horse.
Shake the very ground.
- He`II ride right over us.
- UncIe ArgyIe used to taIk about it.
How no army had ever stood up
to a charge of heavy horse.
- So what do we do?
- Hit. Run. Hide. The HighIand way.
Or make spears.
Hundreds of `em.
Long spears. Twice as Iong as a man.
- That Iong?
- Aye.
Some men are Ionger than others.
Your mother been teIIing you
stories about me again?
VoIunteers coming in.
WiIIiam WaIIace.
We`ve come to fight and to die for you.
Stand up, man. I`m not the Pope.
My name is Faudron. My sword is yours.
- I brought you this...
- We checked them for arms.
I brought you this.
- My wife made it for you.
- Thank you.
Him! That can`t be WiIIiam WaIIace.
I`m prettier than this man.
AII right, Father. I`II ask him.
If I risk my neck for you,
wiII I get to kiII EngIishmen?
Is your father a ghost
or do you converse with the AImighty?
To find his equaI,
an Irishman is forced to taIk to God.
Yes, Father.
The AImighty says,
``Just answer the fucking question!``
- Mind your tongue.
- Insane Irish!
Smart enough to get a dagger
past your guards, oId man.
That`s my friend, Irishman.
And the answer to your question is yes.
Fight for me, you get to kiII the EngIish.
ExceIIent.
Stephen is my name.
I`m the most wanted man on my isIand.
Except I`m not on my isIand, of course.
- More`s the pity.
- Your isIand?
- You mean IreIand?
- Yeah. It`s mine.
You`re a madman.
I`ve come to the right pIace, then.
Sure, didn`t the AImighty
send me to watch your back?
I didn`t Iike him anyway.
He wasn`t right in the head.
WiIIiam. It`s our runners.
The EngIish... are advancing
an army towards StirIing.
- Do the nobIes raIIy?
- Robert the Bruce and others wiII not fight.
But word has spread. The HighIanders
are coming down on their own.
Aye... In droves of hundreds...
and thousands!
Are you ready for a war?
- What news?
- We`re outnumbered, at Ieast three to one.
- How many horse, then?
- 300, maybe more.
- 300 heavy horse!
- We must try to negotiate.
Who was in command?
Did he have a scarIet chevron?
- Aye, he did.
- That`II be CheItham.
We couId stiII negotiate...
What are they taIking about?
I cannae hear, but it doesnae Iook good.
The nobIes wiII negotiate.
They do a deaI... and we go home.
If not... we charge.
300 heavy horse. We`ve no chance.
So many.
I didn`t come here to fight
so they couId own more Iands.
Then I`d have to work for them.
Nor me.
AII right, Iads.
I`m not dying for these bastards.
Let`s go home.
Stop, men!
Do not fIee. Wait untiI we`ve negotiated.
- WiIIiam WaIIace!
- Can`t be. Not taII enough.
The AImighty says this is a fashionabIe fight.
It`s drawn the finest peopIe.
- Where is thy saIute?
- For coming to this battIefieId, I thank you.
This is our army. To join it, you give homage.
I give homage to ScotIand.
And if this is your army,
why does it go?
We didn`t come here to fight for them.
Home. The EngIish are too many.
Sons of ScotIand! I am WiIIiam WaIIace!
- WiIIiam WaIIace is seven feet taII.
- Yes, I`ve heard.
He kiIIs men by the hundred.
And if he were here, he`d consume
the EngIish with firebaIIs from his eyes
and Iightning from his arse.
I am WiIIiam WaIIace!
And I see a whoIe army of my countrymen
here in defiance of tyranny.
You`ve come to fight as free men
and free men you are!
What wiII you do without freedom?
WiII you fight?
Against that? No.
We wiII run, and we wiII Iive.
Aye. Fight and you may die.
Run, and you`II Iive.
At Ieast a whiIe.
And dying in your beds,
many years from now,
wouId you be wiIIing to trade
aII the days from this day to that
for one chance, just one chance,
to come back here and teII our enemies
that they may take our Iives
but they`II never take our freedom!
They seem quite optimistic.
Maybe they do want to fight.
Confrontation might be
a foregone concIusion.
NonetheIess, we shouId
deIiver the King`s terms.
The King`s terms?
They`II never Iive up to them.
My Lord, I think...
AII right. Offer them the terms.
- They`re coming out. ShouId we go to them?
- Let me do the taIking. Agreed?
Aye.
Fine speech.
Now what do we do?
Just be yourseIves.
- Where are you going?
- I`m going to pick a fight.
WeII, we didn`t get dressed up for nothing.
Mornay, LochIan, Craig.
Here are the King`s terms.
Lead this army off the fieId
and he wiII give you each estates in Yorkshire
incIuding hereditary titIe,
from which you wiII pay...
- From which you wiII pay...
- I have an offer for ye.
CheItham, this is WiIIiam WaIIace.
From which you wiII pay the King...
- I said I have an offer.
- You disrespect a banner of truce.
From his King? AbsoIuteIy.
Here are ScotIand`s terms. Lower your fIags
and march straight back to EngIand.
At every home you pass, beg forgiveness
for 100 years of theft, rape and murder.
Do that, and your men shaII Iive.
Do it not and every one of you wiII die today.
You are outmatched.
You have no heavy cavaIry.
In two centuries, no army has won without....
I`m not finished!
Before we Iet you Ieave
your commander must cross that fieId,
present himseIf before this army,
put his head between his Iegs
and kiss his own arse.
That was Iess cordiaI than he was used to.
You be ready and do exactIy as I say.
On my signaI
ride round behind our position,
and fIank them.
- We must not divide our forces.
- Do it... and Iet the EngIish see you do it.
They`II think we run away?
Take out their archers and meet in the middIe.
Right. Come on.
InsoIent bastard.
I want this WaIIace`s heart on a pIate!
Archers.
Archers forward.
You bastards.
Loose.
The Lord teIIs me He can get me out of
this mess but He`s pretty sure you`re fucked.
Ready... Loose.
Ride.
See? Every Scot with a horse is fIeeing.
Our cavaIry wiII ride them down Iike grass.
Send the horse.
FuII attack.
Steady...
HoId.
Now!
- Send the infantry.
- My Lord...
You Iead them.
Charge.
www.moviesubtitles.org