Speed is very important when you're driving
but it must be control accurately
With courage and driving
skill don't you know
Look I've taken my hands off
but keep on proper balance
eyes looking forward
backward and to both sides
keep watching all around you
Maddie I bet on you
beat that rich guy for me
What time did you fix with him
At 12 he's late what's on
Maybe that guy is too scared to come
Damn you You're late
why don't you come next year
No one ever dare to reprimand me right
Yes
ok boss let me handle
I recognize you maddie I remember
You're brother of that dare devil
the prisoner
don't bullshit
who are you
I'm fat c what's your name
Why only tell me now
You don't have to ask me I'm tse
don't bullshit we'll know
who the winner is after the race
like boss like dog
he is a real flatter
sure his head is big enough to bullshit
and not like you you are so weak
your boss give you dog feed
to keep you so fat
Are you ready We bet on
$300 thousand tonight
damn get lost $300 thousand
Let's bet on $1 million full
you boast $1 million
If I had $1 million I don't
need to race with you
right you don't have to but I do
you get the money if you win
but if I win I want no money
what do you want then
You're strong enough
I want it
You're afraid
Don't be afraid
let's go
I can't help if you must make me win
paddy
where's my motorbike
The real chariot of fire
it's superb  give me
Be careful
Boss says he'll be happy
if you perform well
Thanks
he'll give some to each of you
call us if there's such benefit next time
well to him money is not an object
but I'm the only flatter around him
if you like come here more often
and do some help or root us
yes promise thanks
Dee is big head ready
Get into position
be a good narrator
just like the good car race narrator on TV
ok
Sure will be like live show
paddy
is it ok
Just perfect
really
Give way The boss has come
Boss
is it ok
My boss is mighty
I won't let my boss down
Ready start
Sky
Dee it has started
remember report if anything happens
Roger
Really like flying
They've arrived gas station
of clear water bay road
if sky did not fooling
He'd have lead by quite a distance
I'll hand to the next stand
Now they're racing on
it's really interesting
the road becomes their racing track
defeat him Sky
What are you looking little girl
I have bet on so I must know the result
it's only a small amount
They're entering junk bay tunnel
sky and maddie are both trying
to surpass the other
I wonder how many times
they have changed gear
look
They overtake the cars on the road swiftly
pretty fast
It's a Porsche it's really fast nuts
The Porsche is ahead of sky now
Sky really smashes its windscreen
He deserves capsizing
Out the tunnel now sky changes to 3rd gear
maddie is following far behind
and can't see sky's car
he'll surpass me soon
Sky defeat maddie
Who are you
what
What did you say
Shit You lunatic
Boss are you alright
Sky I'm afraid you can't defeat him
boss is smart
Boss is the winner
Ok $1 million give me 2 month time
I have money
We agree to side bet on your leg
don't be too much
it's our agreement and
stake don't you know
Since you agree you must keep your words
boss
don't be so much
no if we must play we
must play till the end
you can't step on the
accelerator from now on
spanner
Here
where's paddy
Sky  knock on him
why Let's break his leg
sky
Don't you know how to
You can't knock his leg
but can repair cars
It's like this to break his leg
Boss
We must keep the promise
of what we have said
boss let's go
You're on my bed what are you going to do
The warden knows I love sleeping
she won't suspect
thanks for helping me again
do you see sky He won or lost
Of course sky is the winner
that maddie dare tell
others he's the dare devil
how far away did he win Tell me
it's a motorbike race
it only takes 3 seconds to reach 100 kPH
What then Tell me
when I arrived
I saw sky on that motorbike
he's so cool
Only that motorbike can match sky
do you know how powerful
that motorbike 1s
Don't know
do you know what means by double speed
No idea  and quadrate speed
What is it Tell me
let me take you to meet my dream lover
great
Does your dream lover have big eyes
And how tall is he Tell us
what does he look like
Is he handsome Tell us
why don't you say
Paddy
thanks
I say sky is a bit too much on that
too much of what
I mean his side bet with
maddie would be a leg
it's too much to break the opponent's leg
but they mutually agreed
this world talks of money
I have to go you stay
here and fool with him
paddy don't go
the boss hasn't let you leave yet
he'll deduce your salary
look
I'm happy today
your tips
why The price for having sex with you
I was only joking
don't you remember what day is today
What day
I was injured 6 years ago
hurrah
I can drive faster still
Why I never see your parents
She hasn't come look at this card
recover soon mom
I know it's written by others
never mind I'll be with you always
Ok
Come on quick
come on
turn your face first
ok
Sky your mom has just called up
saying that she'll pick you up
for dinner after the meeting
dinner will start at 7 sharp
as she has another meeting at 8
forget the dinner
Ask her to stick to the meetings
that policeman will not charge you
for careless driving
as your mom has settled the case
sure the kid shouldn't have
rushed out to the road
his parents should teach
him road safety instead
that kid
Died last night
I've forgotten all the unhappy incidents
What will you send me next year
Next year
I don't want
no
Let's see next year
I don't want
You don't want
You know what I love the most
cars and you
Hello You've come home
How's granny
I have medical appointment at
Princess Mary hospital tomorrow
don't go there go to a private hospital
it's chronic disease for elderly people
I know I'll pay the bill ok
Sleep early
I love the bracelet you sent me
do you Put it on then
good night bye
I know
the national bureau is strict
on foreign investment
but if you are able to help me
everything should be fine
ok
You mom has just signed an agreement
with a Chinese group
if we make it I'll buy you a car
uncle Sam's Ferrari 360
Is laid off
as his driver license got suspended
I'll buy it for you
it's a limited edition only 30 worldwide
none of my business I
don't want any used car
I know you don't want an used car
ok let me order a brand new one for you
does my mom know
No problem
Don't look back if you do
it means you'll come here again
I've been here 5 years
I'm beginning to like it here
you are really something
others come here for a penalty
but you studied and get
several degrees in here
so hk government is nice
to bastards like you
this is for you
read more but not the comics
or you'll spend the rest of your life here
like the prisoners
Brother fung
Brother
Why you had an accident
Don't tell others you're my blood brother
not an accident he lost a race
and the opponent broke it
it's that dude sky
that guy even says tang fung is outdated
that he gets too clumsy for car racing
look how cocky he is
He also advises you to retire
Mind your saliva spoiling my engine
this is lubricant
it'll speed up the car instead
come and listen to the
sound of the accelerator
step on the accelerator
Ok master
classics
It sounds beautifully
it's enough take it
pentium il 400 300mhz
thank youl
Throw away your outdated computer now
can you manage
Yes
I'll see this is heart
ok
Healthy boss
this is kidney is it ok boss
No problem
boss you're healthy
you hire two competent staffs here
paddy is expert of checking engines
and I am expert of checking your health
boss this is the sex organ is it ok
Is it ok boss
Boss  are you no more joking
Sky don't be like this
come on
boss is healthy and has
a powerful sex organ
hit my stick hard
boss is great
Boss have some water
You left hospital so soon
You can walk You take your uncle with you
He is my brother tang fung
you're sky
Not a good guy
you side bet on his leg
Let's clear things up
it's mutual agreement
right tang fung
You were apprentice at 14
and started racing in 1982
in 1983 no one could
follow you by 2 minutes
from Princess road to clear water bay
the fastest time is 15 minutes 28 seconds
you might finish university
if you studied as hard
then your mom would be happy
I'm better than you
you Rose to top in 1988
but you were too greedy
you conspired with robbers and were
sent to jail after being released
you commit a crime again
I wonder if you like jail life
kid
I know you take me as
idol like many others do
sorry I don't admire you
I just read it take it as a souvenir
dare devil returns to the race track
and bringing about new struggle
you're son of black tone
Dad quick
You know how your dad got defeated by me
You're much inferior than him indeed
you think you're superior
just because you're rich
you think you can become
The best car racer with your money
but you won't succeed as you
never improve yourself
want to challenge me
I come to teach you something
cylinder head change the gasket 16mm
decrease the compression ratio
turbo Mark up to 15 bar
also need turbo exhaust
manifold 70mm front pipe
and titanium metal exhausted
air tube at the rear
oilsuspension cooler and shock absorbers
and use 14k spring
fix sti power lock and clutch
also install mines racing computer
then it can be called a car
quote me the price
this only provides 300 HP at the maximum
so be sure you can control it
sorry we never modify Subaru
you won't or you dare not
I don't want to but I
want to race with you
I like this how to
We can bet on whatever the stake is
I don't want money I want
a garage to mod Subaru
this is not a bad one
uncle you get nuts in jail
Boss's garage is worth $3 million
And your stake
My hand if you want both my hands
don't you like side bet on other's limbs
Ok Friday night
at 9:30 pm at kwun tong pier
see you
Boss have tea
don't let saliva come down like him
Your saliva
mind your saliva
can you
Go go on
no drink is allowed here
none of your business
I don't mean you
sir don't you hear
I'm not thirsty now
What's wrong with you
What do you up to
What're you going to do
Take this and clean your head
the clothes are dirty
they need cleaning too
they scared the customers
ask them to leave
it's fine then go ahead
don't you know you follow me
I'm playing with it you cut the line
I really didn't mean to
what's happened
This bitch
wants to cut the line when I'm playing
you say sorry
what is it
Nothing I'm playing with it
and she said I cut the line
you hold her tight She's your girlfriend
Kid what girl Are you of age
I can kill you
Take it easy don't stir up trouble
Do you know who he is
He's brother sky dare devil
Hurrah brother sky
Dare devil You know who I am
Who are you
I'm god of car in this game centre
they call me sugihara takuumi
brother takuumi
It's brother takuumip
a Japanese
What's that got to do with you
You know who we are
I'm called big head
I'm called Dee
big head Dee without us
there won't be you takuuim
I'll take you as of age let's race
sure
don't bullshit let's race now
you are very lucky today
brother sky is racing with you no problem
brother sky will surely win
you must lick my toes if you lose
lick the toes
Shit he's better than me
Why What's wrong with you
Young man calm down take it easy
I want to ask why the power
was suddenly cut off
we've just taken the lead
you boast What shall we do now
What shall we do
It's your place here
and you are god of car you suggest
nuts
We're taking the lead
brother what are you doing
I'm helping your idol
ok forget it It's a tie
Ok when you grow up
I'll race with you on Princess road
get lost
come for brother sky when you grow up
Beat it if you are afraid
brother sky
you have released
Don't let them send you there anymore
don't bother with him
I'll give you a cheque
for the debts I owe you
ok thanks
don't you want to play
with the dancing machine
Yes
where's the dancing machine
Over there boss
go with boss
it's always leaves without saying too cool
forget it don't think astray
you go to play on
This one is good
You must keep to the beat
you're bad why didn't you help me
I did tell you to follow the beat
Brother I'm back
breakfast
Wipe the sweat
I'm tired
last night after leaving the game centre
and where did you go
Brother sky ignored me
so I went to disco
for a dance
I like dancing too
sorry
you helped me out last time
but were sent to girls' home
brother why you say that
I can choose boyfriends
but I can't choose a brother
it's destined don't say such a thing
I'll kill whoever dare say
you're mentally retarded
will you
Then you'll be sent
to girls' home again
You always fight for me
all we can blame on is our dead parents
They passed away when I was young
brother why are you so miserable
I did finish high school
but have you thought of
Going back to school
No way
you know what good
Your school did to you
It let you meet brother sky
you must be nuts
you're underage and you want to woo sky
What do you mean My voice
has changed already
right a coarse voice indeed
why can't I love him
I've thought over I
won't go back to school
but I'll become an
apprentice in your garage
like big head and Dee
I want to learn how to repair cars
will sky employ you
Help me to persuade him
come on help me to persuade him
ask him for me I'll buy you Teddy bear
ask him for me I don't need salary
don't bother me
Please
Go away
paddy 20kg in front
and 10kg at the rear increase by 2 bars
and increase it to 460 HP
but it's been already
fixed with 4 brakes set
it's getting out of control now
the most I can do is to
increase it by 15 bars
but the car will be controlling you
I can always control cars
tell me you can't or you won't
We've known for ages
and I've never turned you down
please dissuade him for me
forget our friendship
I'm boss you will or won't modify it
I ask you will you modify it
Sky
What's it
Stay out it's men's topic get upstairs
get upstairs
will you modify it
Will you
I ask you modify it or not
Ok I'll modify it for you
Will you modify it
1 will
trust me I can control it
ok I'll modify it
We're partners we must trust each other
come on
Where is sky
He left
all left
They left long ago
I should have taken a taxi here
who sat next to him
His girlfriend Kelly you know her
You want to take that seat
If I hadn't arrived late
it must have been me
brother
What's happened
It's vital
the race today is the race of the century
tang fung vs sky
the track is from kwun
tong to lung cheung road
then up castle road to texaco road junction
then uturn and back to the starting point
whoever reaches there first is the winner
Don't lose
Kelly
sky help
it hurts My legs are stuck
Don't sit on go and help
A race never wins unless
he reaches the finale
I'll rush to the finale now
I'll pay you $1 million ok
Money is not all mighty
do me a favour help me please
I've never begged others please help me
You must come out
help me sky
Kelly
sky
No alcohol taken normal
he's racing with tang fung
of course he didn't drink
all who take part in such
underground races will end up dying
is she out
She's dead being under the battered car
sir there's a tipoff
I want you to come back
to the station with us
besides of charging you
with careless driving
We'll charge you with possessing narcotics
Take off shoes put them over there
Kc it's not a serious case indeed
my son is only involved in an accident
why no bail is allowed
Tony call eddy hui their commissionaire
yes
Mrs yu we found 500mg of heroin
in your son's car
what
My son never tabs drugs
I don't know
no way
I must call up Elsie leung as well
I'm sure someone wants to frame youl
$1 million and side bet on limbs
You want that now
No Help
Bastard
Sign here
Sky
how come
I'm ok
did they beat you up
Call for ambulance quick
let's go home first
Martin Mark down the time and location
I must sue all cops here
I ask you
aren't you policeman to
protect the citizens
None of our business
people in the custody beat him
let's go home
miss what's up What do you want
Sky never touches
narcotics someone must
Leave my sister alone What do you want
Stop
Watch your attitude What is your number
Shut up Stop fooling ok
Let's all go home first
none of his business
I'll take responsibility
No don't let them frame you
Sky come home with me
Tell them you never possess narcotics
Sky tell them you're innocent
Paddy need the medication
again take it to him
Sky
Sky it hurts
Help me
Elsie I only have one son
so please do me a favour
yes I know
but it may be interfering
with justice right
Maybe it will and maybe not
we used to be school mates
please help this time
give me a hand please
ok I'll call you back later
I know you are under pressure
but there's a former case
anyway I have good relation with Mr tung
ok wait for your good news
what did he say
It's in vain no need to call again
Sky
your mom has made all efforts already
and it should be fine now
I'm the one who commit a crime
don't worry I won't get you involved
shut up
It's not your affairs only
we're both involved now
if you were not my son
I wouldn't care a dime
look at yourself
I tell you don't ever drive a car
I don't want you to die like your dad
My dad
How did he die
I remember you quarreled with him
and you told me he disappeared
soon you took me to his tomb
you told me he was under there
and wouldn't get up again
is he really dead Is he
I take him as if he were dead
You take him as if he were dead
He's alive
You cheat me Where is he
Where is he
I don't know
Tony arrange for him to leave hk
I won't go unless I make it clear
your mom is right
you'd better leave hk for the moment
you want me to disappear
I'll vanish this minute
I won't ever come back
stand still
Stand there
Look at him
I do have a secret even
your mom doesn't know it
I take your dad as idol
black tone
Is my father
Black tone is the real dare devil
the century race between him and tang fung
was breathtaking
and there is never such a race anymore
every time when black tone won a race
He would give us a ride
we each gave him $5000
riding in his car from Princess road
to clear water bay
was rare experience
you would never forget that experience
I don't know whether
it's out of excitement or fear
we wet our pants
go and find your dad in Thailand
is he in Thailand
Someone saw him in Thailand years ago
but don't know where exactly he is
Granny
sky
Kelly used to say she'd take you to see me
but she is dead now
and we finally meet each other
don't be sad
I'm really sad
but I don't have anymore tears
she arrived from Taiwan 10 years ago
And lived with me since then
and you're her only friend
look it's quiet here
She died in loneliness too
Granny
Take this
there's something that is priceless
there's something we
cannot judge with money
Go away You needn't help me up
Check which club possesses the best girls
aren't we here to locate sky
Sky
Bangkok is so big it's
not easy to find him
go and check got it
Yes
One day how much
B220 one day
ten days
Uncle  have you arrived
How is everybody
We're in trouble as your mom is
charging by the Attorney General
it's troublesome this time
sorry
you must use a false name where'er you go
cops are smart nowaday
be careful for everything
I have enough money with me
I'll turn off my mobile phone
so cops can't detect my location
don't make a call even if it's necessary
uncle and your mom are
eased as you've grown up
don't worry uncle I will find my father
ok the line is impaired
I must hang up now
bye
Sky where are you
Police are looking for you everywhere
tell me and I'll fly to see you
no I'm fine
I'll contact you later
sky
brother sky where are you
Brother and I will come to join you
no Nancy
remember to listen to your brother
and behave yourself
I will
brother sky don't lose heart
we both back you up
Brother try this pork
you speak cantonese
I'm cantonese
right have you seen this guy
No sorry
Help
Thief
What is it
You're competent
you have money to flee to Thailand
All your money has been robbed
shall I give you $1
million to go back to hk
We did settle up our affairs in hk already
damn you Beat him
Catch him
You broke my leg
Syringe affected with aids
let me give you injection
and you'll have HIV
you want to revenge
Get in the car I come
to help you get in
Most guys fleeing here from hk come for me
so everyone here calls me king of fleers
I don't mean I must flee
and those who flee here
call me king of fleers
you say you're so powerful
then can you find those robbers
and get back my money for me
What if I can
Report to the police
Remember you are a culprit
and you have lots of rivals in hk
I want to see a doctor lend me some money
you have valuable belongings
I'll take it to pawn shop
I have no money but I'm rich in hk
lend me and I'll remit it to you
you know why everyone who
flees to Thailand first
The living standard is low in Thailand
a little money lets you live like king
I don't intend to spend my life here
what do you want then
I want to find this man
isn't he black tone
You know him
When he first came to Thailand
everyone in hk thought he was dead
he's still alive
He's so horny he won't die young
where is he now
He is my father
I haven't seen him for 10 years now
he's not in Bangkok
he may be in chingmai or in pattaya
you're really son of black tone
Yes
here's some money
it's sad on the flee do take care
Eat now
thanks
half cooked rice again
It's a month now
why don't you cooked the rice well
I've asked you a whole month already
tell me where sky is
If you want cooked rice
I do want to say but sky
won't let me tell you
he's not on a trip he's on flee
can't we find him though he's fleeing
You don't talk reason
paddy
Nancy
Uncooked rice Throw it
I've bought you good food
thanks
come Sushi come let's eat it
you want to play a fool
What fool
Stay calm you both stay calm
want to enter the girls' home again
Ask him don't be so cocky
he beat you brother
It's alright
sorry  you fix him
calm down
paddy my new boss tang fung
he likes your skills
he wants you to modify cars for him
then we can work together again
that garage belongs to sky
I always tell you: Money is our boss
and when sky returns to hk
you can go back to him
damn you
Play a trick
Stop fighting
Beat my brother
Stop
Brother
Stop fighting
Stop calm down listen to me
we are always like this
you play like this
It's ok we're always like this
don't think you're special
if not brother fung wants you
we won't come here
what do you want
Take it easy boss
tell tang fung
I must revenge for sky and Kelly
tell me remember You asshole
Beat it
Brother
I'm useless
I got a cramp when I yelled at them
brother you behaved very bravely
you're the best mechanic of modifying cars
let me cook you some tender rice
sky asked me to tell you
to behave yourself
Sky
I must modify it into
the fastest car for you
Paddy I've left Bangkok now on a bus
heading south
I can't leave you any phone number
how about them
That tse is asshole
He's real bastard a real asshole
What's on
Don't mention him anymore
I've run a small garage
In yuen long
I'm now modifying the
fastest car for you
come back and try it
wait till I come back
please take care of Kelly's
grandmother for me
I will
should be
you gave me all that money
to run my own garage
it's your money not mine
I want to ask uncle
It's said they're in Canada
and police are watching them closely
remember inform me if you have address
I don't know where I am at present
Have you seen this guy
No
You're from hk
Yes
he's from hk too have you seen him
Is he I haven't seen him before
sky
I want a haircut
you're from hk
Your hair is long sure you need a haircut
don't move
Are you black tone
You're black tone
no I'm not
Black tone  I'm not
You're black tone
Stand there and don't move
you're took me for someone else
Black tone
why did you cut my son's hair like this
Dad
I'm sky
I've been looking for you
mom has been cheating me
Saying you're dead
So many has happened to you
Then uncle asked me to find you here
Tony
He's a real nice guy
your mom is lucky to have him
since tang fung's incident
I've brought them much trouble
tang fung that tang fung again
Do you have rivals with him
Don't say it anymore
Black tone is dead don't
mention the past again
don't keep saying you're dead
why do you bring me here
Waiting for someone
pal
this woman is my honey
you needn't call her mother
this kid is my son he's called blackie
honey
Honey
My son
Honey this is my son no
He's my friend
how are you
Have you greeted
How are you
Honey watch out it's hot
it smells good
Honey I'm happy
be careful
it's tasty
It's just like you
watch out
it's hot
my honey makes the perfect hot soup
it's really hot and spicy
this hot soup is really hot
honey come on sit down
Son you keep watching TV all day
and you smile whenever I talk to you
and you never remember the
cantonese I teach you
you're half Chinese you know
Honey you want to smile too
You want it day and night don't you
Son you like these dishes
Yes
it's habit in Thailand
same dishes for lunch and dinner
it's not as varied as in hk
see how much I earn today
look
what are you doing
Nothing I want to see
how much I earn today
not much about 100 baht
my honey I think it's about 200 baht
so little
It's enough for the 3 of us
300 baht a day it's hk$3000 a month
it's enough it's not hk here
when in hk the money I spent one night
Is enough for few year expenses here
the money I spent on modifying cars
is enough for my whole life here
you know your mom is rich right
Your mom always buys you cars
and each costs $1 million right
You needn't go to work today
How to make a living
There aren't many kids
in pattaya that need haircut
so you ask her to work
and make money for you
That's why I married her
I'm a pimp right
Why are you like this
How come
Nothing here is ok
look
I know it was so noisy last night
that I couldn't sleep
of course it was noisy
Are you impotent
Of course not
of course I can it's not the same son
this is
I teach you because you're my son
I didn't steal it
You are telling lies
What is it Take it easy
she stole my watch while I was sleeping
I didn't
Man my wife says she
didn't steal your watch
I'll have her arrested
if she doesn't return my watch to me
yes
do you know who's most furious in pattaya
Give me back my watch
You must give me back the watch
Man give me 2 days' time
ok I'll give you 2 days
come to see me at thai boxing gym in 2 days
don't move
Let's go
Dad
Do you find me useless
I just don't understand
uncle said you were famous
in Princess road racing
I am so proud of it
because that black tone is my father
that black tone is dead
he's alive he's sitting in front of me
but he became another person
yes I'm another person now
I'm called black tong now
you're still young you can start again
but you never fight back
when others bully you
right because I'm disabled now
so I left hk
and gave the title of
dare devil to tang fung
tang fung and I had 2
races on Princess road
and he wasn't up to me
so they all called me dare devil
I'm the underground champion of car racing
tang fung sent his men to give me money
they took me to Macau and fevered
And that's why your mother left me
once I lost $5 million in casino Lisboa
and this bastard tang fung challenged me
saying if I won he would
pay off debts for me
and if I lost he would break
my left arm and right leg
so this is it
have you figured out why you lost
I didn't figure out why I lost
I used to be snooty
I spent money whatever I liked
I stressed on car modification
and not driving skills
my friend paddy advised me not
to make ample modification
but I didn't listen
he says ample modification makes
the car control me
but I ignore his advice so
Right
do you want to revenge for me
Though I'm disabled I can
become your instructor
how is it
I'm up there too come on
but you
You're in the car you must calculate
Using 3rd gear then down to 2nd gear
to turn this turnoff
pull and pass
Son remember that moustache
If you defeat him
they'll forgive my honey's
stealing the rolex
who is this guy
This is the dare devil in Thailand
he was 3 time champion in Thailand
he represents Thailand going on
formulae race as well
he's ranked 48 worldwide
I must lose then you want me to die
Of course not
it was all the past
he belonged to the 80s like I did
you know you and I are 2 generation
Of the dare devil
so you won't lose
Come on driving such a car
Yeah so you must use your skills
Ranked 487
I really didn't steal the watch
son my honey said she
didn't steal the watch
whether she did or not I must race
but I never thought I would race
for the sake of a rolex
have you thought of how to defeat the 48th
Yes to drive faster than him
How to drive faster than him
Then teach me you're my instructor
Without brake and you'll be fast
don't let the speedometer threatens you
you said it we must overcome our fear
so you must prove it yourself
racing requires a good car
but good skills as well
son you can make it
take this 10 bucks
my face is on it
it's a lucky money
remember like this
honey let's go
It's dangerous for him
yes but I can't help
only this can help him overcome his fear
his fear you understand
I know but he's your son
if anything happens
Right he's my son on the track
even if he dies I still have another son
if you like we can have
more children right
You smile I need it whenever you smile
Don't let the speedometer scare you
if you want speed
you must prove yourself
to overcome the fear
What's it
Sorry I've found my watch
man why didn't you tell me earlier
what
Nothing he said he'd found his watch
get me wine I must drink with them
let's cheers
Cheers
Let's cheers
I'm black tong
you're black tong I want
black tone from hk
You bastard
dad come back to hk with me
What
Dad
no just like today
go back and race on Princess road
I won't
No sit still man
You must care for your health
I can't help the garage is
just opened for business
I must get more business
look at you you cough hard
brother let's go
take the medicine too why so hurry
Where are you going
Where's brother sky Not return yet
I don't know you well
you want both legs broken this time
Nancy maddie does care about sky
just like me I care about my exboss too
you make him flee you care about him
Assholel
don't beat my brother
I wonder why sky employ you
you stammerring guy
boss don't be mad
I know you're expert at modifying cars
how about your driving skill
My race with sky didn't finish yet
As he fell off flyover
and never reached the finale
I don't take it as a victory
brother he's daring you
I never race with stupid guys
but I respect you as you're sky's man
if you want to defeat me to revenge for him
I'll have a race with you any time
boss we have to go to dinner come on
my brother is proved to have HIV positive
if you don't want I'll
wait till sky comes back
I must have a race to
revenge for my brother
I promise you
brother no they're daring you only
I promise youl
I want to test your judgment
your guts and your skills
you rush forward till you
reach the end of the pier
and brake hard see if you can do it
Son stop the car
Stop It's danger
I didn't ask you to drive into the sea
get down
Tone a girl comes to see your son
brother sky
This is my first flight ever
I know nothing I don't
speak english or thai
but I come here with the address
you gave me last time
I want to ask you why are you here
Where's your brother
Brother promised to race with tang fung
but the stake is life
why must your brother race with tang fung
Why must you push me away from you
Can I hold you for longer time
But I'm all wet
I don't mind
Try and dissuade my brother
to go for the race
say it slowly
why must your brother race with tang fung
Your new girlfriend You lucky guy
no nuts
she's sister of my buddy
sister of your buddy
I think she's not mature yet
she must have something to come
all the way here for you ight
No
You still miss the girl who died
But she's already dead right
Don't think about her anymore
Sky
Want to know why I call you sky
and not brother sky
You're still a little
girl don't think astray
You still take me as a little girl
Brother sky
what is it
I want to tell you something
after midnight tonight will be my birthday
I'm 18 then
I won't fight anymore
as I'm over age for girls' home
if I commit anything I'll be sent to jail
ok it's good for you
to think of your future
so please don't take me
as a little girl again
Come to see the moon
Sorry did I wake you up
You are misunderstanding
we're not making love we're
Doing thal massage my honey is a masseuse
it's painful yet comfortable
little girl come here
my honey is expert want to try
No Honey let's go on
take your time we'll go
Sister buy flowers
it's your birthday
Yes
no these are
So old fashioned
want them or not
You really don't want to go back to hk
I'm called black tong
and here is my paradise
hk no longer belongs to me
I've thought it over
if it is not for my buddy paddy
I won't go back to hk
I want to get marry here and live here
I want to count the money
which I make everyday
control your car accurately is important
while you're driving
you must learn to use brake
as you failed to use brake
so you drove into the sea
sometimes it's right
sometimes you must use brake
sometimes the accelerator
some racers don't care about dying
but I'm old
I'm disabled I should retire now
but you are young you still
have a long way to go
so you must accelerate
son return to hk and create your own world
you'll make it
thanks dad
no thanks I've never been a good father
bye brother
Bye black tone
Remember
Remember what I've taught you
Damn it
Brother
defeat him for me
Again
Paddy
forget it let's wait
till sky comes back here
paddy you're my buddy
I don't want anything happen to you
buddy
If sky returns the first he'll do is
To settle up with you
Kid brother fung wants a
special treat dare you
Idiot
you dare not
Mechanic
No don't go mad like him
you can back out this minute
Brother
brother
Nancy I've decided to race with tang fung
as I must get back my ego
I don't want others to look down on me
it's good idea you become apprentice
but you must go to school
it's not bad for you to love sky
but wait till you grow up
be good brother paddy
Big head where's my brother
That bastard tang fung
insisted on racing last night
and required special treat
but paddy's car capsized
he got trapped in the car
come we're at the mortuary
where's my brother
Brother
Why come here You traitor go away
Go away traitor
Sorry
Did ask paddy to back out
go away he doesn't want to see you
I never expected he'd die
I really didn't know this would happen
go and explain to him go
Paddy
Sorry
I asked you to back out
I really don't know this
I don't want to lose a friend
Get an appointment with tang fung go
Take my condolence don't cry
I'm not crying
My brother left this but
I can't open help me
It's like a note of maths
Let me see
no it's notes of how to modify cars
paddy's theory of modifying cars
with this note
You have confidence
No problem
sure
I et's not waste his efforts
Brother I know you'll help us
you must bless brother
sky to defeat tang fung
Sky the car is in excellent condition
Hey does brother's note help
Ok
The spart parts are not enough
we miss some gears and aixles too
what is it
We miss some spare parts
the computer is not the
type which mechanic said
the 4 spring are impaired
too this won't work
don't bullshit let me steal one back
what have I said
What is it
Here is a carton what is inside
That's the gears and aixles we need
all brand new
you ordered them
Even the computer is new
does Santa claus send them to us
Don't bullshit
I won't accept things from that bastard
Come out
I hope this Christmas present will help
you stole them
I stole from you
you know you used to spend like king
You bought numerous spare parts
so me and paddy built a secret drawer
and hide these spare parts
wanting to sell them for cash
now you need them
of course I must give them back to you
I won't let that tang fung have them
Move them in no need to say thank you
Come in Santa claus
help modify the car
Boss you're tired
Leg massage
This part talks about nitrogen speeding
as nitrogen is 3 times more
powerful than gasoline
so nitrogen can increase
the explosive power
yet the time must not exceed 10 seconds
remember you control the car
turbo inter cooler
full time 4wheel drive
this is a super car ever modified
it suits you most
whatever how stupid the opponent is
I must race with all I might have to face
It's on fire
Take it away it's nitrogen it'll explode
Use fire extinguisher
Is it alright
It's the last can
sorry
racing wheel suspending shock absorbers
ap break disk titanium
alloy exhausted pipe
isn't it a bit too much
Do you know the dividend on you
It's 10 times
so I'll try my best
after I left the jail I told myself
I mustn't lose again
brother I promise I won't be bad anymore
I must be a fair lady
I must listen to brother sky
who are you talking to
With my brother
before the launching of this toy
I found brother like a panda
but since it's launched look
it looks like my brother a lot
get up here
me
Do you know I never buy toys
As I find they worthless
but there's something
you can buy with money
don't say so this toy is expensive
want to sit next to me
You let me sit next to you
Great
I must revenge for my brother
how to I'm the driver
Come on let's do some practice
sit still  ok
hold your brother tightly
come 1st gear
turn left
Then right
I eft
You really not scared
No
Ok
Aren't they here yet
That bastard must be too afraid to come
no sky is not such a guy
both his father and
himself aren't such guys
tonight the dividend for
brother fung is 1 to 1
and that bastard is 1 to 5
You drive this lousy car
You'll surely lose
We fear nothing as you don't fear aids
so you're uneducated
there's a saying
tools are vital for a success
car racing requires for driving skills
but tools are important as well
I tell you I have enough tools today
is black tone fine
I tell you I'll defeat you
just as I defeated your father
I tell you too black tone
sends you his regards
he wants me to tell you he lives
like king in Thailand
good
and my buddy paddy
Sky the car is in excellent condition
brother will bless you
to defeat that bastard
be gentle
sorry
Give it to me
you gave me that
Give it to me now
Lucky
take it
It's Kelly's
Remember you are to control the car
some racers don't care about dying
sometimes you must use brake
sometimes the accelerator
Sky
I can't even see his rear lights Why