My jacket
Boss, the car's here
Mind your head
Is the room ready?
Yes, it's ready
OK
The room is all paid for
You girl take good care of our VIP
Over here, sir
Roy, this is Captain Fung
Sit, and drinks?
Yesterday someone got his fingers
chopped off at the nearby public toilet
It's just one finger
One should always pay for his food
You're in charge, tell us who did it
Did I say I'm involved?
You want us to drop by everyday?
Good! I can take a vacation then
And you'll be doing my job for me
I'm sure this street will be completely
safe
Roy
Sit
He told you to sit
Tell them what happened
Hey, see what they want to drink
It's on me
This time it's free
Take your time
You have nothing to do with this
Don ' t move
Boss, I'll cover you, go
Frank, I'm at the Super Bowl restaurant
Someone wants to kill me
The word is out, someone's coming
Leave now
Got it
Dinner? Where's he at?
Tell him this is Frank
have him call me right away
Shit, why do things come up every time
I have a cold?
Boss... Are you all right?
I'm OK
Brother, everything all right?
You go back first
I already called Raymond
He'll take care of the cops
Tell Fay to take the boss back
What a lousy day, I was scared shitless
Go home and rest
OK
This way
Bring me a camera
Go get a camera
Shit
Did I really ask for a camera?
What are you standing here for?
Waiting to have your pictures taken?
Find me those killers
Yes, Frank
Talk
No
I don't know who did it
I'm no a traitor
Ko has been shot to death
You're saying you're not involved?
Why are you alive?
And not even a single wound?
I'm scared, Frank
I really didn't betray the boss, Frank
1O minutes
Believe me... Frank
Frank, don't kill me
If he's still alive after 1O minutes
it means he's innocent
Yes
If he can't make it, then too bad for him
Understood
Joe, get in
Spending millions on re-furnishing
is it worth it?
Where's your tie?
My wife took it to the laundry
A servant never knows his manner
Frank
Sister in law
Going out?
Yes, I'm meeting a friend for lunch
I'm late, I have to go
Joe, have someone go with her
Brother
You're going to scare the neighbors
with all those men outside blocking the
road
They have a problem with that?
Frank
I'll have them replaced by other people
Go get Curtis
Damn
a haircut costs less than a hundred
But this creative director dyed a streak
of my hair blonde
and charged me a thousand dollars
Am I disturbing you?
No
What's the latest trend?
Maybe you can do my hair sometime
I saw this actress on TV who dyed her
hair blonde
It's yellow and glittery
looks just like shit
Have you heard what happened?
Yes
Huh?
I heard about it
I remember now
the paper says
she's a 36C
She's really hot
Tomorrow at 3
Come to the office
Please have a seat
Thanks
You're welcome
I'm Shin
I'm with Roy
Please wait inside
OK
Curtis
Sit
I'm Shin, I'm with Roy
How have you been?
Same old, same old
Please wait inside
Roy
It's OK
Please have a seat
Thanks
Damn
why can't the foreigners learn Cantonese?
Anyone want to order out?
4O cents
Somehow it turned into a two million
dollar profit
Let's go, my brother's waiting
Mr. Lung
Thank you, Helen
Brother, they're all here
Mr. Lung
Curtis, long time no see, how are you?
Pretty good. Thank you
Mike
Mr. Lung, how are you?
Thanks
James
Mr. Lung
Thank you
Roy, Shin
they're very well respected
Thank you
Thank
Everyone please be careful
Mr. Lung, please take a deep breath
Thanks
Mr. Lung, is it too tight?
It's OK
You guys are unbelievable
I only let for a few days
and someone already messed up my
place?
Rat?
I'm not scared of him
Back?
You want me to come back?
Just kill him
Add 2 pounds to the recoil spring
So they had more people
5 arrested and 2 wounded
No?
5 wounded and 2 arrested
What?
Damn it, you go eat shit
Mrs. Lung
Going out?
No, I want some water
Let me help you
Thank you
Hot or cold water?
Hot water please
Thank you
I know you don't have one
You said you can find anything
and you can't find me a bullet-proof vest?
Call me
Hello... Mr. Chan
What?
You need a room
and 4 women?
I'm not in the business anymore
Bye
I hate addressing these losers as "mister"
Got cigarettes?
James, Shin get the cars ready
Mr. Lung is going out
Got it
What's up?
What? What's up?
Anything wrong?
We're born to see action, not to stand
here all day
If we have to stand, we might as well
become hookers
It's better than doing night-watch here
Go tell that to Frank
Anyway, I hope it'll be over soon
What's up?
What are you talking about?
He wants me to have a talk with him?
Who does he think he is?
I'm one of the 5 bodyguards
It's a job that other kids can only
dream about
If I can make a name for myself this time
I can brag about it in the years to come
So how did you make a name
for yourself
Were you involved in all the big events?
Tell me, there's a lot I need to learn
Mr. Lung, are you all right?
Are you all right?
It's a rifle
Mike, see where the sniper is
He didn't fall for it
I'll go
Roy
Start the car
Mike
His gun's got a scope
You don't have the advantage from
this distance
I'll move up
Go Shin
Let him go
Roy
Get in your cars
Where ' s Roy?
Everyone get in
I don't know how to drive
Roy
Where ' s Curtis?
In the backyard
I don't care. Just find him for me
Roy
Stop it
Hey, are you crazy?
Put the guns away
Break it up
James, Mike
you guys will do the night-watch
Good morning, Mr. Lung
Mr. Lung
Curtis went out
Are you going out?
I'm not going to the office today
Are you all right?
It still hurts a little
I'm getting old
Who want coffee?
Milk tea?
Ovaltine?
What?
Make yourself at home
If I was killed last night
It's just my bad luck
you guys are not responsible
For someone in my position
you have to be ready for a lot of things
Who doesn't take sugar?
Curtis
This way
Rat
Who is this?
Curtis
What do you want?
Stay away from Roy's bar
Why?
Just leave it alone
Shit
That's my boss
Roy, what a coincidence
So you left your street to become
a driver?
About Rat's death, good for you
Someone did you a favor
Lately your street has been a lot more
quiet
I know you're busy
so I go to your bar everyday
It's like a daily routine
Rat is out of the picture now
And I'm not scared of cats or dogs
Visit your place sometime
I'll buy you a drink
Bye Roy
Shin, listen... listen to me
From now on you go pick up Mrs. Lung
lt'll be your job
Who did Curtis work for?
Mr. Lung
Why is his name Curtis? He looks funny
Don't judge him by his looks
He had a formidable reputation around
Tsim Sha Tsui
You mess with him and you're dead
You serious? Go ask around
People call him The Ice
Curtis Hey
Thanks
Roy
Thank you
You're welcome
How did you kill him?
You did it alone?
It's none of your business
Thank you
What matter is that Mr. Lung is safe
Feeling better now?
Who wants to kill Mr. Lung?
Just focus on our job
How long do you think we have to do
this job?
How do I know?
You busy? If you are, then leave
I'm OK, I can do this for another 8 or
1O years
Is there another cigarette?
Mr. Lung, you've been in trouble lately
You're not around to call the shots
All the business came to a halt
how can we go on?
We can't let this continue
We need business
But we don't have anyone in charge now
And we don't know who's trying to kill
Mr. Lung
Mr. Lung, you're the boss
Mr. Lung, you should give us some
assurance
Something like this happens periodically
How will outsiders look at us?
How will our men look at us?
Frank is looking into it
Everyone knows I'm the boss
If you have any good ideas
then tell me
You're the boss, it's your call.
Mr. Lung, we'll go first
Super Bowl...
is not doing well
I want to take back my shares for
another use
Uncle
You don't have many shares left
Then forget it
How much do you need?
2O million
I'll give it to you tomorrow morning
Thank you
Uncle
don't go to Macau so often
OK
James
What happened?
the care broke down
I could reach you on your cell phone
The phone battery is dead
I spent an hour and still couldn't fix
the car
The spark plug is wet
Go take a shower
Helen, this is the file you need
Thanks
Helen, I'm leaving for the day
Yes, Mr. Lung
The old men didn't say much
It was only that bowtie bastard who
can't shut up
I'm looking into him
he's suspicious
Let's not talk here
Manchester United has had a bad season
Should bet on them?
I bet 5 million dollars, half of it is your
money
Frank, got any money?
Do you have any money with you?
I always carry enough with me
Give me some
James
Understood
It's hared to believe he didn't die
This is from Mr. Lung
Curtis
Remember me?
I'm Hoi, long time no see
Am I disturbing you?
Looks like you're doing well
Call me if there are any good jobs
I just got out of prison
OK, this is my number
Remember to call me
Look out, boss
Where are you shot
Can't you see the bullet yourself?
Thank God I got my bullet-proof vest
in time
But it still hurts
Frank, I got it
Got it
OK, I understand
So it's Fat Cheung
How many men are left?
Wait for my call
He'll call me
We have to act now
If that bastard gets the word and escapes
How will we find him?
Bring him over here
What if he refuses to come?
You eat too much
You should be careful
Go see a doctor
Have your blood pressure and
cholesterol level checked
Loose some weight
My brother wants to see you
Finish your food first
There was a time when I had to rise my
life just for a good meal
I admit I plotted the hits
I lost
I accept my fate
Go talk to my brother
I'm an old man
I'm tried to always having to serve some
else
Take my life if you want it
Your father came from Shan ton
to Hong Kong
We roamed about to take a living
We started with nothing, but we became
an organization
We all put our heats into it
But there's one thing I don't understand
Can you tell me...
How come it's your family in charge of
the organization now?
Finish the job before you leave
So people know we mean business
Understood
Let's move
Enjoy the food, Curtis, I'll go get the
shark fins
Sorry for the trouble
Don't mention it
I thought I was going to do this job for
8 or 1O years
But the moment we struck back
They just fell apart quickly
Now, I'm already missing the actions
Farewell
If the 5 of us are such a great team
We should get together and make some
money
Sure
I'm going to work for Roy
Don't count me in, I still prefer cutting
hair
James?
Friendship forever
Sure
Curtis
My brother wants you guys to take this
Thank you
I want to say good-bye to Mr. Lung
Don't disturb him
In the old days when we finished a job
all we did was go out dancing and
got massages
There was this crazy old man
But he's already dead
He gave everyone a bag of cocaine
after each job
What do I need that for? Shit
These days...
The organization treats everyone
impartially
My brother doesn't know about this
It's only between the two of us
What?
My sister-in-law
She had an affair with Shin
Who told you that?
Go ask him
What if he says it's true?
I'll take care of it
That means I won't see him again
Sure
Curtis
These are for you guys
Can you get me a gun before 1O
Anything in particular?
Just the usual
Don't forget, before 1O
Let me borrow your phone
Wait for me outside
Shin, this is Curtis
Got time? Let's meet up
I'll pick you up after work...
OK
Hello, who are you?
Who are you?
Shin?
Who is this?
This is James
Wrong number
Hello
James...
Yeah?
Slow down
What?
What happened?
Do you know what happened?
Yes
Mike
Let's find Curtis
Did you drive Mrs. Lung to places? Did
you?
I did
Did she seduce you? Did she?
She tried to seduce me
Curtis
Shin is with me
He's young and inexperienced
We're all good friends
I'm just doing my job
I have to protect him
You have to finish the job, right?
I know people call you The Ice
but do you have to be that cold-hearted?
If you use your gun, I'll use mine too
I'll protect him
Don't touch him
Roy
Did you have an affair with Mrs. Lung?
Did you?
Now Frank wants Curtis to kill you
Make sure he gets on the boat tonight
What's the matter with you?
Take it
What's your plan when you get to Taiwan
I've never been there
I'm afraid to fly
I've never be there either
I didn't expect the first thing to do for
Roy would be getting you out of HK
Thanks
Roy is a good boss
You're with the right man
The boat's here
Maybe we'll meet again
Shin
If you leave, Curtis will have to take the
wrap
Because Roy protected you, Frank will
deal with him
James and I will also be in a lot of trouble
It's you, or the 4 of us
James
is the gun ready?
I gave it to him
It's black
It's all set
Curtis
They're here
Sit, Curtis
Can you let him go?
Joe is outside
Then let's enjoy this meal
You can say it's a farewell dinner
Sure
Eat
Curtis
Let me talk to Mr. Lung
I'll be back before 3
OK, before 3
Mr. Lung
Shin didn't mean it
you can't blame it all on Shin
Your wife
Mr. Lung
give me face, I guarantee you he won't
do it again
Mr. Lung
please let Shin go
He's just a kid, he knows he's wrong
Just cut his hand off and spare his life
You're a generous man
I'm here to see Mr. Lung
Mrs. Lung
Time's up
How did it go?
James, don't make it difficult for me
Roy, don't shoot
Mrs. Lung
is dead
Thank you
Take care of it for me
Sure thing
James