In the year 2046,
a vast rail network spans the globe.
A mysterious train leaves for 2046
every once in a while.
Every passenger going to 2046
has the same intention.
They want to recapture
lost memories.
Because nothing ever changes
in 2046.
Nobody really knows
if that's true
because nobody's ever come back,
except me.
998.
997.
If someone wants to leave 2046,
how long will it take?
Some people get away fairly easily,
others find that
it takes them much longer.
I forget how long
I've been on this train.
I'm starting to feel very lonely.
As I recall,
many have gone to 2046.
You're the first to come back.
May I ask why you left 2046?
Whenever anyone asked
why I left 2046,
I gave them some vague answer.
Before,
when people had secrets
they didn't want to share,
they'd climb a mountain,
find a tree
and carve a hole in it,
and whisper the secret
into the hole.
Then cover it over with mud.
That way, nobody else
would ever discover it.
I once fell in love with someone.
After a while, she wasn't there.
I went to 2046.
I thought she might be waiting
for me there.
But I couldn't find her.
I can't stop wondering
if she loved me or not.
But I never found out.
Maybe her answer was
like a secret
that no-one else
would ever know.
ALL MEMORIES ARE TRACES OF TEARS
Didn't you promise
not to come back?
I came to see you.
Why?
I have no prospects here.
So I'll see
how things are in Hong Kong.
When are you leaving?
The boat sails in two days.
Why are you telling me?
I thought we might go together.
You know nothing
about my past, do you?
If you'd rather not tell me,
I don't mind.
If you win, I'll join you.
She found an indirect way
of rejecting me.
As I recall,
that was the very last time
we saw each other.
Right after that,
I left Singapore.
I got back to Hong Kong
at the end of 1966.
It was the time of the riots.
I wasn't sure
how long I'd be staying,
so I took a room
in a small hotel in Wanchai.
I wrote columns for newspapers.
They paid HK$10
per thousand words.
It was pretty tough at first.
As long as
I could make ends meet,
it made no difference
what kind of stuff I wrote.
"Diary of the Bazooka Hero."
"The new star at Club Luk Kwok
is Fei Fei."
"A knockout beauty
with amazing bazookas."
"A smash hit with tit-lovers!"
Hang on, of course I exaggerate.
I can't say her tits are fake,
can I?
I soon got used
to this kind of life.
I became an expert ladies' man.
Lots of one-night-stands.
But nothing lasts
forever anyway.
24 DECEMBER 1966
Is that really true?
Why would I lie to you?
You really know me?
Weren't you in a show
in Singapore in '64?
Yes.
You're Lulu.
I was then.
Not any more.
What's your name now?
Why should I tell you?
On Christmas Eve 1966,
I ran into a friend
from Singapore in a nightclub.
We'd been rather close
but that night
she'd apparently forgotten me.
Have we really met before?
How could you forget?
You said I looked
like your late boyfriend.
You taught me the cha-cha.
Go on.
You were always dragging me
to the casino.
You'd hit a losing streak.
You owed a fortune.
My friends and I paid
for your passage to Hong Kong.
You talked a lot
about your late boyfriend.
A Chinese Filipino
from a rich family.
You planned to marry him.
But he died young.
You said
he was the love of your life.
I shouldn't bring back sad memories
at this time of year.
But do you remember
that Christmas night
we went drinking?
We talked a lot.
Was she just pretending
she'd forgotten me?
I took her back to her hotel.
She was dead to the world.
She'd had too much to drink
so I left quickly.
On my way out,
I noticed a very familiar number.
If I hadn't run into her that night,
I wouldn't have seen that number
and I wouldn't have written "2046."
Can I help you?
Is Miss Lulu in?
Lulu? There's no Miss Lulu here.
There was a Mimi,
but she moved out.
But I was here two days ago!
Do you know where she's gone?
No. What do you want with her?
Nothing, really.
I have her key.
I wanted to return it.
You can give it to me.
Thanks.
You want to rent the room?
I'm just back from abroad.
I don't have my own place yet.
If the room's vacant,
I could take a look.
This is just a small hotel,
but our residents are all
decent people.
What's your line of work?
I write for newspapers.
Great! A fellow artist!
I haven't always done this.
I used to be an artist, too.
Really?
I took singing lessons in Harbin.
Back then, I was a tenor.
It'll be a pleasure
to have you here.
- When will you move in?
- As soon as possible.
But 2046 has to be redecorated.
2047 is vacant.
Take a look at it.
Never mind.
I'll come back when it's ready.
Why that particular room?
Maybe it's the number.
It has some significance for you?
I'm joking.
Tell you what.
Take a quick look at 2047.
If it's okay, you can move in.
Then switch to 2046 when it's ready.
How about it?
- Can I see the room?
- Of course. Please.
Once I moved in,
I found out what had happened
the night before.
Lulu was stabbed
by a jealous boyfriend.
A drummer from the club.
She'd really liked him,
and compared him
with a bird that could never land.
For all these years,
she has been looking for
her "legless bird."
Most of her affairs ended badly,
but she didn't mind sad endings.
No matter what happened,
at least she was always
the leading lady.
Good!
Sure!
Go!
Let's go!
I'll go with you!
Good, I'll go with you!
Sure!
I understand!
You know what I mean?
I know... I understand.
I got it!
Can I go?
I can go!
Sure!
I understand!
Got it!
It didn't take long
to finish redecorating 2046.
But by then
I was used to 2047.
Sure!
I started hearing a strange voice
through the wall.
I thought someone had moved in.
But it was the daughter
of the hotel owner, Mr. Wang.
Please take me with you!
Definitely!
I'm definitely going!
Okay, let's go!
I had no idea
what she was saying.
The bell-hop told me
it was Japanese.
It seems she had
a Japanese boyfriend.
Tell the driver
"220 Granville Road."
- Ga...ran...wai...
- 220 Granville Road.
Turn from Humphreys Avenue,
near Kimberley Road.
Can you say again?
- Don't turn down Salisbury Road
- Slowly, please.
- I'll draw you a map.
- That's my pen!
I'll repeat it once more.
Turn from Humphreys Avenue,
near Kimberly Road.
But don't turn down Salisbury Road.
Understand?
I'll draw you a map.
Granville Road.
Turn from Humphreys Avenue,
don't turn down Salisbury Road.
Remember, don't turn down Salisbury Road.
His company in Japan
had sent him to Hong Kong.
when he got here,
he checked into this hotel.
The world is full of men!
Why do you have to choose a Japanese?
Get rid of him!
I will never meet him!
You want my blessing?
Not while I'm alive!
It had been going on for ages.
Their family suffered
under the Japanese in the war,
so they had to break up.
Can you tell me what you feel?
Do you like me?
Or not?
I'm scared to hear your answer.
But I have to ask anyway.
Leave with me.
Goodbye.
The man finally went back
to Japan.
That's when Miss Wang
began talking to herself.
Hey, ask your boss
to turn it down a bit!
Mr. Chow,
you'd better ask him yourself.
Mr. Chow...
Hasn't he left already?
Why is he back?
I will not see him!
If you won't give him up...
Get out! Go away with him!
I assumed that Mr. Wang
played it so loud
because he loved his opera.
Actually he didn't want anyone
to overhear the family row.
What are you doing?
Come back for me
when you're a little older!
Wait till you grow up!
I like it.
Mr. Wang thought about very little
but his two daughters.
The elder one was crazy
about her Japanese man.
The younger one was precocious.
She always came in my room for drinks.
Then she ran off with some man.
Another drummer
from a club band, I heard.
After she left, her elder sister
got into trouble too.
Hey, have a word with your boss for me.
I'm a bit late with the rent.
Anyway, he has my deposit.
Mr. Chow, tell him yourself.
He's in a foul mood these days.
What's eating him?
First, one daughter ran away,
now the other one's in hospital.
Why is she in hospital?
He wouldn't say, he was quite strange.
Steer clear of him.
So, that's it?
Anyhow, give him my invitation.
It's my father's birthday banquet.
He can deduct his gift
from the rent I owe.
On 22 May 1961, they imposed
a curfew in Hong Kong.
Home-made bombs caused panic.
The economy stopped dead.
I stopped going out.
Some thought I was
a reformed character.
Actually, I was writing.
A story called 2046.
All about men and women
looking for love,
risking everything
to get to a place called 2046.
What's that?
Let's go to...
I made it bizarre and erotic,
without crossing the line.
The readers liked it.
Some didn't take
to the science-fiction angle,
but all "2046" meant to me was...
the number of a hotel room.
I made up the whole thing.
But some of my own experiences
found their way into it.
People I ran into
in the normal course of things
turned up in my stories.
I felt more and more at ease
in my fictional world.
Around that time,
Mr. Wang's music got louder again.
More trouble
with his two daughters.
But also because
of the bad state of the economy.
A lot of the rooms were empty.
Then in September,
the rioting ended.
Life went back to normal
Soon, someone moved into 2046.
Have you nearly finished?
It's too early in the day for that!
Some of us are trying to sleep!
Peeking?
The woman next door is quite a dish!
What are my chances?
You're off your head. A father-to-be
shouldn't have that on his mind.
Now she's pregnant.
My wife won't let me touch her.
Come on. Put in a word for me.
Okay.
How much?
How much have you got?
Only $100.
Wait for my call.
Mr. Chow!
Mr. Chow, a call for you!
Bright and early, huh?
She's not up yet.
Why come over?
I told you, it has to be arranged.
She's not some street walker!
A fellow artist like you.
Show her a little respect, will you?
Yes, I'll tell you right away.
Miss Bai, your key.
You're back, Miss Bai.
Who is it?
Who are you looking for?
Mr. Chow suggested I come by.
You're back, Mr. Chow.
Did you win on the dogs?
- I lost!
- I won a little.
Looking for me?
I think you know this person?
What are doing in that room?
You said you'd arrange it!
I paid you!
- I said that room.
- I said this one.
Your girl's in that room.
How embarrassing!
Please excuse him.
I told you,
the room on the left!
- I said I wanted that one!
- Shut up!
Who is it?
Oh, you again!
I just wanted
to apologize for last night.
Forget it.
Go away.
Ping, my editor,
was out of line.
But he's not really so bad.
Just a bit stingy.
Never pays his way.
Always says he's broke when the check arrives.
So I played a trick on him.
At my expense?
Didn't you go a bit far?
He only fell for it
because you're so beautiful.
You're quite a flirt!
Just stating the fact.
A small token of apology.
Please accept it.
I don't want it.
You're still cross, aren't you?
Please accept it.
- No.
- Come on.
- It's just a token...
Don't make fun of me,
I mean what I say!
Now, get out!
That's good, let it all out.
Slap me again if you want.
Think I wouldn't dare?
Come closer.
Bastard!
Don't be so petty.
That's enough.
I'm courteous enough
not to slap you again.
That doesn't mean
you can take advantage.
This time I'll give you face.
If there's ever a next time,
I'll be less polite.
It won't happen again.
My face is still numb.
Accept it.
They're just a token of my regard.
I chose them myself.
See if you like them.
If you don't,
just throw them away.
Good.
I'll leave now.
Calm down!
It's none of your business
who I dated last night!
Who?
Dabao!
Which Dabao?
The fat one or the skinny one?
From Shanghai or from Shandong?
The trouble is,
I know so many men named Dabao.
How should I know
which one you mean?
Yes, I did.
What are you going to do about it?
Fine!
I'll be waiting!
Let me just say...
Get out!
You think I can accept this?
Her or me.
You'd better choose!
Now get out!
24 DECEMBER 1967
You're back early!
It's Christmas!
Shouldn't you be having dinner
with your boyfriend?
What boyfriend?
Then let's have supper.
Come on.
You have so many girlfriends!
You need company?
Go out with them!
They all want to be with me,
but I can't choose.
The fairest thing is
to see none of them.
Come on, no point in staying
cooped up in your room.
I'm not in a good mood tonight.
I might get drunk
and slap you again.
That's okay.
I'm used to it.
If slapping me would make you happy,
take that as my Christmas present.
Come on.
Come with me.
Let go!
I didn't expect
to spend Christmas like this.
What did you expect?
We'd made plans.
He was taking me to Singapore.
He says it's warm there
at Christmas.
So I didn't even pack
winter clothes.
What I'm wearing now
is for summer.
Have you been to Singapore?
I worked there
for several years.
What kind of work?
On a newspaper.
Is it fun there?
It's okay.
Tell me more.
I won't be going,
so I'll just have to imagine it.
What do you want to know?
How's the climate?
Pretty warm.
All year round.
Sometimes you can't tell
what season it is.
The food stalls are great.
Ping and I ate there after work.
We'd eat and drink till dawn.
Our landlord was a funny man.
Short and fat,
and he always wore a skirt.
What the Malays call a "sarong."
But when you're away from home
it sometimes gets boring.
That was a dull meal.
Another drink somewhere else?
You really like to drink?
It makes things easy.
When I'm drunk,
I have no worries.
Won't your girlfriends
be missing you tonight?
They're not stuck to me.
They see other men too.
We just have fun together.
They still need to make a living.
I don't get it.
Where does all that "fun" get you?
If you find the right person,
why waste time on the others?
If I find the right person!
A man like me has nothing much
except free time.
That's why I need company.
So people are
just time-fillers to you?
I wouldn't say that.
Other people can borrow
my time too.
And tonight?
Are you borrowing me
or am I borrowing you?
No difference.
Maybe I borrowed you earlier,
and now you're borrowing me.
Ridiculous!
Don't get me wrong.
I don't intend
to take advantage of you.
If that was what I wanted,
I had plenty of options.
I just want us to be drinking pals.
Is that okay?
It's hard.
But I'll give it a try.
Okay.
Let's try.
- Where to?
- Let's drink!
Mr. Chow,
you seem happy tonight.
I certainly am,
my friends are buying me dinner.
This way, please.
Ping! Is it someone's birthday?
Better than that!
Chow has a new girlfriend!
Definitely worth celebrating!
What would you like to eat tonight?
Something expensive.
- Snake?
- Yes, snake would be good.
Snake isn't cheap.
Can you afford it?
Shut Up! Don't mind him.
- What'll it be, Mr. Chow?
- Snake!
And a lamb casserole, too.
And bring Hoi's whiskey.
Can't let this go to waste,
it's delicious.
Where's your girl, Chow?
It's already 2 AM. Is she coming?
She can't be coming.
I don't think she's coming.
It's all your fault.
You're why this happened.
Why blame me?
You brought this on yourself.
You said she was gentle and obedient.
Now we know the truth.
I said
she was sometimes obedient,
and sometimes gentle.
But she's full of surprises,
that's part of the fun.
- So, what next?
- Yes, what now?
Whatever you feel like doing.
And then what happened?
Tell me!
How are you going to thank me?
Pervert!
Open Up!
- Who is it?
- Open the door!
It's late.
You played a fine joke
on me tonight.
I finished work late.
Too late to get there.
So I didn't come.
What's this?
That's your fault too.
How could I know
you'd stand me up?
I thought
I'd win a few hundred.
Instead I lost my mustache.
This is all your fault.
You deserved it.
Who pushed you into the bet?
I'll tell you something.
Ping asked me not to show up.
Anyhow,
I wasn't that fond of the mustache.
You look younger now.
Don't you like it?
You're making fun of me!
You tricked me. I'll get you for this.
How will you make it up to me?
At least give me a kiss.
You bit me!
Come and get me!
You're in for it
when I catch you!
Don't touch me there!
Bastard!
You've bruised me.
Think you were any better?
Look, I'm bleeding.
Maybe it's because winter's coming.
See what happens
when I eat lamb?
Brings out the beast in me.
- What?
- Don't move.
- What are you doing?
- Shaving you.
Don't!
Who knows where that shaver's been.
It could bring me bad luck.
Let's go for Round Two!
No way.
Why are you dressed?
I'm going back to my room.
I'm exhausted.
This is all I have.
Aside from loose change for the bus.
Here's $200.
Please take it.
I don't want it.
I wasn't selling.
That's not how I meant it.
I want to pay for your torn dress.
Please take it.
I see.
You're afraid
I'll cling to you, is that it?
Fine.
I'll take $10.
Think of it as a discount rate.
If you ever want
to come over again,
I'll charge the same.
I'm going back to my room.
Come here.
Not tonight.
Why not?
Not in the mood?
Can't take the strain tonight.
Anyhow,
I'm a bit short of cash.
Never mind,
you can owe me.
I don't like being in debt.
The reception's at 6,
dinner at 8.
I don't mind if you can't make it,
just send your gift.
No more than you do.
You hold banquets all year round.
You've had 4 birthdays this year.
I'll send over some more
invitation cards later.
Think of people with money,
write in their names
and send them invitations.
Mr. Chow,
holding another banquet?
You know we have birthdays
in different calendars?
Another of mine's come up.
No doubt.
- Here's one for your boss
- Alright.
Tell him that since we're so close,
he can deduct his gift
from the rent I owe.
- Make sure he gets it.
- Okay.
It's late, what's so urgent?
Just got back from Macau.
Chow asked me to bring you a present.
You two went to Macau?
Yes, we had some days off,
so we went to the casino.
Oh, it's beautiful.
He says he found some money
in his pocket.
So before losing it all
at the tables,
he bought you a present.
Where is he?
Not back yet.
You know what he's like.
Extravagant
at the start of the month,
and broke well before the end.
He made several thousand
holding that party,
so now he's really enjoying himself.
Is he there alone?
Of course not. There's a gang of them.
He likes company.
Was he always like this?
Let's not talk about him.
Let's have a drink.
But I should warn you,
I know you like Chow a lot.
Don't waste your time on him.
He's not serious.
Guess who?
There's only one possibility.
Let me have a bite first.
What are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
What do you think?
I thought I was pretty wild.
But you're much wilder.
Pay up.
I haven't seen you for ages.
I've been busy.
Liar.
Tell me the truth.
I am.
Who was that woman
the other day?
What woman?
Don't pretend.
I saw her leaving your room.
Who is she?
- A friend.
- A friend?
What was she doing
in your room?
Don't be nosy, alright?
Go back to your room.
I have work to do.
I won't!
I'm sleeping here tonight.
- An overnight stay is expensive.
- No problem.
Name your price.
I'd pay anything to be with you.
Every day.
Retail is fine.
Wholesale is out of the question.
Why?
I just don't like it.
Could you make an exception for me?
No.
You treat all women like this?
Except one.
Who?
My mother.
I'm serious.
I don't mind
you having other women.
But I won't be treated
the same as them.
I don't care
if you love me or not.
I'll love you anyway.
Since we got together,
I haven't brought other men back.
I hoped you'd think the same way.
Will you promise me that?
No.
I see.
Then we're through.
I'll never bother you.
And I never want you in my room again.
Here, $10.
Tonight, I'm paying.
Thank you.
If you're ever in the mood,
feel free to come over.
I'll charge you the same.
Having fun?
What do you care?
You were rather loud last night.
I meant to be.
You bring back women,
why shouldn't I have men?
I want to see
if you really don't mind.
I won't go,
why don't you come here instead?
Forget it! Don't come!
After Bai Ling moved out,
she started dating Dabao.
And I saw other women too.
If our paths ever crossed,
we'd pretend not to see each other.
Rather pathetic, I know.
But it was better
for us to end it this way.
I've never seen her since.
But sometimes she pops up
in my stories.
Your change, please check it.
Thank you.
Are you going out later?
Why?
Could you post this letter for me?
Sure.
Then Miss Wang came back.
I knew from the familiar sound through the wall.
Please take me with you!
Good!
What are you doing?
Wasn't I clear?
Don't contact that Japanese man!
Why are you writing to him in secret?
Aren't you ashamed?
Return his letter!
No?
What are you reading?
A martial-arts novel.
You like them?
If your friend wants to send you
more letters,
and you don't want your dad to know,
tell him to send them to my room.
I'll pass them on to you.
She looked happier
when she came back this time.
We talked more often.
Mr. Chow,
another letter for you.
Another!
Those Japanese girls
get so carried away!
"Let's see each other again.
Then, if you still think
we shouldn't be together,
tell me so, frankly.
That day, six years ago,
a rainbow appeared in my heart.
It's still there.
Like a flame burning inside me.
But what are your real feelings for me?
Are they like a rainbow
after the rain?
Or did that rainbow
fade away long ago?
I'm waiting for your answer."
Why do you write all that stuff
about sex?
So I won't starve!
Don't you worry
about your reputation?
Maybe I'm not such a nice guy.
- Why not try writing something else?
- Who'd read it?
How about a martial-arts novel?
People love them.
That's too hard.
I tried once,
co-writing it with someone.
We locked ourselves away
for months.
Just got sore heads.
Those were good times.
I like writing too.
It's hard to make a living
by writing.
I just do it for fun.
I'll show you some of my stuff.
Here you are, read this first.
Wow, you're prolific!
When you've read it, tell me what you think.
And don't forget to return it.
Sure!
Have you read my story yet?
I have.
What did you think?
I think you should never write
another word.
Why not?
You're so good.
You could put me out of work.
"The Spider Sage thrusts out
his fist.
Two chopsticks take off
like rockets.
They land with explosive force.
The mountain splits apart."
Slow down, I can't keep up.
Come on, they're waiting for it.
Alright, alright.
Caught up?
Go on.
Where was I?
"The mountain splits apart."
Right.
"The mountain splits apart,
smashing Iron Abacus
to the ground."
Iron Abacus?
Isn't he dead?
Is he?
Then make it Iron Head.
Where did Iron Head
come from all of a sudden?
Hey, anything goes
in martial-arts novels.
Why don't you get some rest?
I'll finish it for you.
Okay.
It felt like having an assistant.
When I was late with my copy,
I asked her to ghost it for me.
She was just a girl,
but she could write
as raunchily as the best of us.
We got along very well.
That was my happiest summer ever.
But it didn't last.
I encouraged her
to face up to her father,
but she didn't dare.
She wanted to pay her own way,
so I got her job
in the cloakroom at a club.
Thanks.
She told her father
she was going out with me.
Sometimes I found an excuse
to pick her up after work.
You're here late.
If you're ready to go,
I have a taxi waiting.
I can give you a lift back.
No, thanks.
Then I won't wait.
Feelings can creep up on you
unawares.
I knew that, but did she?
She was always asking if there was
anything at all that never changed.
I could see what was on her mind.
I promised to write a story for her,
based on my observation.
Something to show her
what her boyfriend was thinking.
As a joke,
we thought of calling it "2047."
But maybe I was being too oblique.
I'd begun to feel that it wasn't
about her boyfriend at all.
Rather it was more about me.
So I began imagining myself
as a Japanese man,
on a train for 2046,
falling for an android
with delayed reaction.
If someone wants to leave 2046,
how long will it take?
No one can say.
Some people get away
fairly easily.
Others find that
it takes them much longer.
It takes great strength.
And it can hurt terribly.
I forget how long I've been on this train.
I start to feel very lonely.
It's rather boring at first.
But slowly you get used to it.
We have a range of cabin attendants.
They can satisfy your every need.
They will serve you devotedly,
like an intimate friend.
But you must never
fall in love with them.
Who'd ever fall for an android?
Who can say?
Events can creep up on you
without you ever noticing.
It can happen to anyone.
Paragraph 201
in the Passengers' Guide
warns that Area 1224-1225
is especially cold.
The train heating
won't be strong enough.
Passengers are advised
to hug each other to keep warm.
Since I'm the only passenger,
I hug my android cabin attendant.
I wonder if it's her mechanism
or just my imagination,
but I sense some responsive warmth
in her artificial body.
Why do you want to leave 2046?
Do you know
what people did in the old days
when they had secrets
they didn't want to share?
They'd climb a mountain,
find a tree,
carve a hole in it,
whisper the secret into the hole,
and cover it up with mud.
That way,
nobody else would ever learn
the secret.
I'll be your tree.
Tell me,
and nobody else will ever know.
I always...
Very funny. I always...
Whenever anyone asked
why I left 2046,
I gave them some vague answer.
I always...
I once fell in love with someone.
I couldn't stop wondering
whether she loved me or not.
I found an android which looked
just like her.
I thought the android might
give me the answer.
10 HOURS LATER
I have a secret to tell you.
Leave with me.
I kept on asking.
But she never answered.
I began dreaming up excuses
for her silence.
Do you know the Buddhist canon?
"The 5 Decays of Celestial Beings"?
The 5 Decays of Celestial Beings.
It's all about the gods
and how they go
through this process too.
Our cabin attendants
are superbly designed.
But there's one problem.
When they've served
on so many long journeys,
fatigue begins to set in.
For example,
they might want to laugh,
but the smile would be slow to come.
They might want to cry,
but the tear wouldn't well up
till next day.
This one is failing fast.
I think you'd better give up.
I grew desperate.
I felt like giving up.
But I was soon trying again.
I have a secret to tell you.
Will you leave with me?
I have a secret
to tell you.
Will you leave with me?
Do you know what people did
in the old days
when they had secrets?
They'd climb a mountain,
find a tree,
carve a hole in it...
990...
991...
992...
993...
994...
995...
I slowly began to doubt myself.
Maybe the reason she didn't answer
was not that her reactions were delayed,
but simply that she didn't love me.
So at last I got it.
It's entirely beyond my control.
The only thing left for me
was to give up.
24 DECEMBER 1968
Why are you inviting me
to Christmas dinner?
You know how much I'll lose in tips
by not working?
Wouldn't it be awful
to be alone tonight?
I need company.
That means me?
Your boyfriend hasn't written
in a while.
I told him not to.
Anyway, it's hopeless.
No point waiting for me.
Why is it hopeless?
Go and look for him.
If you don't,
it really will be hopeless.
My dad will never give his consent.
If you were him,
what would you be doing tonight?
Why don't you ask him?
Have you got his phone number?
I can't hear you!
Can you speak louder?
I'm already shouting!
I felt like Santa Claus
that night.
Not in Cantonese!
I took her
to the newspaper office
and let her make a long distance call
to her boyfriend.
I was happy
to see her so happy.
In fact, zone 1224-1225
meant Christmas Eve
and Christmas Day.
On the night before Christmas
many people need more warmth than usual.
I didn't get that.
Maybe that was for the best.
10 HOURS LATER
I realized
the reason the android didn't answer
had nothing to do
with her mechanism wearing out,
nor that she didn't like him.
More likely
she already loved someone else.
Soon after that,
she went to Japan.
I gave her a copy
of my story "2047."
I hope she read it.
100 HOURS LATER
1,000 HOURS LATER
Love is all a matter of timing.
It's no good meeting
the right person
too soon or too late.
If I'd lived
in another time or place,
my story might have had
a very different ending.
I have to tell you.
Yes?
I'll be away for a couple of days.
Pay my daughter this month's rent.
She's back?
Not Jingwen?
I mean pay my younger girl, Jiewen.
So your worries are over!
Going on holiday?
No, I have to go to Japan.
But you hate Japanese!
Why go to Japan?
Jingwen is getting married.
Congratulations.
I wasn't sure
whether to go or not.
Now I've decided.
I just want her to be happy.
Can you help me choose a present?
No need for that.
She wanted me to ask you something.
What is it?
She read your story "2047."
She likes it a lot.
But she finds the ending too sad.
She wonders if you can change it?
I'll see what I can do.
AN HOUR LATER
10 HOURS LATER
100 HOURS LATER
Taxi!
I also like the story
to have a happy ending.
But I don't know how to write it.
Some years back
I had a happy ending in my grasp,
but I let it slip away.
Don't turn your back on me!
Has he been here?
While I was depressed, I ran into Lulu again.
She hadn't changed.
Still intensively jealous.
You think he's yours?
I thought you knew him well!
We've just been amusing ourselves.
So control yourself, Missy!
Watching her taught me something.
When you don't take "no"
for an answer
there is still a chance
you'll get what you want.
18 MONTHS LATER
Hello, is Mr. Chow there?
I know I have no right to ask,
but they say I need a guarantor.
The man who recruits girls
for the nightclub
says he knows you.
Can you talk to him for me?
No problem.
I know the man you mean.
I'll see him in a day or two.
Why did you choose Singapore?
I don't want to stay here
any longer.
I've been thinking about it
for some time.
I want to take a look
at the place.
Don't drink too much.
You don't look well.
Don't worry, it won't kill me.
You know what?
I came by here at Christmas.
I thought I might run into you.
Why didn't you call me first?
I don't know.
I came on impulse.
I don't know why.
That night I suddenly missed you
so much.
We're drinking pals.
Of course you'll miss me.
You're right.
"We're drinking pals".
Let's go.
- Waiter.
- Yes?
- The check.
- Yes.
Where are you staying?
In a hotel, a rather small room.
But it's not too bad.
I'll see you back.
No, thanks.
I've just moved in, it's a mess.
I'll invite you
once it's cleaned up.
I'll go first.
Seeing how much
Bai Ling had changed,
I was suddenly overcome
by a feeling of grief.
Indeed, last Christmas
I was not in Hong Kong.
24 DECEMBER, 1969
Have you seen Miss Su?
Miss Su?
Not for some time.
Any idea where she might be?
Probably back in Phnom Penh.
I didn't want to spend
Christmas 1969 in Hong Kong
so I visited Singapore
and went back to the casino.
I waited for several days,
but Black Spider never turned up.
No one knew where she was.
Some thought she'd gone back
to Phnom Penh.
Others thought she was dead.
Ping and I began working
in Singapore in 1963.
When my life lost
most of its meaning,
I started gambling every day.
Those were hard times for me.
Only one person
came to my rescue.
A professional gambler.
Some said she was a cheat.
She always wore black.
They called her Black Spider.
She kept her black glove on
for 365 days of the year.
Nobody knew why for sure.
Had her hand been chopped off
for cheating?
Did the glove cover up
a fake hand?
Nobody really knew.
Why do you wear that black glove?
It's a habit.
You're not from here?
I'm from Phnom Penh.
What a coincidence!
I was just in Cambodia.
It's in chaos.
Why were you there?
The newspaper sent me.
You're a journalist?
Not any more.
Why's that?
They made some changes,
and I'm now a "consultant"
on half pay,
with next to nothing to do.
So why are you spending your time
in the casino?
I tried to win enough
to pay my way back to Hong Kong.
You lost a lot?
A few thousand.
You should never set foot
in a casino in a bad mood.
You won't win.
I didn't expect to win.
I just hoped to get back my stake.
If you have any money left,
I can help you.
On one condition .
When you've got your money back,
stop gambling.
Why are you helping me?
I take a commission.
10% of whatever I win for you.
Think it over.
What good to her were her tiny
commissions on my winnings?
After that, we went hack
to the casino night after night.
We'd eat at the stall
next to the railway station.
She won back
all the money I'd lost.
Thank you.
Don't thank me, it's yours.
If you need me again tomorrow,
I'll be waiting here after dinner.
I still don't know your name.
It's Su. Su Lizhen.
A few years ago I fell in love
with another man's wife.
Her name was also Su Lizhen.
It was because of her
that I moved to Singapore.
I never dreamed I'd meet
another Su Lizhen.
I told her a lot
about the other Su Lizhen.
At first, we kept it secret.
But gossip soon spread.
Later we moved into a hotel.
We had Room 2046.
When I think back,
the whole thing was like a dream.
You loved her deeply?
It's history.
Let's change the subject.
You, what did you do before?
You want to know about me?
Come on, we'll play high-low.
If you win,
I'll tell you everything.
It struck me
that her past was like
the hand she always kept gloved.
A mystery with no solution.
Of all the men I've met,
you've been the best to me.
I'm already missing you.
Why won't you come with me?
Didn't you
promise not to ask?
Hold me.
It may be years
before we meet again.
The last time we saw each other
I told her...
Take care.
Maybe one day
you'll escape your past.
If you do, look for me.
Now it strikes me...
that what I told her
was actually meant for myself.
In love,
you can't bring on a substitute.
I was looking for what I'd felt
with the other Su Lizhen.
I didn't realize that myself.
But I'm sure she did.
WHEN THE PEONY BLOOMS
SHE STANDS TALL
AND THEN GOES AWAY
DOES SHE MEAN "NO" OR "YES"?
All for me?
You want to get me drunk?
I know you're a good drinker.
Let's drink
as much as we can.
If there's any left over,
finish it next time you're here.
One small thing
I have to ask you.
Here's some money,
please take it.
What for?
I know you borrowed
from a friend for my plane ticket.
Pay him back.
If there's any left,
pay my rent for me.
Where did you get so much money?
An old customer.
He's always been fond of me.
He treats me well.
But he's too old for me,
so I never paid him much attention.
I ran into him yesterday
while I was shopping.
He insisted on buying me dinner.
I needed money, so I went.
After dinner,
I told him I needed money.
He said I could have
as much as I wanted.
I told him I needed $5,000.
At first, I planned to save it
for Singapore.
But I'm using it now.
Don't be silly.
You're still young.
You have great prospects.
I borrowed the money
from my friends.
They don't need it back yet.
So keep this for yourself.
Pay me back later,
there's no rush.
Why are you so kind to me?
Perhaps it's fate.
Too bad it didn't last.
I wish
it could have gone on longer.
Don't be like this.
Let me buy you dinner tonight.
- Waiter, the check!
- Coming.
No, let me.
You're too kind.
You've spent enough time
and money on me already.
I don't want to owe you too much.
I need to make a phone call.
Please settle the check,
I'll be outside.
Will you come in?
No, thanks.
Get some rest.
I'll see you
to the airport tomorrow.
Please don't.
I'll be terribly sad
if you're there.
Take good care of yourself.
Why can't it be
like it was before?
Please don't go.
Stay with me tonight.
Let me borrow you.
Do you remember?
You once asked me
if there was anything
I wouldn't lend.
I've given it a lot of thought.
And now I know
there is one thing...
I'll never lend to anyone.
As I recall,
that was the very last time
we saw each other.
I haven't seen her
since that night.
Why can't it be
like it was before?
HE DIDN'T TURN BACK.
IT WAS AS IF HE'D BOARDED
A VERY LONG TRAIN
HEADING FOR A DROWSY FUTURE
THROUGH THE UNFATHOMABLE NIGHT.
Everyone who goes to 2046
has the same intention.
They want to recapture
lost memories.
Because in 2046...
nothing ever changes.
But nobody really knows
if that's true or not.
Because nobody has ever come back.
Version 1, ripped by Lwandle on December 4, 2014