Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Do it!
Get him! Get him!
You got him!
I only ever met one man
I wouldn't want to fight.
I can't stop that.
Get outta here, you useless tit.
When I met him, he was already
the best cut man in the business.
Can you stop it?
Started training and managing in
the '60s, but he never lost his gift.
No.
Let me have a look at him.
He's fine. He's fine.
He ain't if you don't stop this
bleeding. I'll give you one more round.
Seconds up. Let's go.
What do we do?
Tell me what to do.
You let him hit you.
Sometimes there's just
nothing you can do.
Cut's too wide,
too close to the bone...
maybe you got a severed vein...
or you just can't get
the coagulant deep enough.
There are all kinds of combinations
you come up against...
down in the different
layers of meat...
and Frankie knew
how to work every one.
People love violence.
They'll slow down at a car wreck
to check for bodies.
Same people claim to love boxing.
They got no idea what it is.
Boxing is about respect.
Getting it for yourself...
and taking it away
from the other guy.
I'll warm up the car.
Mr. Dunn?
I owe you money?
No, sir.
I know your mama?
I don't rightly know, sir.
Then what is it you want?
I was on the undercard. I won
my fight, too. Maggie Fitzgerald?
Well, Maggie Fitzgerald, what's up?
- Did you happen to see it?
- Nope.
I did pretty good.
Thought you might be interested
in training me.
I don't train girls.
Maybe you should. People see me
fight, say I'm pretty tough.
Girlie, tough ain't enough.
It's a mistake.
Car should be able
to back up, Frankie.
Just push, will ya?
- What did Hogan want?
- Offered us a title shot.
About time.
I turned him down flat.
Two or three more fights,
you'll be ready.
Been two or three more fights
for a long time now, Frankie.
Willie, you get
one shot at the title.
You lose it,
it may not come around again.
Now, two or three more fights
and we'll be ready.
Whatever you say, Frankie.
Frankie liked to say
that boxing is an unnatural act...
that everything in boxing
is backwards.
Sometimes...
best way to deliver a punch
is step back.
Well, do Your best, Lord...
protect Katy.
Annie, too.
Other than that...
You know what I want, there's
no use me repeating myself.
But step back too far,
you ain't fighting at all.
Bye.
Father, that was
a great sermon, made me weep.
What's confusing you this week?
Same old one.
God, three God thing.
Frankie, most people figure out
by kindergarten it's about faith.
Is it sort of like Snap, Crackle,
and Pop all rolled up in one big box?
You're standing outside my church
comparing God to Rice Krispies?
You come to mass every day to wind
me up. It won't happen this morning.
I'm confused.
- No, you aren't.
- Yes, I am.
Then here's your answer:
There's one God.
Anything else? Because I'm busy.
- What about the Holy Ghost?
- He's an expression of God's love.
- And Jesus?
- Son of God. Don't play stupid!
What is he, then?
Does that make him a demigod?
There are no demigods,
you fucking pagan!
- Did you write your daughter?
- Absolutely.
Now you're lying to a priest.
You know what? Take a day off,
don't come to mass tomorrow.
Some people'd say the most important
thing a fighter can have is heart.
Frankie'd say, "Show me a fighter
who's nothing but heart...
and I'll show you a man
waiting for a beating."
I think I only ever met
one fighter who was all heart.
My name's Dangerous Dillard Fightin'
Flippo Bam-Bam Barch...
out of Broward County, Texas!
Danger showed up
couple of years back.
He'd come visiting L.A. With
Ervel, his mama's new boyfriend.
Apparently Ervel got lost
and ended up back in Texas.
Danger looked for him for about
a week before he introduced himself.
You know, I gots nothin'
against niggers.
That's nice to hear.
Lotsa people
where I comes from does...
but my mama taught me
not to cause hurt to no man...
niggers or not.
You got a nice mama.
Anything else I can do for you?
Just one of those questions you ask,
but Danger wanted to give it
his best answer.
I'd likes to become the Welterweight
Champion of the world.
And I challenge
the Motor City Cobra...
Thomas "Hit Man" Hearns...
to fight me for the Welterweight
Championship of the whole world!
Yo, Flip, shut up, man!
You ain't even ranked.
You gotta have at least
one fight to be ranked.
I'll fight any man, anytime!
You a bad man, huh?
Get in the ring.
Go a round with me.
Shawrelle...
I will.
Leave him alone.
Danger, go on back to training.
Will do, Mist' Scrap!
Them some nice tights, Danger.
I'll give you that
ass-whuppin' later, Olive Oyl.
Those pants
look real pretty on you, bro.
Give his mama back her tights.
Shawrelle Berry had a left hook
that would move a tank...
but he had a heart
the size of a split pea.
Frankie bought the Hit Pit
from Bobby Malone 17 years ago.
Bobby wanted to move to Florida
and Frankie wanted some security.
Bobby died
while he was packing.
Frankie found out
most gyms lose money.
I thought I told you I didn't want
Danger working out here anymore.
He ain't hurting nothing, Frankie.
Well, he's hurting me.
Breaking my heart watching him punch
the air like it's gonna punch back.
And how many times have I gotta
tell you that bleach is bleach?
Why can't you buy the cheap stuff? You
don't have to buy the expensive stuff.
It smells better, Frankie.
Bleach smells like bleach!
- Hey, Scrap.
- Hey, Mr. Willie!
Nice fight last night.
- Big Willie!
- Hey, Sally.
Nice fight.
People are talking.
What the hell kind
of language is that?
What do you want?
I thought you might like to know
you got a fighter not talking
to another manager.
Not talking to another manager?
And not just any manager...
Mickey Mack.
You came in here to tell me that Big
Willie is not talking to Mickey Mack.
Not a word.
Neither one of them.
I'm trying to read here.
Well, if you think
that's more important.
Who's your new girl?
What?!
Jesus Christ.
Better hurry up. If she keeps hitting it
like that, she gonna break her wrists.
You're wasting your time.
I told you I don't train girls.
Thought you might change your mind.
Dozens of trainers train girls.
You won't have any trouble finding one.
Don't need a dozen, boss.
You'll do fine.
Don't call me boss, now. I'm not your
boss, and don't you be calling me that.
- Willie, you ready to work?
- Anytime.
If I stop calling you boss,
will you train me?
No.
Then I might as well
keep calling you it.
She came from
southwestern Missouri...
the hills outside the scratch-ass
Ozark town of Theodosia, set
in the cedars and oak trees somewhere
between nowhere and good-bye.
She grew up knowing one thing:
She was trash.
It's for my dog.
She'd come 1800 miles,
but Theodosia was still
just over the hill.
Working the bag, boss.
Not your boss.
And that bag's working you.
Give her her money back.
You sure?
- How much did she pay?
- Six months.
- Jesus Christ.
- No, I'll give it back.
No, don't be
a smart-ass now, will ya?
Woman thinks I'll throw away
six months' worth of dues...
just to get rid of her,
she's out of her mind.
But just don't encourage her,
understand?
And what's Danger doing
out there? What's he looking at?
Looks like a bottle of water.
He paid his dues?
Dues? Boy can't afford pants,
want him to pay dues?
Get out of my office.
Fuck me.
Can't think of it as a bag.
I'm not a trainer, but I can
show you this, if you'd like.
Appreciate any help I can get.
You want to think of it as a man,
see? He's constantly moving.
He's moving towards you,
around you, away from you.
All right?
Don't hit him when he's coming towards
you because he'll just push you back...
he'll smother your punches,
take your balance, right?
So, you watch him real carefully. Keep
rotating and keep your head moving...
and keep one shoulder back so you're
always ready to fire a power shot.
Go ahead, now. Good. Keep
rotating, keep moving. That's it.
Good, good.
Keep that chin tucked in.
Come on around.
Keep moving, keep moving.
- Good, good, good.
- Like that?
Yeah. Give it a few shots.
Tuck that chin in now.
Yeah, that's good.
That's good.
Now, you get this down,
we'll put you on the speed bag.
You do have a speed bag.
I'll just borrow it
till I can buy my own.
All right.
You go on home now.
- I'll walk out with you?
- I am home.
- Want to see?
- Yeah.
It's nice.
Would it bother you much
if I worked a little longer?
Nah, just pull the door closed
when you leave.
Thank you.
If there's magic in boxing...
it's the magic of fighting
battles beyond endurance...
beyond cracked ribs,
ruptured kidneys
and detached retinas.
It's the magic
of risking everything
for a dream
that nobody sees but you.
Okay. Watch the footwork!
That's it.
Hey, Flip.
Hey, Flippy, come here, man.
I think
I found somebody you can beat.
I don't fights women.
Why not, bro? It's perfect, bro.
You know why?
'Cause she, nah, you,
you could fight to him...
and then you could kiss to him.
Then fight one more time.
That's beautiful, man,
that's like poetry!
It's like poetry.
You been reading and shit.
That's a girl, man?
I think you right. Look at her little
titties. They're like mosquito bites.
Man, that's barely
even a mouthful.
Saw your last fight, Shawrelle.
Spent so much time face down,
I thought the canvas had titties.
Canvas has titties!
Look at me! I'm Shawrelle!
Just humping the canvas.
Humping the floor.
Come on, bro, the floor having
titties, that's funny, bro.
Shut up, man.
What you laughing at?
Man, hold the bag, stupid.
Yo, when they start making
those tights for men, Flippy?
Punk.
All right, that's enough
for the day.
I'll give you a rubdown.
I can't. My middle one's got a piano
lesson. I told Grace I'd drive her.
- Something wrong with Gracie's car?
- She hates that car.
Wants the old one back, but
the dealer already got a buyer.
Maybe I should talk
to the dealer.
I'd appreciate that.
Okay.
Thanks.
See you later.
The man's a rubdown whore
and today he doesn't want one?
You ever do any work
around here?
Not my job I'd worry about,
if I was you.
Little girl seems
to be coming along.
Yeah. It's almost like
somebody's been helping her.
She might just be a natural.
Looks like she's got something.
She's got my speed bag,
that's what she's got!
I wonder how the hell she got that.
I wonder.
I'm gonna need
that speed bag back.
- This bag?
- Yes, that bag. That's my bag.
If you're hitting it, people
will think I'm training you.
Is that such a bad thing, boss?
Yes, it is. Every time you touch it,
you're losing me business out here.
I gotta agree,
I am embarrassing myself.
Well, I can't just lend it
to anybody, you know?
I understand.
Look, you seem
like a nice girl.
- Can I give you some advice?
- I'd appreciate that.
You'll find a trainer here or elsewhere
that will want to train a girl.
It's the latest
freak show out there.
The only trouble is they'll be wasting
your time because you're too old.
I don't feel that old.
Neither do I, but you don't see me
fighting 21-year-olds, do you?
Takes about four years
to train a fighter.
How old are you?
31 until my next birthday.
There you go. 31.
You wouldn't start training to be
a ballerina at 31, would you?
Already been working it
for three years.
And you can't hit a speed bag?
What kind of training is that?
I've never had any, boss.
I hate to say it, but it shows.
Somebody's gotta
be honest with you.
I hate to be the one
to tell you the truth.
Yeah.
Sorry for using
your bag, Mr. Dunn.
You're not
gonna cry now, are you?
No, sir.
Here.
- Keep the goddamn thing.
- No, you need it.
No, take the bag.
I haven't seen it
in 20 years anyway.
I've had three since then.
Just enjoy it, will you?
I'll just borrow it
till I buy my own.
Just don't lose it.
Yeah, I know, Hogan, your guy's
the champ, so we don't split fifties...
but if I don't see
forty percent...
Call me back when it's sixty-forty
or don't call me back at all.
Hey, Willie?
Hey, Frankie.
Is something wrong?
Sorry to come to your house like this, I
know you don't like people dropping in.
You're not people, Willie,
you're welcome anytime.
Thank you for getting
Grace's car back.
You don't have to thank me.
Paying an extra thousand dollars
for your own car ain't exactly a favor.
Gracie broke out and cried
when she saw it.
Really?
I also needed to talk
with you about business.
I just got off the phone with Hogan.
We're all set for September.
Everything but the split.
I gotta leave you, Frankie.
What?
Willie, the title is just
two fights away.
It ain't that. It's like
you said, I got one shot.
If I win, I gotta make
as much as I can while I can.
I need somebody in the action,
who can make things happen.
And I gotta make the change
before the fight.
Only way this guy say he'd take me
is if he took me to the title.
So, I get you the title fight,
and this guy takes you there?
Only way he'd do it!
I'm sorry, Frankie. I know how long
you've been waiting on a title.
I wish it could've been with me.
Mickey Mack's a business man.
He can't teach you nothing.
You already taught me
everything I need to know.
There's some things that people
just don't want to hear.
And I challenge
the Motor City Cobra
Thomas Hit Man Hearns...
to fight me for the Welterweight
Championship of the whole world!
Danger, I'm wearing
these mitts for a reason.
Just working
on my footwork, Mist' Scrap.
Danger, you throw a punch
or get the hell out of this gym.
Danger, while you thinking about
that punch, I'll be right back.
I'm thinking how I'm gonna
hit it hard for you, Mist' Scrap!
No one had the heart
to tell Danger
that Hearn had retired years ago.
I heard about Willie.
That's cold, man,
that's dead cold.
Course, it wouldn't be so bad
if you weren't so damn old.
At least I can see
through both eyes.
Didn't do you a lot
of good though, did it?
Well, I've got the gym.
Don't need to be training
fighters at my age.
Willie tell you why?
It was Mickey.
Mickey's got the connections.
Nah, it ain't about connections.
It's about you not believing in him.
I found him, I stuck with him
for eight years.
How's that
for not believing in him?
You could've got him a title fight
two years ago. Hell, he knew that.
I'm amazed
he stayed around this long.
Getting there and taking home
the belt are two different things.
What was I supposed to do? Just put
him in over his head, not protect him?
You were protecting him
from the championship.
Yeah.
Well, now it makes sense.
What about you, Scrap?
What did your manager do?
You were a hell of a fighter,
a lot better than Willie.
He get you a title fight...
or did he bust you out banging your
head against other people's fists...
until you lost your eye?
I had my shot.
I went out swinging
and no man can say I didn't.
I remember.
Excuse me if I didn't want my fighter
spending the second half of his life...
cleaning up other people's spit.
Yeah, you're right. You're the smart
one. You're the one learning Greek.
It's Gaelic.
You just protected yourself
out of a championship fight.
How do you say that in Gaelic?
Thanks.
The action continues as the Champ
is battling Big Willie Jones...
and commanding him
with rights and lefts.
Up against the ropes, he's...
Boxing is an unnatural act.
'Cause everything in it
is backwards.
You want to move to the left,
you don't step left...
you push on the right toe.
To move right,
you use your left toe.
Instead of running from the pain,
like a sane person would do...
you step into it.
So Big Willie comes back...
He hits the champ with
a right hand and the champ is down.
The Ref is into the count
and Big Willie Jones
is the new champion of the world!
It's unbelievable how this
has taken place tonight...
but there you have it,
folks, a new champion.
Everything in boxing
is backwards.
Want a cheeseburger?
You bought me a cheeseburger? I never
seen you buy anybody a cheeseburger.
I couldn't eat it and
I ordered it. You want it?
I guess the planet
can go back to spinning.
You watch the fight?
Yeah, I watched it.
Willie did good.
That's what you got to say?
Well, he won, didn't he?
He did good.
I see you been working on yourself,
learning to open up. Good work.
You watch it?
Yeah, I got HBO.
How can you afford HBO?
How long have I been telling you
to save your money?
Since I fought
Louis "Typhoon" Johnson
at the Stadium Club
in Tupelo, Mississippi.
That true?
Manager ran off and left
you and me to hitch home...
don't you remember nothing?
I remember walking halfway,
thinking I was gonna be lynched.
I remember you leaving me with my
dick in my hand behind that gas station.
I got a ride. The guy took off
before I hardly closed the door.
I had to walk back two miles.
Your conscience got the better
of you, that's what.
What the hell's that?
It's her birthday.
You're not breathing right.
That's why you're panting.
So, it's your birthday, huh?
How old does that make you?
I'm 32, Mr. Dunn, and I'm here
celebrating the fact...
that I spent another year
scraping dishes and waitressing...
which is what
I been doing since 13.
And according to you, I'll be 37 before
I can even throw a decent punch...
which after working this speed bag
for a month and getting nowhere...
I now realize
may be God's simple truth.
Other truth is, my brother's in prison,
my sister cheats on welfare...
by pretending one
of her babies is still alive...
my daddy's dead
and my mama weighs 312 pounds.
If I was thinking straight,
I'd go back home...
find a used trailer,
buy a deep fryer and some Oreos.
Problem is, this is the only
thing I ever felt good doing.
If I'm too old for this,
then I got nothing.
That enough truth to suit you?
This your speed bag?
Put yours behind the counter.
Wish I could say I wore it out.
Just hold it. Hold it.
I'll show you a few things,
and then we'll get you a trainer.
No, sorry.
You're in a position
to negotiate?
Yes, sir, because I know if you
train me right, I'm going to be a champ.
I seen you looking at me.
Yeah, out of pity.
Don't you say that! Don't you
say that if it ain't true!
I want a trainer.
I don't want charity,
and I don't want favors.
If you're not interested, then
I got more celebrating to do.
Stop, stop, stop.
Goddamn it, stop.
What the hell are you doing?
Okay.
If I'm going to take you on...
You won't never regret it.
Listen to me.
If I take you on...
I promise I'll work so hard.
God, this is a mistake already.
I'm listening, boss.
If I take you on, you don't say
anything, you don't question me.
You don't ask, "Why?" You don't say
anything except maybe "Yes, Frankie."
And I'm going to try to forget
the fact that you're a girl.
It's all I ask.
And don't come crying to me
if you get hurt.
- All rightey.
- We got a deal.
No, not quite.
I'll teach you how to fight...
then we'll get you a manager
and I'm off down the road.
- I hate to argue with you but...
- That's the only way we're doing it.
I teach you all you need to know and
you go off and make a million dollars.
Get your teeth knocked out, I don't
care. I don't want to hear about it.
That's the way it's going to be.
It's the only way I'll do it.
All right.
One of the things I've noticed around
the gym is you never move your feet.
You stand therejust flatfooted.
You've got to move your feet.
That's one of the best things
I'll be able to teach you.
So, here's what you do.
Get yourself,
bend your knees a little bit.
Get in an athletic position. Look
like you're going to hit something.
Move them how, boss?
Hit the bag.
- Stop.
- What'd I do wrong?
You did two things wrong.
One is you asked a question and
two is you asked another question.
Now, what I want you to do
it's not about hitting it hard,
it's how good you hit it.
So, watch me. You can count
with me if you want.
On a one count, I hit
right through the bag.
Can you show me that again?
Just say one, please.
One.
Okay. Yeah, just say one,
that's good.
Then I move over to my right foot.
My weight is shifting to my right foot.
Then I hit it with my back of my hand,
like I'm chipping ice with an ice pick.
Then I come over and
I shift to my left foot...
and I hit it with my right hand...
and ice pick maneuver again...
and I come over on my right foot,
and hit it right, left.
Don't watch anything
but my feet.
Just do it like that.
Just keep practicing.
You show them how to stand, keep
their legs under their shoulders.
To make a fighter, you got
to strip them down to bare wood.
Rest when you're dead.
Come here.
You can't just tell them
to forget everything you know...
because you got to make them
forget it in their bones.
Make them so tired they only listen
to you, only hear your voice...
only do what you say,
and nothing else.
Move your feet around,
let's see you go.
Show them how to keep their balance
and take it away from the other guy.
Not so low. Look at me.
How to generate momentum
off your right toe...
and how to flex your knees
when you fire a jab.
How to fight backing up, so the other
guy doesn't want to come after you.
Then you got to show them all
over again. Over and over and over.
Till they think
they were born that way.
Shift. Shift away.
Okay, that's enough for today.
Good work. Good girl.
Think I'm ready for a fight, boss?
Come here.
You're not breathing.
Hate to disagree with you.
Every time you get under pressure,
you're holding your breath.
Now stop doing that.
But other than that,
I'm doing pretty good, right?
I mean, for a girl.
I don't train girls.
You think I might be ready
for a fight, boss?
We'll get a manager
and we'll find out, won't we?
I'd like to but you've been
keeping me too busy.
- Got any family, boss?
- What?
You been spending all this time
with me. I didn't know if you had any.
No.
Well, I've got a daughter. Katy.
That's family.
We're not exactly close.
How much she weigh?
What?
Trouble in my family
comes by the pound.
Not very big.
Used to be real athletic,
don't know if she kept it up.
So, what do you think?
I ready for a fight?
Hey, Sally.
Come here for a minute, will you?
Frankie? I need to see you
in the back for a minute, okay?
Can I see you a minute?
Sally here's a real good manager.
Has a couple of Golden Glove boys.
Looking for a girl, Sally?
I'm looking for a good one.
Well, see, there you go.
Nice working with you, girlie.
- What'd you want?
- Nothing.
I ain't lying, I been watching
you work. You got a hell of a left.
Thank you.
You want to give this a try,
see if it's a fit?
Yeah, sure.
Good, because I think
you're ready for a fight.
Break!
What am I doing wrong? Every
time I get inside, she's on me.
You're doing great. You're
wearing her down, just keep punching.
I ain't doing great.
I'm losing.
You're wearing her down.
Nice night, ain't it?
Jesus Christ.
That's Lonnie Washington's girl.
Hell of a fighter. 11-0.
Your left. Keep your left up.
Lonnie's got a lot of good fighters.
He's got Joey Adagio,
lightweight champ?
Your left, damn it.
Wouldn't have been my choice for a
first fight, but Sally's a good manager.
He must think she can take her.
Your left! Keep your left up.
You think she can
hear you from back here?
Of course, if Maggie loses,
it wouldn't mean anything to Sally.
Might even help him.
Lonnie's girl gets another win...
Lonnie might let Sally's lightweight
fight Joey Adagio for the title.
Sally's trying to set
a fight with Adagio?
Hey, what do I know? Ljust
come because I enjoy the fights.
Mother of God.
Okay, break!
Come here.
Get over here!
You're dropping your left hand.
Quit dropping your left hand.
You mind if I talk to my fighter?
You're doing a hell of a job. Is this
the way you advise your lightweight?
- Dunn, what the hell are you doing?
- I'm talking. What are you doing?
- Is this your fighter?
- It's my fighter!
It ain't fitting real well, Sally.
Fine. You take her.
She can't fight worth a shit anyway.
Somebody tell me what's going on!
I was late.
Sally was subbing for me.
This is your fighter?
Yeah. This is my fighter.
Then you got ten seconds!
I keep holding my left up, then
I throw a punch and it keeps dropping.
- Well, let it drop.
- That'd be a lot easier.
She thinks she knows you. Every time
you drop it she comes over the top.
So you just wait for her, see?
That's all she's thinking about.
And when she cocks
that big right hand...
I hear you.
Step to the side and come over
with a big good night hook.
Got it right here.
Fight or I'm calling it!
Go give it to her!
The body knows what fighters don't,
how to protect itself.
A neck can only twist so far.
Twist it just a hair more
and the body says:
I'll take it from here, because you
obviously don't know what you're doing.
See the way she did that?
Sugar Ray would do that.
Girl's got sugar.
"Lie down, now,
rest and we'll talk
about thiswhen
you regain your senses."
It's called the knockout mechanism.
Don't get carried away, now.
You did good.
Thanks, boss.
You forgot the rule.
Now, what is the rule?
Keep my left up?
It's to protect yourself
at all times.
Now, what is the rule?
Protect myself at all times.
Good.
You gave me away.
How was that protecting me?
It wasn't.
It's okay.
I'll work on my left, boss.
Drink your water.
Other than that, how'd I do?
Fine. You did fine.
You going to leave me again?
Never.
That place you work, do they
have homemade lemon meringue pie?
Sure.
Not with the canned filling crap?
Big can, yea size.
Says "homemade" on the label.
I want you to take the weekend off.
It's only Thursday.
You going to argue with me?
Know better
than to do that, boss.
Good.
All fighters are pig-headed
some way or other.
Some part of them always thinks they
know better than you about something.
Can you spare a few minutes
for the lmmaculate Conception?
Truth is, even if they're wrong...
even if that one thing is going
to be the ruin of them...
if you can beat that last bit out of
them, then they ain't fighters at all.
Thought I said
I'd see you Monday.
You sure did, boss.
That was last night.
You said not to argue with you.
Damn woman won't do
a thing I tell her.
You want my advice?
What?
Where are your shoes?
I'm airing out my feet.
You got big holes in your socks.
They're not that big.
Didn't I give you money
for some new ones?
These are my sleeping socks.
My feet like
a little air at night.
How come you're wearing them
in the daytime, then?
Because my daytime socks
got too many holes in them.
Well, if I give you
some more money.
You buy some new socks
Please?
Well, I'd be tempted,
but I couldn't say for sure.
Might find its way to the track.
It's over! It's over!
Didn't take Maggie long
to hit her stride.
I got the breathing thing down.
No, you ain't breathing, because you're
knocking them out in the first round.
Thought that was the point.
The point is to get good.
Can't get good if you keep
knocking them out in the first round.
How am I going to get you fights?
Nobody wants to see
their fighter embarrassed.
Why am I still doing
four-rounders, boss?
You haven't got
the lungs for six rounds.
I do if I keep knocking them
out in the first round.
Frankie made her fight
one more four-rounder...
just to let her know who was boss.
Sorry, boss.
Maggie left no doubt about it.
All right!
Her first six-rounder
didn't go quite as smooth.
To your corner!
Three, four,
five,
six, seven...
eight, nine, ten! It's over!
Maggie didn't knock her out
till the end of the first round.
After that, no manager wanted
to put his fighter in with Maggie.
Frankie had to go into his pocket
to get her decent fights...
sweetening the purse by paying
managers on the side.
That only worked for so long.
Then Frankie did something
he hated doing.
He took a chance.
He moved her up in class.
That could've been a mistake.
Break! Step back! Break!
Time!
Damn, damn, damn.
I'm all right.
Give us two seconds, will you?
Just two seconds.
Your nose is broke.
- Dang! Fix it.
- I can't.
You can fix it.
I can't.
I've got to call it.
I've seen what you can do!
Fix it!
I can snap it back into place,
but I can't stop the bleeding.
The ring doctor's
going to call it.
Please, Frankie. If you
can stop the blood I can beat her.
Bite down on this.
Inhale.
- What?
- Inhale.
Breathe in!
Okay, huh?
Yeah, it's okay.
You got 20 seconds before this turns
into a geyser and sprays the front row.
20 seconds, that's all you've got.
Now get going.
Go to your corner!
Two, three, four, five...
six, seven,
eight...
nine, ten!
Mo Cuishle.
Whatcha reading?
What's she saying?
Wants to know what you're reading.
It's Yeats.
Keep your head back.
Why don't you talk a little Yeats
to her? Show her what a treat that is.
When the hell
they going to get to her?
I'm okay, Frankie.
- What'd you learn tonight?
- Always protect myself.
- What's the rule?
- Margaret Fitzgerald?
- Here!
I'll be right here.
How you doing?
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
I'm not the one who's hurt.
- Broken nose don't hurt that much.
- Why are you telling me that?
No reason.
But some wounds are too deep
or too close to the bone.
And no matter how hard you work
at it, you just can't stop the bleeding.
Did you write your daughter?
Every week.
I've no idea
why you come to church.
After her 12th straight knockout,
Frankie got a couple real good offers.
The first was to fight Billie
"The Blue Bear" Osterman...
for the WBAwelterweight title.
Billie was a former prostitute
out of East Berlin.
Had a reputation for being
the dirtiest fighter in the ranks.
Didn't seem to matter to her that
something like that could kill a person.
And the crowds loved her.
He turned it down
without even telling her.
The next was to fight the British
champ, a Jamaican girl Billie just beat.
Hello?
Not interested.
He turned that down, too.
That's a lot of money, boss.
You're making money. What
are you still working here for?
It's a title match, right?
Are you British? It's a title
you can't take away.
She's got nothing to lose.
You got nothing to win.
Might still be a good fight.
Yeah. I just brought you up
to welterweight.
Too good to fight these contenders,
you'd rather fight some bullshit champ?
Didn't notice
I was fighting any contenders.
You can get yourself
another manager any time you want.
In fact, if you'd learn to protect
your face a little better...
I wouldn't have
to turn down this money.
My face out there so much it's a
miracle I ain't been knocked out yet.
No, you can't work here
anymore tonight.
I made us a reservation.
You might want to shower.
Here you go.
What's this?
It ain't no big secret
what you're wishing for.
Go on and blow.
Thank you.
33 ain't so old.
I was still fighting at 39.
Fought for 23 years.
How's it going, Scrap?
Doing good, Mickey.
Doing good.
- What will you have?
- Coffee.
You two not speaking?
Don't hardly know him.
I met Frankie
right after my 37th birthday.
He was picking up cut work.
He used to patch me up
when I thought it was impossible.
Good man to have in your corner.
Yes, he is.
He stayed with me through
my last fight in San Berdu.
My manager was off
getting drunk somewhere...
and it was just Frankie and me.
I was taking a hellacious beating.
Everybody's got a particular
number of fights in them.
Nobody tells you
what that number is.
Mine was a 109.
I just didn't want to admit it.
Fourth round...
this cut opens up.
Blood starts pouring
into my eye.
They should've stopped
the fight, but, hell...
I was a black man in San Berdu,
blood was what I was there for.
Round after round, I kept
getting Frankie to patch me up.
He's talking about
throwing in the towel...
but he ain't my manager,
he can't throw in nothing.
Round after round...
he's arguing with me.
I'm almost laughing because, hell,
it's getting more to him than to me.
I go 15 rounds...
Iose by decision.
Next morning,
I lose the eye.
In 23 years, he's never said
a thing about it.
Doesn't have to. I can see it
in his face every time he looks at me.
Somehow Frankie thinks
he should've stopped that fight...
should've saved my eye.
Spends his life wishing
he could take back that 109th fight.
I wanted to go to 110.
Thing is...
if you want to get to the title...
maybe he's not the one
to take you there.
You tell Mr. Mack
we'd be here tonight?
Eat your cupcake.
No, I got it.
It's the rule.
Always protect yourself.
People never take
their own advice.
If she was going to leave Frankie,
better she did it to him then.
Mr. Mickey Mack?
I'm Maggie Fitzgerald.
I hear you're a real good manager.
Doing good things for Big Willie.
But I thought you should know
I ain't never leaving Mr. Dunn...
so you don't need to make
any more excuses to bump into me.
Sorry for interrupting
your dinner.
Maggie always did like taking
them out in the first round.
The letters always came back
marked the same way...
"Return to Sender."
I will make you some coffee.
What are you doing
with your money?
Saving it.
Good girl.
You save enough of it, you ought
to get yourself a little house.
Cash, no mortgage.
It'll be a while
before I can do that.
It might be a stretch, but you got
to get yourself a place of your own.
Go around wasting it on things that
don't matter and what do you got?
You understand?
Pretty soon, you wait
long enough, you got nothing.
Okay, soon as I get the money.
I made a lot of mistakes in my life. I'm
trying to keep you from doing the same.
I know, boss.
I'm not going to live forever.
What is it?
A tape on that girl
in England you'll fight.
If you're going to go for
the title, we got some moves to...
Get the hell down.
You know how old I am?
Thank you, boss.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome, darling.
Now let me put this in the machine.
What machine?
Don't have a TV, huh?
No.
Yeah!
All right. Okay.
- Ten minutes, luv.
- Thank you.
Man says he loves me.
He's probably not
the first one to say that.
First since my daddy.
I win, you think he'll propose?
You win, I'll propose.
I've got you a gift here.
I think they gave you
somebody else's.
No. This is it.
What does it mean?
I don't know.
It's something in Gaelic.
It's beautiful.
I thought so.
Real silk thread.
From the United States
of America,
the challenger...
Maggie Fitzgerald!
Did you see what was on her robe?
Yeah, Mo Cuishle.
Mo Cuishle!
She wasn't the main attraction.
She was on the undercard
of a middleweight title fight.
But ask someone who was there...
they couldn't tell you
who else fought that night.
Box!
Mo Cuishle! Mo Cuishle!
She's tough.
I can't get inside. I can't
get close enough to hit her.
- You know why that is?
- Why?
She's a better fighter than you are.
She's younger, she's stronger,
and she's more experienced.
Now, what are you going
to do about it?
Get in there.
Box!
Four, five, six...
seven, eight, nine, ten!
Mo Cuishle!
I could ask someone, you know?
Good.
You find out,
you let me know.
Whatever it meant,
the name stuck.
Maggie fought in Edinburgh
and Paris, Brussels and Amsterdam.
It was always "Mo cuishle".
Seems there're Irish people
everywhere, or people who want to be.
By the time
they came back to the States...
Maggie was in a whole new league.
Mo cuishle! Mo cuishle!
After that they got another
offer to fight for the title.
What's the split?
- 60-40.
- Good.
We'll take sixty and you take forty,
being as that Maggie's the draw.
That little girl?
You think I'm wrong, really?
You think people are saying
that they want to see
some scabby Kraut beat up
on little Miss What's-her-name?
You find someone who says that
and we'll take the forty.
There you go.
They're at 60-40, but
they'll come up to 50-50.
How's that girl doing?
She's got a concussion
and a broken eardrum.
She be all right?
And if she isn't?
Maybe I should send her something?
Well, you could send her your check,
if you'd like. I'm sure she'd take it.
Boss?
That little house we talked about?
I bought it.
Well, smart girl.
For my mama.
It's only about a mile
from where she lives now.
No mortgage,
just like you said.
You're a good daughter.
She don't know about it yet.
I was hoping maybe we could stay
an extra day, drive over there?
I know she wants to meet you.
Yeah. We could do that.
Oh, my God.
Mama, come on out here.
Mary M's here.
This is the Johnson's old house.
Not anymore.
It's all yours, Mama! For you
and Mardell and the kids!
Mary M, you bought this for me?
Yeah, all yours,
free and clear!
Darling...
There's no fridge.
No stove, neither.
They'll be here
before you move in.
- How much money did this cost you?
- You never mind that.
- You shouldn't a done this.
- You need a decent place.
You shouldn't a done it!
You should've asked me first!
Government's gonna find out about
this house, they'll stop my welfare.
Mama, no, they ain't.
You're fine, you're working, but
I can't live without my welfare.
Mama, I send you money.
What about my medicine?
Medicaid going to cut me off.
How am I supposed
to get my medicine?
I'll send you more money.
Hope you don't expect J.D. To move
in here with us. He's getting out.
Why didn't you just give me the money?
Why'd you have to buy me a house?
Didn't have to, Mama.
But it's yours.
You want the money, sell it.
I know you didn't mean nothing hurtful,
but you just don't think things through.
That's true, Mama.
I'll try and keep the house.
I just worry about all those expenses.
I'll send you some more money.
That man hitting you?
It's from the fight.
I'm a fighter, Mama.
Find a man, Mary M.
Live proper.
People hear about what
you're doing and they laugh.
Hurts me to tell you,
but they laugh at you.
- You ever own a dog?
- Nope.
Closest I ever came was
a middleweight from Barstow.
My daddy had
a German shepherd, Axel.
Axel's hindquarters were so bad...
he had to drag himself
room to room by his front legs.
Me and Mardell'd bust up laughing,
watching him...
scoot across the kitchen floor.
Daddy, he was so sick by then,
he couldn't hardly stand himself.
But one morning he got up
and carried Axel to his rig...
and the two of them went off
into the woods, singing and howling.
Wasn't till he got home
that night, alone, that I saw
the shovel in the back
of the truck.
Sure miss watching
the two of them together.
I got nobody but you, Frankie.
Well, you've got me.
At least, that is,
until we find you a good manager.
Hey, can we stopjust up here?
Yeah.
This place has
the best lemon pie around.
None of that canned filling crap.
Now I can die and go to heaven.
I used to come here with Daddy.
Wonder if a place like this
is for sale.
I got a little bit of savings.
That's fine. Fine, thanks.
What the hell's Danger
looking at?
Looks like another
bottle of water.
Want to come to Vegas with us?
Watch you suffer
over the nickel slots.
My heart can't take
that kind of pounding.
Well, she's got a title shot.
The Blue Bear.
Million dollars,
split right down the center.
That's good, Frankie.
That's real good.
I could use a good second. Can't
find one, I thought I'd ask you.
Why the hell
would I want to do that?
Because you're a half-blind old fool
who never got there himself.
Thought you might like to feel what it's
like to be in a ring on a title match.
Excuse me for feeling
sorry for you.
No, you pick up somebody
there in Vegas.
Somebody with young hands.
You're not going to cry now,
are you? I've already got one girl.
No, I leave this place
for one day...
got any idea what it would look
like when I come back?
Kind of like
it looks right now.
Go to hell.
Tell Maggie don't come back
without a belt.
Will do.
Mr. Scrap.
I got a question, but I feel
real stupid asking it.
No such thing as a stupid
question there, Danger.
How'd you get all the ice in here
through this little tiny hole?
I been thinking on it.
Can't figure it out.
Why don't I show you, Danger?
You could show me?
I think so.
Also, Mr. Scrap, I was kind of
thinking I might be ready for a fight?
You do, do you?
Well, I got the tickets.
You ready?
We're flying?
Would you rather drive?
You're asking me?
Would you rather fly
or would you rather drive?
So I finally get
to decide something?
That's what I'm saying.
Fine.
Fly there, drive back.
That's the stupidest thing I've ever
heard. How are we going to do that?
You said it was up to me.
Give them hell there, Danger.
Hey, old school,
the toilet's overflowing.
Hey, Flippy,
come here for a minute.
Jesus.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
Dumb-ass.
- Come on, Danger!
- Come on! Defense!
Could be sitting up at
The Mirage, drinking mai tais...
Iooking at naked women.
Come on, Danger,
put up your hands and fight.
Fight back! Come on!
There you go, Danger,
there you go!
Come on, now, Flip!
What you doing? Let him go!
I've gotcha now.
It's all right.
We don't need no corner trainer!
How'd I do, Mr. Scrap?
You did good, Danger.
You my man. You rock.
Come on, Flip. You ain't done.
You ain't even fight good yet.
Anybody can lose
one fight, son.
You'll come back from this,
you'll be champion of the world.
No, I won't, Mr. Scrap.
I should've knowed.
Let's go, man,
we don't need this honky.
- Let me help you.
- Naw, I can do her.
Just untie the Velcro for me.
Don't take the gloves off, man.
You ain't even used them, Danger.
Mind if I borrow these, Danger?
Man, I thought your name was Danger?
Come on, now.
Now I get to fight
a retard and a old man.
Call ESPN, 'cause
you can't write this shit!
110.
Get a job, punk.
Win this one and
I'll tell you what it means.
I got you some pipers.
Mo Cuishle! Mo Cuishle!
I want you to jab her right in the tits,
until they turn blue and fall off.
Ladies and gentlemen, this
is the feature presentation
of the evening.
In this corner,
the challenger,
Maggie Fitzgerald,
in the red corner.
In the blue corner,
the WBAWelterweight
champion of the world...
Billie "The Blue Bear".
Sweet Jesus.
Fitzgerald is pushing the Blue Bear
around the ring, coming on strong.
Challenger darts in, lands
a combination to the head and the body.
And a right hook
stuns the champ!
Break it up!
Break it!
Do that one more time, it'll
cost you a point, do you hear me?
Go fight.
What the fuck is that?
That's it.
I'm going to take away a point.
One point deduction
off the blue corner.
Ref, open your eyes!
The first round is in the books
on this championship match.
Looking good.
You pull that crap one
more time, you're disqualified.
It's going to be all right.
Got no doubt, boss.
You just watch yourself.
Stay away from this dame.
Go on.
Go to the neutral corner!
4, 5, 6...
Stay down, bitch.
7, 8, 9...
Break it up!
Break it!
Fitzgerald continues to pummel
the East German Champion...
I got it.
Eyes are blurring, boss.
- How many eyes you need to fight?
- One's enough.
Now, what do I do about the Bear?
Do you know that step into
the outside and hook into the liver?
I been doing that.
She's made of steel.
Don't go to the liver this time,
hit her right up
under her skinny ass.
Right in the sciatic nerve.
Just keep digging it in there.
Keep sticking her.
You hear that?
What about the Ref?
Keep yourself between the Ref and
the Bear and everything will be fine.
This is you.
Break!
Get the doctor!
Come on. Breathe.
That's it. Breathe.
Good.
Look at me.
Concentrate on me.
Breathe. Good.
That's it.
How you feeling, darling?
Growing a beard, boss?
Yeah, I thought it might
help me with the ladies.
Can't say it does.
Does it hurt much?
Don't hurt at all.
Well, that's good.
Where's Frankie?
Well, he's out there
talking to the doctors.
Probably telling them
how to do their job.
They're telling him
I'm a C1 and C2 complete.
Means that my spinal cord's so broke
they'll never be able to fix it.
Going to be frozen like this
the rest of my life.
I asked them to tell him. I don't
know how he's going to take it.
Did you see the fight?
Course I did.
You had her cold, Maggie.
I shouldn't a dropped my hands.
I shouldn't a turned.
Always protect myself,
how many times he tell me that?
Yeah.
Does like to repeat himself.
Will you tell him I'm real sorry?
No.
I won't do no such thing, Maggie.
Damnedest thing.
So, what's the plan?
I know you got one, so you
might as well tell me what it is.
It's your fault.
Yeah, it's your fault
she's lying in there like that.
You kept after me
until I trained her.
I knew I shouldn't have done it.
Her being a girl and all.
Everything kept telling me
not to. Everything but you.
I'm going to get you out of here.
These doctors around here
don't know squat.
Otherwise why would they
be living out here in the desert?
As soon as you're able
to be moved...
we'll find someplace where
they've actually studied medicine.
You just rest there.
I'm on it.
Frankie must've called
every hospital in America...
Iooking for somebody who'd
tell him they could fix her.
He came close twice till
they checked her over...
said there was nothing
to be done.
Took two months till she was
stable enough to move.
They got nurses
for that, you know.
Yeah, they're amateurs.
She developed skin ulcers
because she couldn't change positions.
Thank you.
They made the six-hour trip
by ambulance.
Fly there, drive back.
The rehab center Frankie found
was a nice place.
They took good care of Maggie. She
wouldn't have complained if they hadn't.
Took several hours every day
to get her ready for the wheelchair.
One, two, three.
Since she couldn't breathe on her
own, her respirators were always on.
Oxygen was pumped into her
24 hours a day.
Maggie's mama called to say
they were all coming for a visit.
She waited by the window
every day for the next two weeks.
Frankie finally tracked them down
learned they'd checked
into their hotel six days earlier.
Kept leaving messages,
which were never returned.
You don't have
to hang around all day.
I like it here. I don't mind.
Fact, if you weren't here, I'd
come here anyway to read my books.
Mama will be here soon,
share some of the burden.
Well, it's no burden.
Here...
read this.
Okay, okay, that's enough.
That's terrible.
Anyway, I'll tell you
in English what you were saying.
It says:
"I will arise and go now,
and go to Innisfree.
And a small cabin build there,
of clay and wattles made.
And I shall have some peace there,
for peace comes dropping slow.
Dropping from the veils of the morning,
to where the cricket sings."
Not bad, huh?
You going to build
a cabin, boss?
Me?
You know,
when you quit all this.
You mean boxing?
No. I'll never quit.
Like the stink too much,
I guess.
You think? I could see you there, real
easy, with your books and lemon pie.
How about you? Would you like
to go live in a cabin?
I could learn how to bake.
Well, then,
maybe I'll start looking.
Yeah.
I'm Frankie Dunn.
I met you back out in Missouri.
Where's my little girl?
Don't you think you ought
to go back to the hotel and change?
She doesn't know you've been here
a week visiting Woody and Mickey.
We got business with my sister. Why
don't you just tell us where she is?
You must be J.D. And you
must be the business guy?
There's some rides you missed. Go on
back, I'll tell her you couldn't make it.
I drove all the way here
to take care of my child
and you're suggesting
I'm not a good mother?
Mary M can't go nowhere.
If we could have taken her
to Disneyland we would have.
Margaret Fitzgerald?
Right down here. 301.
- Come on, Mama.
- Let's go.
I saw myself breathing!
My body was going up and down.
I thought,
"Why didn't somebody tell me?!"
Your hair needs washing.
It's kinda greasy.
It's just some kind of legal thing.
What is it?
How we all doing here?
Sorry, darling,
but we ain't got a lotta time.
Mr. Johnson's charging us a lot to be
here to make sure this is done proper.
Leave that and
I'll read it to her later.
Hey, old man...
you part of our family?
Stay the hell out of this.
Read it to me, Mama.
It'sjust something legal...
to protect your money.
Mama, you don't have to worry.
The Boxing Commission's paying
for all this. Everything.
But what if they don't, Mary M?
Mr. Johnson says
they can take my house.
If you assign your assets to her,
no one will be able to touch them.
No doctors, no funeral expenses.
Nothing.
Why don't you just leave it and then
I'll just read it to her later on?
Mr. Dunn, with respect,
this isn't your business.
I'll be out in the hall.
You been a good daughter, Mary M.
You sign that paper, it'll
take care of your family...
the way your daddy
would have wanted you to.
How do you make your mark?
Can you hold a pen?
She gotta do it
with her teeth, Mama.
You gotta put it in her mouth.
Here you go, honey.
Did you see the fight, Mama?
Honey, you know
how I feel about that.
I did pretty good.
You lost, Mary M.
Ain't your fault, the way
I heard it, but you lost.
Don't want to lose the rest
of what you got left.
There you go.
What happened to you?
What's that supposed to mean?
Mama, you take Mardell
and J.D. And get home.
Before I tell that lawyer there that you
were so worried about your welfare
you never signed those house papers
like you were supposed to.
So, any time I feel like it,
I can sell that house from under
your fat, lazy, hillbilly asses.
And if you ever come back,
that's exactly what I'll do.
Well, maybe someone
ought to count to ten.
Don't smell real pretty,
does it, Doc?
We might have to lose it,
Maggie.
They took my leg, boss.
It's gonna be all right.
You hear?
I always hear your voice, boss.
You need anything?
I need to know
what Mo Cuishle means.
Well, you didn't win.
I don't have to tell you.
You're the meanest man
I ever met,
no wonder no one loves you.
You remind me of my daddy.
Well, he must have been
a very intelligent,
handsome man.
You ain't gonna make me
talk no more Yeats, are you?
No, I was...
Iooking at this catalog
from City College.
I thought I'd get you
a wheelchair...
maybe the kind that operates
by blowing through a straw.
I thought maybe you'd like
to go back to school.
I got a favor to ask you, boss.
Sure.
Anything you want.
Remember what my daddy
did for Axel?
Don't even think about that.
I can't be like this, Frankie.
Not after what I've done.
I seen the world.
People chanted my name.
Well...
not my name,
some damn name you gave me...
but they were chanting for me.
I was in magazines.
You think I ever dreamed
that'd happen?
I was born at two pounds,
one-and-a-half ounces.
Daddy used to tell me I fought
to get into this world...
and I'd fight my way out.
That's all I want
to do, Frankie.
I just don't want
to fight you to do it.
I got what I needed.
I got it all.
Don't let them
keep taking it away from me.
Don't let me lie here till I can't
hear those people chanting no more.
I can't.
Please...
please, don't ask me.
I'm asking.
I can't.
Hello?
In the middle of the night,
Maggie had found her own solution.
She had bit her tongue.
Stop. Stop.
Look at me. Look at me.
Nearly bled to death before
they stitched her up.
She came around and ripped them out
before Frankie even got there.
They stitched her up again, padded
the tongue so she couldn't bite.
You can't do it,
you know that.
I do, Father.
You don't know how thick she is,
how hard it was to train her.
Other fighters would do exactly
what you say to them and...
and she'd ask why this and why
that and do it her own way, anyway.
How she fought for the title, I...
Well, it wasn't by listening to me.
But now she wants to die, and
I just want to keep her with me.
And I swear to God, Father...
it's committing
a sin by doing it.
By keeping her alive,
I'm killing her.
Do you know what I mean?
How do I get around that?
You don't. You step aside,
Frankie. You leave it with God.
She's not asking for God's
help. She's asking for mine.
Frankie, I've seen you at mass
almost every day for 23 years.
Someone who comes here that much
can't forgive himself for something.
Whatever sins you're carrying...
they're nothing compared to this.
Forget about God...
or Heaven and Hell.
If you do this thing,
you'll be lost...
somewhere so deep...
you'll never find
yourself again.
We're keeping her sedated
so she won't try that again.
I went to see Maggie
this morning.
You must have been
somewhere else.
Yeah.
You got a fight
I don't know about?
It wasn't your fault.
I was wrong to say that.
You're damn right.
I found you a fighter...
and you made her the best
fighter she could be.
And I killed her.
Don't say that.
Maggie walked through that door
with nothing but guts...
no chance in the world
of being what she needed to be.
A year and a half later, she's fighting
for the championship of the world.
You did that.
People die every day, Frankie...
mopping floors,
washing dishes.
And you know what their last
thought is? I never got my shot.
Because of you,
Maggie got her shot.
If she dies today, you know
what her last thought will be?
"I think I did all right."
I know I could rest with that.
Yeah.
I'll get a cup of coffee.
All right.
I'm gonna disconnect
your air machine...
then you're gonna go to sleep.
Then I'll give you a shot
and you'll stay asleep.
Mo Cuishle...
means "my darling, my blood."
He gave her a single shot.
It was enough adrenaline
to do the job a few times over.
He didn't want her
going through this again.
Then he walked out.
I don't think
he had anything left.
I went back to the gym.
Waited, figuring
he'd turn up sooner or later.
And that's when a ghost
came through the door.
I got to thinking
what you said, Mist' Scrap.
What was that, Danger?
Anybody can lose one fight.
That's the truth.
Put your gloves on.
You missed a lot of training.
Will do, Mist' Scrap.
Frankie never came back at all.
Frankie didn't leave a note,
and nobody knew where he went.
I'd hoped he'd gone to find you...
and ask you one more time
to forgive him.
But maybe he didn't have
anything left in his heart.
I just hope he found someplace
where he could find a little peace.
A place set
in the cedars and oak trees.
Somewhere between
nowhere and good-bye.
But that's probably
wishful thinking.
No matter where he is...
I thought you should know what kind
of man your father really was.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org