Who are you?
You okay?
Don't I look okay?
If you were any thinner
you wouldn't exist.
No!
Trevor?
You still got a half-hour.
I could fix you some eggs.
I'm tired. But thanks.
Let's go, monkeys.
Watch your work, not your ass.
Come on, guys. Keep it moving.
Yessuh, Mistah Tucker!
Mutha-Fucker.
Why's this machine down?
Maintenance.
Takes seven minutes
to power-up that mill.
Where am I gonna make up that
seven minutes, Miller?
- From your paycheck?
- Back off, Tucker.
You know
it's against regulations.
What "regulations"?
Lockout devices must be in place
during the cleaning and maintenance
of all heavy machinery." oSHA, 1989.
Yeah?
Write your congressman.
And hurry that up.
Congratulations, Reznik.
Youjust made my Shit List.
She's copping his joint.
He starts tellin' her
"baby this" and "baby that",
chattin' her up like
motherfuckin' Barry White.
Tellin' her what he wants to do,
and how he's gonna make
the coochie feel and all that.
- That's right.
- So dig.
She's stops, she looks up at him
with these big puppy dog eyes
and she's all: "that sounds good
puppy but me no have no coochie..."
And the brother's like:
"Say what?"
And he looks down
and sees that she is really a he!
Man, that's bullshit.
You telling me
the ho's wearing a thong
and the fool can't tell
the difference?
She had a tuck job, man! Come on,
Jonesy. You know how they do it!
- You might. I don't.
- Yeah, wathever...
Ei, Re<nik?
You up for some cards tonight?
Can't. Got plans.
Shit. Nigga says the same
damn thing every poker night.
What's up with you, man?
You used to be all right.
He used to hang
but he ain't been all right.
You may not reali<e this, but some
men prefer the company of women.
Who? Howdy Doody?
He don't get no booty.
Maybe he's got himself
a date with the Tuck Job.
Nah. Your mother said
she couldn't make it.
Re<nik talk...
You okay?
Don't I look okay?
If you were any thinner
you wouldn't exist.
What's wrong?
I don't know. Deja vu?
You're tired.
You need to sleep.
- How do you do it?
- What?
Sleep so little
and still look so good.
Are you flirting with me?
Commiserating.
- Trying to fatten me up?
- What if I am?
Suppose I wanted blueberry?
You had that last night.
You don't fool me, Trevor Re<nik.
I have you figured out.
You do, huh?
What else do you know about me?
That you're lonely.
When you work graveyard
as long as I have,
you get to know the type.
Hey. Everyone gets lonely, Trevor.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
How can I be lonely
when I have you to keep me company?
Trevor Reznik.
Furman's office. Now.
How you doing, Re<nik?
What's this about?
Frankly, I'm concerned
about you.
To be honest,
I think you look like toasted shit.
I've had a lot
on my mind lately.
- Anything we could help with?
- No. Thanks.
- It's nothing I can't handle.
- Want to see the doctor?
That's not necessary.
I'm fine. Really.
Are you doin' drugs, Re<nik?
- Where's the shop steward?
- He couldn't make it.
I shouldn't even be in here
without a union rep.
- See what I mean?
- Look, Trevor.
I understand how you feel.
Believe me.
But there's absolutely
nothing to worry about.
- Then I'll just get back to work.
- Trevor.
Not yet.
I have to ask you for a U.A.
Looks like rain.
Radio says
it's a storm's on the way.
Guess they're right.
I'd say it's already here.
You on the 1st shift?
- Yeah.
- Me too.
That's funny.
I've never seen you before.
I've been here.
I work in the pit.
Just picked up Reynolds' shift.
Where's Reynolds?
Feds picked him up.
Old warrant.
I'm lvan.
Trevor.
Well,
I guess I better be getting back.
I hear that Tucker guy
can be a real prick.
You heard right.
I'll see you around.
What's wrong?
I just want to lie here.
We could do that.
I'm so tired.
You could fall asleep
if you want. Off the meter.
That's the problem.
I can't sleep.
Nothing helps.
Don't worry about it, honey.
Everyone gets insomnia
now and then.
Stevie.
I haven't slept in a year.
Jesus christ.
I tried Him, too.
Sorry.
Hello?
Yeah.
I can't talk right now.
Ok.
My ex.
He's a fucking psycho.
Trevor, I'm worried about you.
Don't worry.
No one ever died of insomnia.
I hope not.
You're my best client.
I can't afford to lose you.
Gee, thanks.
Reznik.
I need a hand!
I'm trying to get this bed
leveled here. Help me.
- Safety on?
- Yeah.
How's that?
No. Still off.
That any better?
Do your sleeping on your own time.
I need some help.
Better. But not level.
Try the other side.
Bitch of machine...
What'd you do?
I'm hang up here!
Kill it!
- C'mon, kill it.
- It's not working.
Shit!
It's not working.
- Hit the breaker!
- What?
Use the foot brake!
We need some help over here!
Holy shit!
What happened here?
For chrissake, Tucker!
Call an ambulance!
What the fuck happened here!
I was helping him level the mill.
I thought the safety was on...
You thought?
Somebody kill
that fucking machine!
Jesus christ.
Shit.
Hello, Mrs. Shrike.
I've come with the rent.
And so early!
Oh, Mr. Re<nik,
I wish all of my tenants
were as considerate as you.
I'll give you a receipt
in the morning.
Goodnight, Mr. Reznik.
Mrs. Shrike...
Forgive me, but,
have you noticed anyone
hanging around my apartment?
- Has there been a burglary?
- No! No, nothing like that.
I was just wondering
if you've...
you know...
noticed anything
unusual lately?
Unusual?
Never mind, Mrs. Shrike.
Sorry to disturb you so late.
Good night.
What we know is this.
One.
Miller was operating the mill
in long sleeves.
Two. Miller's arm was
in the cutting zone of the mill
while it was off.
Three. The mill
suddenly activates,
catching Miller's sleeve,
resulting in this.
What's the fucking point?
These accidents
are never pretty, Mr. Reznik.
It's our job to investigate these
events from every possible angle,
so that we might prevent
their recurrence.
So we'd appreciated it if you
would be a bit more cooperative.
I knocked into the fucking
activator. By mistake.
What caused the mistake,
Mr. Reznik?
- I was distracted.
- By what?
What "distracted" you?
It was lvan.
I was watching lvan in the pit.
The whole thing
was my fault. Okay?
Who did you say?
The new arc welder.
I don't know his last name.
What new arc welder?
Lvan. The guy
from the swing-shift.
Reynolds was picked up on a warrant
and this guy took his place.
What the fuck
are you talking about, Re<nik?
Reynolds is right over there
in the pit, as usual busting his ass!
There is no "lvan"
at National Machining, Reznik.
What is this?
Mr. Reznik, have you recently
suffered any head injuries?
Ever hear of pumpkin pie?
Nope.
- Trevor?
- Yeah?
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure.
Why do you go out of your way
to come here every night?
Is it out of the way?
An airport?
For coffee and pie?
Suppose I went to Denny's.
Suddenly I get an overwhelming
urge to skip town.
Could I do that at just any diner?
Is someone chasing you?
Not yet.
But they will
when they find out who I am.
Oh, really? Who are you?
Can you keep a secret?
To the grave.
I'm Elvis Presley.
I ran away from home to pursue
my blue collar aspirations.
I thought you looked familiar...
Got plans for Mother's Day?
I'm taking my little boy
to the amusement park.
It's supposed to be my day,
yet he gets all the fun.
That's okay, when he's older
I'll let him make it up to me.
A little guilt goes a long way.
- How about you?
- Cemetery.
- Oh. I'm sorry.
- Thanks.
I lost mine, too.
Still hurts.
I'm not too good
at losing family.
Who is?
What's weird is it didn't hit me
till I picked out her burial dress.
I pictured her buying it...
not knowing it would.
You know, be the one...
seems unfair, doesn't it?
Not knowing things like that?
How about spending the day with me
and Nicholas after the cemetery?
Sounds dreamy.
Hey, Reynolds?
What'd the Feds want you for?
Armed robbery.
Yeah? Me and Jackson had you pegged
as a pedophile. Right, Jackson?
Probably guilty of that too.
Hey, I don't see
what's so fucking funny.
Y'all clownin' the motherfucker
like it's some big joke.
Well it ain't!
Personally, I don't feel
too comfortable workin' with you.
You make me nervous.
You look like shit.
Actin' all crazy.
What's up with you?
Nothing's up with me.
It was an accident.
And I'm the one who's gotta
live with it. Not you.
You ain't hearin' me, man.
Nobody wants you here.
Nobody.
See you tomorrow.
Howdy, partner!
You gotta go back to the shop.
Tucker needs to see you.
What about?
I don't know.
But it seemed important.
Well, it'll have to wait.
It's Miller time!
We need to talk.
Follow me.
C'mon.
Another bourbon.
Make it a double.
You shooting coke or something?
You look like a dope fiend
to me. No offense.
I don't use drugs.
Normally I don't even drink.
How about abnormally?
I see Reynolds is back to work.
Yeah. Guess he made bail.
Tell you one thing.
Whatever he did,
- he sure ain't coppin' to it.
- Would you?
Never trust a con, cowboy.
They don't get through
life being honest.
Where they hiding you these days?
Around.
Wanna see something?
Look at that.
Lost 'em on the lathe.
Took the big toe from my left foot
and the pinkie from my right.
That's why I walk with a gimp.
Can't shuffle cards like
I used to but...
the ladies sure like it.
You look like
you've seen a ghost!
Funny you should say that.
The guys at work
don't think you exist.
That's why I can't get a raise!
According to Tucker,
you aren't even on the payroll.
You believe that?
Why would they lie?
They'rejust having
a little fun with ya.
I'm not laughing.
Quit fucking around.
A man lost his arm. He could've died.
That's not my problem.
You caused the accident,
not me.
Where you going?
To take a leak.
You wanna watch?
I'll be right back.
Don't disappear on me.
Son of a bitch.
Hello.
Reynolds. It's Trevor.
What time is it?
How they biting, Reynolds?
- You're drunk, Reznik.
- The game's over.
I got proof on you
and I'm gonna use it.
You better watch your fucking ass,
buddy, before you lose it.
Trevor.
I need to see you, Stevie.
Well, Jesus. Trevor.
I mean I'm not exactly alone...
Please, Stevie.
I think I'm falling apart.
Why don't you come back
in an hour?
No. I need to see you now.
In case of something happens,
I need someone to know.
Gimme a minute.
I appreciate you making time for me.
You're the only one I can talk to.
It's my pleasure.
Most guys don't come here
for my conversation.
Something's
happening to me, Stevie.
Some kind of plot.
There was an accident
at the shop.
A man was nearly killed
thanks to me.
Now the guys at work
are against me.
They want me out.
I can't blame 'em.
It's the way
they're going about it.
Their eyes. Their little games...
What?
E-R.
T-U-C-K-E-R.
Trevor?
Tucker?
Maybe you're taking
this accident thing a bit too hard.
I mean,
if they wanted you out
they'd just fire you.
I'm not worried
about being fired.
Then what are you worried about?
I don't know yet.
- There you go. Made to order.
- Thank's.
Surprise!
Gotcha. That one's going
on the frigde.
Here. Let me get one
of you and Nicholas.
By the carousel.
Just a minute.
Okay. Ready.
Smile.
It helps to push the button.
Trevor? What is it?
This place.
- Brings back memories.
- Good memories I hope.
Yeah.
I haven't been here
since I was a kid.
My ex.
Probably calling to wish me
a happy Mother's Day.
Could you?
Yeah... No sweat.
I'll take Nicholas for a ride.
Thanks.
Hi!
How long have you known
my mother?
About a year.
How'd you meet her?
Well, we just kind of met...
- Are you gonna see her again?
- I hope so.
- Would you like that?
- I guess so.
Wanna know a secret?
What?
My father left us
when I was your age.
Wanna know something else?
It made me reali<e
what a wonderful mother I had.
You'll realize that too someday.
What's that?
It's a ride.
"Route 666."
What's it mean?
Well, a route is a road you take
when you're on a long journey.
Can we go on it?
Well, Nicholas, maybe
we should wait for your mother.
Looks like someone
had a bad cracked up.
Filler up cowboy!
Won't be eating there
anytime soon, eh, Nicolas?
Look at that!
You should close
your eyes, Nicolas.
Jesus...
- Boy, this is one heck of a ride.
- Yeah.
Shady Lady.
Oh, my God!
Stop!
A right Nicolas.
A right! A right!
Nicholas.
Nicholas!
I need some help here!
Somebody get a doctor!
Hang on, Nicholas.
I'm going for help.
Nicholas!
I swear to god,
I don't know what happened.
He's epileptic.
I should've told you.
- I'll call an ambulance.
- No. It'll pass.
It's okay, baby.
This hasn't happened
for a while.
I didn't think to mention it.
I could kill myself
for taking him on that ride.
It's okay.
It's not your fault.
He won't even remember it.
It'll be as
if nothing ever happened.
Wanna come in?
I think you could use a drink.
I hope wine's okay with you.
It'll work.
What good is a home
if you can't relax in it!
I'll have to remember that.
Trevor, can I ask you something?
Should my lawyer be present?
Why are you always leaving me
such generous tips?
Do I?
Twenty dollars for coffee and pie?
And entertainment.
Entertainment?
You.
Trevor, you don't have to buy
my companionship.
Sorry.
It wasn't meant that way.
If you really want to spoil me,
take me to the movies sometime.
It's a deal.
My goodness. There must be
a hole in this glass.
I'll get it.
- You wait on me enough.
- Thanks.
It's the last door on the left!
Reznik.
I want you
on the Swansea Lathe today.
Where's Sanche<?
That's an irrelevant question,
Reznik. I'm asking you.
Shit!
If there is anything
we can do for you let us know.
Thank you, Mr. Furman.
See him out.
Who it is,
Vampire Miller.
- You're okay?
- Good, good.
- You be easy.
- Yeah, man. Take it easy.
My god, Miller.
Where do I begin?
Don't sweat it, kid.
There's nothing to say.
I wish there was someway
to repay you.
For a start
give me your left arm.
In fact, that's why
I came by. Right, Tucker?
Fair is fair.
We'rejust ra<<in' you, Reznik.
You can keep your arm.
And I'll keep my settlement.
Hell, most guys would give
an arm and a leg
for a deal like this.
I guess you can call me lucky.
Well,
Miller, if there's
anything I can do...
Forget it.
No hard feelings, huh?
See you around, pal.
Jump the line.
Somebody help me.
Somebody.
Reznik! I gotcha, I gotha!
Be cool... Be cool...
Who did it?
One of you threw
the fucking breaker!
Or was it all of you?
- Cool your heels, man.
- Was it you?
Or you? Was it you?
Nobody did shit, you asshole!
You're imagining things again!
Yeah? Have you been fishing
with lvan lately, Reynolds?
Let's see you talk
your way out of this one!
Where is it?
What a fuck now, Re<nik?
Get him off me!
You're through, you fuck!
Pack up your shit,
get outta here, you're fired!
Motherfucker's crazy.
You lost it, man.
Damn it, where is it?
Asshole.
What the fuck
did you do with it?
Idiot.
Fuck you! Get out!
Hey.
What...
It's an occupational ha<ard.
So, Trevor,
you gonna rescue me
from this miserable life or what?
Y'know,
I could give it up
for the right guy...
Boy did that come out wrong.
What I mean is...
I'd y'know,
stop hooking...
if you wanted me to.
I mean there's a lot of lesser
paying gigs out there, right?
I think I would like that.
- Mr. Reznik!
- I'm sorry.
I thought you were
somebody else...
You gave me such a scare.
What are you doing
in my apartment?
There's a leak in my ceiling.
It's coming from your apartment.
That's impossible.
- I was going to leave a note.
- A note?
- What kind of note?
- About the leak...
What's that terrible smell?
There's no leak in this apartment.
Now if you'll excuse me.
- Are you sure you're all right?
- Yes, I'm sure.
If you need anything,
please call first.
Miller...
Miller!
Eh, Reznik!
Pleasant surprise.
- We need to talk.
- Take a look at this.
Picked it up at Grossman's.
Top of the line.
That's enough yard work
for one day, dear.
I need to be
doing something.
I can't be watching
soap operas all day.
The lawn will be here tomorrow.
But you won't if you don't
listen to the doctor.
Margie, this is Re<nik.
The man who cost me an arm.
How do you do, Mrs. Miller?
I've been better, Mr. Reznik.
Is there someplace we can talk?
Check it out.
Ain't she a beauty?
8 cylinders.
Magnasteer
Speed-sensitive steering.
ABS braking
with road-texture detection.
Prevents lock up, helps you maintain
control in an emergency.
'Course she's an automatic.
I really wanted
a manual transmission,
but I figured my shifting
wouldn't be so hot.
You know I'm not
at National anymore. Right?
Yeah. I heard about that.
Sounds like you nearly lost one, too.
Don't you find
that a bit ironic, Miller?
Ironic?
Sorry, kid, but I left school
in the 8th grade.
I'll break it down for you, Miller.
Moments after
you left the shop,
someone powered up my machine
with my arm in it.
- I nearly got killed.
- Accidents happen.
It was no accident.
Accidents happen
out of negligence.
This happened out of spite.
- That's some vocabulary, kid.
- Spite.
Ill-will. Vengeance.
Vengeance means revenge, Miller.
I'm sure you know what
"revenge" means, don't you?
I'm on to you, Miller.
Despite your stupid jokes
you secretly blame me
for the accident.
New car or not,
you despise me for it.
How'd you get into my place?
Duplicate key?
Credit card? What?
Fuck you, Miller!
This shit's gonna stop!
Get off my property, punk.
Bastards.
Shit.
C'mon!
7-4-3-
C-R-N. 743cRN.
743cRN.
What?
Shit!
Fuck.
Fuck!
I'm sorry, sir,
but we don't provide motorist
information to the general public.
I'm not a member of the general public.
This guy's a friend of mine.
You don't know
your friend's address?
We just met.
I don't know him that well.
Sir, this is the DMV.
Not a dating service.
Look, ljust
want to talk to him.
I'm sorry, sir, but I can't help
you unless a crime has been committed.
Has a crime
been committed?
Please. I wouldn't ask
if it weren't extremely important.
Sorry, sir.
No crime, no information.
What if I told you
I was hit by this car?
I don't see any bruises.
If you did would
you give me an address?
No. But the police might.
What is it, sweetie?
Tired?
You want to go take a nap?
We're almost home.
I want to report
a hit-and-run.
Bring it back
when you're finished.
- Fill it out over there.
- Thanks.
Mr. Reznik?
Are you sure
about these plate numbers?
743 cRN. That's the one.
- Have you ever had a car stolen?
- No. Why?
Because the car that allegedly
hit you was your own.
1965 Red Pontiac Firebird.
Registered in your name.
Nearly a year ago you reported it
as being totaled in a wreck.
Do you reali<e it's a felony
to file a bogus police report?
Wait a minute. I think you have
some explaining to do.
Jesus, Reznik!
We just want to talk to you!
Re<nik! Re<nik!
Reznik!
Trevor?
Oh, my god.
Trevor.
What happened?
Trevor. Tell me.
How the hell did it happen?
I was crossing the street.
The light changed on me.
Did he stop?
No, he just keep going.
Fucking hit-and-run drivers.
They ought to be hanged.
It was my fault.
I wasn't paying attention.
Trevor, I got to get you
to a hospital.
You may have
some internal injuries.
- They're just bruises.
- You see this?
This is a bruise.
That is a train wreck.
All right?
What is it with you and doctors
anyway? Don't you trust anyone?
I trust you.
Now I know you're crazy.
Can I stay here tonight?
Baby, you can stay here
every night.
You know that.
What?
What's going on in
that cra<y head of yours?
I really want this
to work, Stevie.
But?
You know so little about me.
What if I turn
into a werewolf or something?
I'll buy you a flea collar.
Hello.
- Stevie?
- Yeah?
Thanks.
I set out some clean clothes for you.
You're stuff's not dry yet.
Do you always keep men's clothes
lying around?
Some regulars like to keep
a clean change of clothes here.
I'll probably just throw them
out now, right?
A perfect fit.
Yeah! Trevor, I don't have
a si<e 26 waist here.
How about that idea?
I could get a job
selling menswear.
Those tricks
get paid vacations, too.
I could settle for that.
It's not a bad life.
It could be worse. You know
what else I want to do?
I want to clean up
this place
and get rid of all that
fucking junk.
Probably looks like
I'm a terrible housekeeper,
which I sometimes am, but I can
be also very organi<ed.
I'd do more of that.
I would love
to paint the place.
Just make it nice,
be organi<ed
and neat and paint it white...
It'd be nice to have a white,
beautiful place
and... a decent stove.
It's not a lot to ask.
Well, don't look so surprised.
Even a call girl scramble an egg.
It's funny I never did this
for a guy before...
even cook for my husband.
Jesus christ.
Where is he?
Who?
You know who.
- Trevor?
- Don't.
Jesus, Trevor. What's wrong?
This! Lvan!
He's your ex, isn't he?
- What?
- Why's he doing this?
It's because
I'm fucking you, isn't it!
Now it makes sense.
I'm fucking you!
So he's fucking me!
Where is he?
Hiding in the closet?
Beneath the bed?
I don't know what
you're talking about, baby...
Don't "baby" me!
"Yeah, baby!
I'll change my whole
fucking life for you!
I'll do anything
you want, baby!"
You know what?
I don't deserve this...
What'd you do?
Slip this from my wallet
while proposing to me?
Fuck you! You left that
in my tip jar the other night.
- Bullshit!
- I thought you wanted me to have it!
Cut the crap, Stevie!
What's the big deal
about a goddamn picture?
They say the guy in this photo
doesn't exist. This says he does.
I don't understand what
the fuck are you talking about.
I'm talking
about your ex! Lvan!
Who?
This guy standing next to you
with the fish?
I am not in that photo.
I'm looking at a picture of you
standing next to some fat guy
with glasses holding a fish.
It's not me!
Trevor.
It's you. Look.
You lying whore.
Get the fuck out,
you fucking freak!
You bet a fucking will,
- you fucking whore!
- You fucking freak!
Now I know why
you're so afraid of doctors!
'Cuz you're a fucking psycho!
My ex, the fucking psycho...
- Hello.
- Baby....
... fucking psycho?
Where is Maria?
- Who?
- You know who.
Maria. My waitress.
My. You're chatty tonight.
Darling. I'm your waitress...
What's going on here?
I've never seen you before.
What are you talking about?
You come in here every night...
sitting on that same stool...
staring at your coffee.
To be honest, I was starting
to think you were a mute.
I want to see Maria.
Mister. There is no Maria
that works here.
Is everybody in on it?
Let's have a laugh on Trevor,
is that it?
Whatever lvan's paying you,
he's wasting his money.
Go home, mister.
Get some sleep.
Don't forget your Post-lts.
Christ, Stevie.
How could you?
Nicholas?
You ougth to pay
your utility bills, Parthner.
You know how difficult
is shaving in the dark?
What have you done with Nicholas?
What have I done with Nicholas?
Nicholas?
He can't hear you now, pal.
Come off it.
You know he's dead.
You ought to see
someone about that...
faulty memory of yours, pal.
Might make your life
a little easier.
By the way,
I love the little notes
you leave yourself.
The one on the refrigerator
just kills me...
Where's your hospitality, partner?
God!
People might get
the wrong idea.
Who are you?
It looks you have some
explaining to do, parthner!
I know who you are!
Going somewhere, Mr. Re<nik?
Yes, Mrs. Shrike. I'm moving.
I didn't receive notice.
Your lease requires you to give
30 days notice in writing...
It wasn't planned.
Something came up.
You can keep
my security deposit.
I won't be needing it anyway.
Really, Mr. Reznik.
You used to be
such a good tenant.
I just don't understand it...
Isn't that pretty?
Would you care to sell it?
No.
It was my mothers.
I've made arrangements
to donate all my things.
A truck will be coming by
this afternoon.
Well, if you're just going
to give it away...
If you'll excuse me, Mrs. Shrike.
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
I'd like to report
a hit-and-run.
We're still gonna need
to get your statement.
Later.
I just want to sleep.