♪ She walks in beauty ♪
♪ Like the night ♪
♪ Of cloudless climes ♪
♪ And starry skies ♪
♪ And all that's best ♪
♪ Of dark and bright ♪
♪ Meet in her aspect ♪
♪ And her eyes ♪
♪ Thus mellow'd to that tender light ♪
♪ Which heaven to gaudy day ♪
♪ Denies ♪
♪ She walks in beauty ♪
♪ Like the night ♪
♪ Of cloudless climes ♪
♪ And starry skies ♪
♪ She walks in beauty ♪
♪ Like the night ♪
♪ Of cloudless climes ♪
♪ And starry skies ♪
- Look after your carriage, mister.
- Oh, please, sir! Please!
Is this your daughter, madame?
I will take her, half cash down
and half in consuls.
Surely, Mama, you cannot sell me
to the highest bidder, though he is a lord.
Why ever not, child?
We cannot flout the rules
of good society.
Mind your backs. Excuse us.
You can catch a lord
with 30,000...
Is this an inconvenient moment?
I've returned for another look, Mr. Sharp,
but I can always come back another time.
No need, my lord.
There it is.
Virtue Betrayed.
Look.
Look as long as you want.
- And the price?
- Four guineas, my lord. Just as I said.
They're all four guineas.
Not that one!
That one is 10!
Virtue Betrayed is 10 guineas.
- Oh, but that is too much, little miss.
- Good.
The model was my late wife.
The child doesn't want to part with it.
And if I give you 10 guineas
for this picture of your mother,
will you be happy then
to see it go?
No.
But it will be too much to refuse.
Hmph. Very well then.
Ten guineas it shall be.
Mark!
I'm very much obliged, sir.
- Good day to you, Mr. Sharp.
- Good day, my lord.
The orphanage can take her,
but I thought you might find her useful.
With both parents dead,
there's no one to fuss.
You can...
do what you like with the child.
Hmm.
How fluent is her French?
Oh, very.
Her mother was Parisian.
An opera girl.
I see.
Well, the less said
about that the better.
Good-bye, Miss Sedley.
You are a credit to us.
Take this copy of the great
Dr. Johnson's dictionary
as a token of our good wishes.
Thank you,
Miss Pinkerton.
You've tidied the library?
Yes, Miss Green.
And the sheet music?
It's all put away?
Yes, it is,
Miss Green.
Well, what about the study hall?
Have you swept it
thoroughly?
I have and for the last time.
Don't be too sure, Miss Sharp.
Life can be very unpredictable.
Oh, I do hope so,
Miss Green.
Miss Sharp,
I can't pretend to understand...
why you prefer the post
of a country governess
to your position here.
- Can you not, Miss Pinkerton?
- And you feel quite ready to leave us?
I'm glad to hear it.
Then good day to you,
Miss Sharp.
Good day.
Oh, Miss Pinkerton?
Am I not to have
myJohnson's dictionary?
Very well.
Here you are.
Treat it as a symbol of the education
we have given you.
I certainly will,
Miss Pinkerton.
Bye.!
Silly old trout.
She doesn't know a word of French,
though she's too proud to admit it.
Vive la France.!
Vive Napoleon!
Becky, how can you be
so wicked and vengeful?
And why not?
In all the years I spent there,
I only ever knew
kind words from you.
Revenge may be wicked,
but it's perfectly natural.
Perhaps it is.
But you're wrong to make me say so.
Never mind that.
Let's talk ofhow I'm to spend
my precious week of freedom.
My first priority
is to form an opinion
of Captain Osborne.
I take that duty
very seriously, you know.
It will not tax you.
George is quite perfect.
- And so he should be. And your parents?
- Get on there.!
I must confess
I'm a little nervous of them.
Just be yourself
and everyone will love you.
I do.
- Tell me more about your brother.
- Jos?
There's nothing to add
to what you already know.
He's home on leave from India.
The position is a fine one.
It has made him rich.
But I'm afraid his life is a lonely one.
If only he were married.
Come on! Get up!
And what children exactly...
are to have the benefit of
your instruction, Miss Sharp?
The daughters of Sir Pitt Crawley
of Queen's Crawley, ma'am.
He's among the first
gentlemen of Hampshire.
Or so I was told
when I applied for the position.
Mmm.
He is not so prominent that
we have ever heard of him.
Do you know the county at all?
No.
But that does not frighten me.
I love to visit new places.
- Really?
- Oh, indeed!
How I envy men who can explore for
themselves all the wonders of the world.
And, uh, should you like
to visit India, do you think?
India?
I cannot think of anywhere
I'd rather see.
The palaces of Delhi,
the Taj Mahal,
the Burning Ghats...
Have you made a study
of India, Miss Sharp?
Not so much
as I would like.
I'm enraptured with every scent
and flavor of the East.
Oh, gad, if you think so.
Biju, fetch a plate.
Becky, be careful.!
Those curries can burn.!
So, Miss Sharp, how do you
find your first taste of India?
Delicious.
♪ Over the mountains ♪
♪ And over the waves ♪
♪ Under the fountains ♪
♪ And under the graves ♪
♪ Under floods
that are deepest ♪
♪ Which Neptune obey ♪
♪ Over rocks that are steepest ♪
♪ Love will find out ♪
♪ The way ♪
My word, Miss Sharp.
You've the voice of an angel
in heaven.
Oh.
Yes.
You must have some lessons,
my dear.
Captain Dobbin!
Is George not here?
Yes.
Where is my dear godson?
Pray don't concern yourselves.
George sends his regrets.
- Work holds him prisoner.
- But he is coming to the picnic
at Vauxhall tomorrow?
- Do please say that he is.
- Oh, he wouldn't miss it for worlds.
Come to bed, now.
You must be finished
with all those boring
old numbers.
If only I could be.
I wish Jos wasn't
taking her to this silly
Vauxhall picnic.
He'll drink too much,
and who knows what he'll say
if the little minx works on him.
LetJos marry whom he likes.
She has no fortune,
but nor had you.
Better her than a black
Mrs. Sedley from Boggley Wollah...
and her dozen
mahogany grandchildren.
Now, now, now.
George,
your Amelia awaits.
Ho-hum, Dobbs.
Unflagging devotion is all very well,
but it does rather take out the challenge.
So tell me, what is
the hanger-on governess like?
Amelia.
Miss Sharp.
Thank you.
Step carefully now.
And here he is. It's George.
My dear Amelia.
I can't tell you how much Becky
has been longing to meet you.
I want to be quite sure you're
good enough for dear Amelia.
And who's to decide? You?
Oh, but, Becky only meant...
Come, Miss Becky.
May I show you the pavilion
and all the delights I've prepared for us?
You may show me anything
you choose, Mr. Sedley.
She was only joking.
I don't care for governesses
to joke at my expense.
Miss Sharp! Miss Sharp!
I thought I was to help unravel your silks,
not to be sold into slavery.
Nonsense, Mr. Sedley.
Stay still, I beg you,
or I shall never have
them untangled.
I surrender.
I am your prisoner.
You have only to ask
and I shall release you.
But...
why would I ever want that?
Hmm.
I hopeJos isn't
getting in too deep.
Becky is my friend,
dearest George.
And I would welcome her
as a sister, as I hope you would.
Biju, we're ready.
Hmm.
Dearest Miss Sharp,
I give him to you.
What?
Your beautiful bird?
No, I couldn't!
You say you love everything
that comes from India.
Take him.
He is my ambassador.
Hello.
Amelia!
Well?
He called me "dearest" twice,
and he squeezed my hand.
And look.
He gave me his precious bird.
- Well, surely that is a good sign.
- I know! I know!
Feel my heart,
how it beats.
What are you playing at
with the little governess?
- Well, I told her I was...
- Jos. Jos.
You've forgotten
how these things work.
Do you think the fellas
down at the club...
would let their wives
dine with a governess?
Seriously, Jos,
if I'm to marry your sister...
lf?
What are they talking about?
Can you guess?
Yes.
I think I probably can.
Oh, Becky, who knows?
It might turn out to be
a blessing in disguise.
The disguise
is very convincing.
Good luck.
Here. This is for you.
Oh.
It's one of my father's.
I've nothing else to give.
Oh, I couldn't.
Take it.
I want you to have it.
At least I know
it will be safe with you.
Oh, Becky!
Good stuff! Inside!
Off I go then.
Couldn't I pay for a seat inside?
They're all taken.
But don't worry.
I prefer the open air.
Hello, madame.
Hurry along now.!
Bye!
Get it on there.!
Queen's Crawley.!
Yes?
Can you tell Sir Pitt Crawley
that Miss Sharp has arrived.
And bring in my trunk
if you please.
- Miss Sharp?
- Yes, Miss Rebecca Sharp.
Governess to your master's children.
Now, will you kindly let me pass?
Certainly.
As for telling Sir Pitt,
there's no need.
Why not?
You've just told him yourself.
♪ For these and all Thy other gifts ♪
♪ May the Lord make us truly thankful ♪
♪ Amen ♪
Ah.!
You haven't met Lady Crawley,
my dear.
She's the girls' mother.
She's not the mother of my sons.
Is she, Pitt? No.
Pitt's mother, my first wife,
she was the daughter of a lord,
which makes him grander
than all of us put together,
doesn't it, Pitt?
Whatever you say, sir.
Oh, yes. Very grand.
Too grand for me.
But this one ain't.
Her father was an ironmonger,
wasn't he, my lady?
He was, sir.
Yeah.
When shall we discuss
the girls' lessons?
My strengths are music,
drawing and French,
but I can teach them
whatever you wish.
You'll be kind to my girls,
Miss Sharp?
Oh!
Don't worry. I'll treat them
just as sensitively as they deserve.
Hmph.
What is this?
It's, uh,
"Potage de mouton à I'Ecossaise. '"
Oh, mutton broth.
What sheep was it, Horrocks?
When did you kill?
One of the black-faced Scots, Sir Pitt.
We killed on Thursday.
Did she squeal?
Didn't she just.
Oh, good.
Always improves the flavor, that.
Oh.
"To be honest, dearest Amelia,
"Sir Pitt is not what you and I
would think a baronet should be.
More ancient stable than ancient fable."
No lights after 11:;00,
you little hussy.
Go to bed in the dark,
unless you'd like me to come in
for your candle every night, hmm?
"All in all, my hopes for the family lie
with Sir Pitt's younger son,
Captain Rawdon Crawley,
who will soon be back from
his regiment. '"
I would like...
to go to Spain.
Je voudrais allez en Spain.
And that's an "E."
"His brother, Mr. Pitt Crawley, meanwhile,
has the charm of an undertaker...
and the humor of a corpse. '"
Uh, Miss Sharp,
I thought you might like to see
my pamphlet on the Chickasaw tribes.
I swear, Mr. Crawley,
you must be a mind reader.
For there is no subject
of more interest to me.
"You'll be happy to hear I've found a way
to make myself indispensable to Sir Pitt.
There is to be a visitor
at Humdrum Hall. '"
Please!
Be careful with that.
"Sir Pitt has a half-sister
as rich as Croesus,
whom, or should I say which,
he adores. '"
No! No, no!
No, no, no, no!
She's organizing those!
Stupid wench!
"And now he is all of a dither
to make the house ready
to receive her. '"
Up! Up, up, up!
A little higher.
"We are quite a party.
"Mr. Pitt's intended,
LadyJane Sheepshanks,
has arrived with her mother,
"the old Countess of Southdown,
whom Sir Pitt detests.
"I promise you, dearest Amelia,
that by the time I have finished,
Hmm.
"The old man will have
a very proper sense of the merits
ofhis latest employee.
I will bring order from chaos
and light from darkness. '"
Quickly now!
Sorry, sir.
By Heaven!
Miss Becky,
we don't deserve you.
Steady now.! Steady.! Steady.!
"They say Miss Crawley
means to leave her fortune
to Captain Rawdon Crawley,
who will accompany her
for thejourney. '"
I see Pitt's intended is among the guests.
They'll be after you to marry next.
Oh, Aunt Tilly, how could I,
when my heart belongs to you?
- Matilda!
- Wicked boy!
Welcome.
Brother.
You know
Lady Southdown, I think,
and her daughter, LadyJane.
Aunt Matilda,
on behalf of the entire Crawley...
Keep your toadying
till I get to a fire.
You can suck up all you wish
once I'm warm.
Well, that's put us in our place.
We may have the titles, Mama,
but Miss Crawley has the money.
Mm, and don't we know it.
Put the trunk inside.!
Now, Miss Becky,
this is my younger son,
Rawdon.
And mind you stay clear
ofhis fluttering lashes.
He breaks hearts
for a hobby, but...
he's a soldier
through and through.
- I'm warned.
- Mm-hmm.
With a little liquor, I can do it.
You must be bored
as a brick down here.
I have your father
and brother for company.
Precisely.
Not a great many laughs
in Miss Crawley, I can tell you.
I seem to remember
anchovy paste is a favorite delicacy
of yours, Aunt Tilly.
But not for do... doggies.
I don't agree.
I suspect she's the quickest wit
in the room.
No, no, no.
I mean my brother, not my aunt.
They used to call him
"Miss Crawley" at Eton.
Go on. Admit it.
He looks a little underweight.
He's the dullest dog
in shoe leather.
Really, Captain Crawley.
Are you trying to steer me
towards an indiscretion?
Why?
Would you like me to?
No man has managed it yet.
- What was that?
- Nothing. A false note.
Allez, Rose, Celia. Dépêchez.
Faites vosà obeissances a votre tante.
Don't waste your time,
Miss Sharp.
All foreign languages
are ancient Greek to my sisters.
And they always will be
if they're not spoken before them.
I quite agree, Miss Sharp.
What a treat to find someone
cultured in this house.
Vous parlez bien.
Merci.
My mother was French.
A French mother?
Now, that's altogether
too romantic for a governess.
Who was she?
Have you heard
of the Montmorencys?
Who has not?
So, you're an impoverished aristocrat.
Pity.
I had you down for an adventuress.
And are they mutually exclusive?
Oh, please tell me there's something
disreputable in your past.
Well, my father was an artist.
Ah, that's better.
A starving one, I hope.
Absolutely ravenous.
Who's ravenous... besides me?
Horrocks? When's dinner?
Any minute now,
Sir Pitt.
Good.
I'd best excuse myself.
Come along, girls.
- Is Miss Sharp not to dine with us?
- Well, don't ask me. Ask Pitt.
Mm.
Nephew?
I hope she's not banished
in my honor.
You know I am nothing
if not democratic.
It's no great sacrifice
in the cause of peace.
Of course,
Miss Sharp must dine with us
if you wish it, Aunt.
Dinner is served!
Good!
Come along, my dear.
You'll sit by me.
And after dinner,
we shall abuse the company.
Really,
the hoops she makes
us jump through.
I don't mind, Mama.
I like Miss Sharp.
Mm.
Caesar liked Brutus
and look where it got him.
- ♪All these and all Thy other gifts may...♪
- Pitt!
Amen.
Aunt Matilda,
you are the guest ofhonor.
Um, what shall we drink to?
Better food and a warmer room.
Should we not drink to peace at
last... with Napoleon safe on Elba?
To the men who put him there...
to Wellington and Nelson.
Wellington and Nelson.
Wellington I grant you, hmm,
but, um, it is hard
to match Nelson's heroism...
with his private life.
The life of Alexander
did not bear much scrutiny.
Is he not a hero, either?
Quite right, Miss Sharp.
And to my mind, that was
the best part of Nelson's character!
He went to the deuce for a woman.
There must be some good
in a man who'll do that.
Hmm.
I adore imprudent matches.
- Wellington and Nelson.
- Wellington...
Mm. You set no store
by birth, then?
Birth?
Look at this family.!
We've been
at Queen's Crawley
since Henry II,
but not one of us here
is as clever as Miss Sharp.
- To all the King's officers!
- All the King's officers!
The King's officers.
Mmm, lobster.
Delicious.
Come in, my dear.
I've left my toadies in London.
And what bores they are
downstairs.
It falls to you
to make me laugh.
She's clever enough,
isn't she, Firkin?
I think Miss seems
very clever.
Oh, yes.
If merit had its just reward,
you ought to be a duchess.
Mm.
You set no store by birth, then?
Silly old fool,
grabbing at my money
for her daughter's intended,
that hypocrite Pitt.
He should put down his Bible
and do the dirty work himself.
With a decent position,
you could put the world on a leash.
Perhaps I'll surprise you
and run away with a great man.
Oh, that'd be perfect.
I love elopements.
I've set my heart on Rawdon
running away with someone.
A rich someone
or a poor someone?
Well, above all,
a clever someone.
He's the dearest of creatures,
but not the wisest.
What's the matter?
Oh, it's the lobster.
They've poisoned me
with the lobster.
Off you go.
Sir Pitt? Mm.
Can I not be of any assistance?
L- I don't think so, madam.
The doctor is with her now.
The best we can do
is pray, pray for her soul.
Mm.
And for her
hundred thousand.
Ohh.
Will she live, Doctor?
Well, I've pumped her.
I've purged her.
There's nothing more I can do.
Now, it rests with the Lord.
Uh, would you like to settle
with me now, Sir Pitt?
Tomorrow,
if you don't mind, Doctor.
I only pays on results.
How do I look?
A good deal stronger.
They will be disappointed.
Lady Southdown hovers
at the door night and noon.
"Mm-mm, I always travel
with my medicine chest.
"Can I not be of any assistance...
with my special tonics?"
That's a dose I doubt I'd live through.
Nonsense!
It's Captain Rawdon
that needs you dead.
Lady Southdown and Mr. Pitt Crawley
want you well enough to change your will.
Rebecca Sharp,
I've made up my mind.
You must come with me
to London.
I insist upon it,
and so does Byron.
And we won't be gainsaid,
will we?
But what could I say
to dear Sir Pitt,
after all his kindness?
Oh, leave him to me.
When a man has two sons
and a rich spinster sister,
he seldom gainsays her,
my dear.
Must you go, Rawdon?
Uh, l-I thought you might stay
for some shooting.
Oh, no. I... I thought it best
to see them safely back home...
to, uh, Mayfair.
Clear the way, there!
There she goes,
the best little governess
the girls ever had.
Mm, mm.
Suppose I better write to
Miss Pinkerton for a replacement.
Let me, Sir Pitt.
Mm, Miss Pinkerton is an old friend,
and I should so like to be useful.
Mm.
Meddlesome old cat.
"My dear, Miss Pinkerton, mm.
"Apupil of yours has recently
come to my notice, mm.
"I should so like to know
more ofher history.
Her name is Rebecca Sharp. '"
The governor will miss you.
Sir Pitt has been good to me.
Who wouldn't be?
Apples! Juicy apples!
Come on, people!
Juicy apples!
Welcome to London.
Oh, goodness.! Look busy.
The mistress is home.!
Here we are, my dear.
Who was that?
It's my neighbor,
the Marquess of Steyne.
Why?
No reason.
Are you going out?
I'm meeting Tarquin and Villiers.
And the rest of the chaps.
We might play some billiards.
Ah, yeah.
Lord Tarquin
and the HonorableJohn Villiers.
It is not done to pronounce
"the Honorable" aloud.
Well, well.
You know these things
better than I.
What I wonder is: Do they ask
you to their homes, these chaps?
Do you meet their mothers
and their sisters?
Sometimes.
Because you shall not want,
you know?
The British merchant's son
shan't want.
You may marry whom you please
and keep her well.
Father.
George is engaged.
It's understood...
Then it can be un-understood.
Don't you see, boy?
There's nothing you can't have
if you will reach for it.
Why not a viscount's daughter?
Better yet, an earl's.
Or marry an heiress
and buy a peerage for yourself!
You shouldn't read in a carriage.
It will make you sick.
Reading always makes me sick.
Who's it from?
My friend, Amelia Sedley.
I thought she might have set a date
for her marriage, but it seems not.
And who is her intended?
Captain George Osborne.
Osborne?
Any relation to the Duke of Leeds?
Oh, no, ma'am.
He's a tradesman's son.
Oh!
I know Osborne.
He's in one of the line regiments.
He's as green as this grass...
and will go to the deuce
to be seen with a lord.
Captain Osborne's vanity
must make him a tempting victim.
I say, Aunt. Why don't we do
Miss Sharp a favor...
and invite them over?
If you think it would be amusing.
I am glad to see
Miss Crawley knows your worth.
As long as George knows yours.
Of course he does.
- Shall I play for you?
- Oh, thank you, my dear.
Rawdon, will you explain
the rules of piquet to Miss Sedley?
- I've quite forgotten.
- Be careful, Amelia.
Captain Crawley
knows his cards.
I'm warned.
Oh, there are
no fortunes in piquet.
All the same, be kind to her.
She is my only friend.
Not your only friend,
Miss Sharp.
Rawdon, you explain.
Now, come along.
- You may discard up to five.
- Oh, do go away.
So, Miss Sharp.
- How do you like your new place?
- My place?
How kind of you to remind me.
It's quite tolerable, thank you.
And they treat me very well.
But then,
this is a gentleman's family...
and quite a change
from tradespeople.
You seemed to like tradespeople
well enough last year.
Joseph Sedley, you mean?
It's true.
If he'd asked me,
I would not have said no.
How very obliging of you.
I know what you're thinking.
What an honor to have had you
for a brother-in-law.
Captain George Osborne,
son ofJohn Osborne, Esquire,
son of...
what was your grandfather?
Never mind.
You cannot help your pedigree.
Miss Sharp.
Come and take over from Rawdon.
He's worse than useless.
Ah, 'tis true.
This is not my game.
Osborne, would you care to come
and play something a little more grown up?
Bye!
Do thank
Miss Crawley for us!
Crawley. Miss Sharp.
Are you cross with me?
Cross? I could kiss you.
To see George Osborne fleeced
makes the perfect end to the perfect day.
Oh, dear!
I was rather hoping
the evening wasn't over yet.
Oh?
I was wondering...
if you might like to
show me your room.
Of course.
I'll run and ask
Miss Crawley's permission.
Don't joke.
Really, Captain.
You cannot imagine I would do anything
to incur your aunt's displeasure.
I thought you and I
had an understanding.
Well, I understand this.
Two men and two men only
will enter my bed chamber...
my husband and the doctor.
You know my heart, Becky.
You know
I'd do anything for you.
I'm flattered.
But Aunt Tilly's
views on these things
came out of the Ark.
That's not how she sounds.
Oh, don't be deceived.
She talks like Oliver Cromwell
but thinks like Charles I,
and, believe me,
it's an outside wager
she'll ever change her mind.
It's lucky, then, Captain,
that you're a gambling man...
and no stranger
to taking a chance.
"Dearest Becky, a letter from Jos
arrived from India this morning...
filled with regrets
about a certain person."
Has Miss Sharp
taken to Mayfair?
She seems quite at home
in her new life.
I do not doubt it.
I had thought her
a mere social climber.
I see now
she's a mountaineer.
"I should tell him, dear Becky,
"he has missed his chance
for his goddess has acquired
other suitors.
Your loving friend,
Amelia Sedley. '"
Aahhh.
This one's for you.
It's from Mr. Pitt.
Read it.
"Dear Aunt,
I have both happy
and sad news to relay.
"The good news
is that I'm married.
LadyJane Sheepshanks has done me
the honor of becoming my wife."
Well, no great surprise there.
Well, she's a nice enough girl.
Although, I don't envy him
his mother-in-law.
What's the bad news?
"I am sorry to tell you
that my stepmother, Lady Crawley,
has gone to a better place."
After Queen's Crawley,
almost anywhere's a better place.
Come on!
The best thing for you, my girl,
would be...
No, no. Too strict.
Hmm. Thank you.
Madam,
would you consider, um...
Good gracious!
Here's Sir Pitt!
Oh, my dear, l-l-I can't see him.
My mood,
my nerves won't stand it.
- Go away.!
- Yes, Sir Pitt.
Ah, good.!
It's-It's not Miss Crawley
I want to see, it's you.
You have to come back
to Queen's Crawley.
You've heard my news?
Only just now.
I'm very sorry.
If there's anything I can do...
There is. There's plenty for you to do.
Everything's wrong since you left.
You must come back!
Well...
Marry me!
Come back as Lady Crawley,
if you like.
But do come back!
What? Oh!
- Don't leave me down here forever.
- Oh, Sir Pitt.
I can't.
Can't or won't?
Wouldn't you like to be
an old man's darling?
No, Sir Pitt, I really can't.
The truth is, I'm married already.
Married?
Oh well, it was worth a try.
Well, what a chance is lost!
Never mind, my dear,
we'll set him up,
won't we, brother?
I'll buy him a shop
or commission a portrait.
Whoever he is, he and his family
are very lucky to have you.
- I hope you think so.
- Indeed I do.
Then if you cannot take me
for a wife and sister,
will you not love me
as daughter and niece?
What?
Dear Sir Pitt,
dearest Miss Crawley, it's true.
I've married Rawdon.
Rawdon!
My... Rawdon?
Coal!
Pick 'em up, boy.
Look after her, Firkin.
Poor, dear Miss Crawley.
I do worry so.
Don't waste your syrup
on me, Miss Sharp.
Just get back in the knife box
where you belong.
Are you all right, Miss?
I will be if you're going past Baker Street.
Would that be proper, Miss?
More proper than
standing here in the street.
Now give us a hand
with the trunk.
You...
We'll be in Queer Street
if she don't come round.
I'd rather be in Queer Street with you
than Park Lane with any other.
But, Rawdon, she will come round.
She said herself, she'd love you to elope.
It's all talk, you know.
She loves romance in her novels,
but not in her family.
Where they're concerned,
she's as snobbish as Queen Charlotte.
Well, then...
We'll have to send
an ambassador to plead our case.
Oh, yes?
Mm.
What kind of ambassador
would that be?
I'd say a very little one,
with rosy cheeks and blue eyes,
and probably not too much hair.
What?
You mean...
Oh, you brilliant, darling girl.
Well, that will mend fences
if nothing else will.
Oh, Becky!
When one thinks of how she tended you.
And all the time...
Oh, I should have guessed that
nobody does anything for nothing.
But for a pauper's daughter,
a penniless governess,
to make off with my Rawdon.
Ohh.
Oh, dear.
Oh, at least her mother was a Montmorency.
I suppose we must cling to that.
Not a bit of it. I have it
on the best authority.
Her mother was an opera girl
in the chorus at Montmartre!
- What?
- I have it on the best authority.
Yes, yes, yes! All right!
Oh, very well. I know what I must do.
Would you be so kind
as to bring my little desk here?
Certainly. Where is it?
Where's her little desk? I can't see it.
It's over here.
- I almost feel sorry for poor Rawdon.
- Mm...
But I cannot let that girl
profit from her scheming.
Nor should you.
I'm glad to see that
you've changed your opinions.
Firkin.
Do you remember when
you told us all at Queen's Crawley...
That you adored imprudent marriages?
Not in real life.
What do you want?
Time, Osborne, that's what I want.
I owe you nothing.!
I will give you nothing.!
You owe me friendship.!
You have no friendship
coming from me, sir.!
Oh!
Do we have enough of this china?
It's to be a buffet and I don't
want to risk the Crown Derby.
Oh, listen to this.
"Emperor Napoleon Escapes
from Elba and Marches on Paris.
Allies Prepare for War. '"
- Amelia, what's the matter, dear?
- Will it affect George?
Well, he's a soldier, isn't he,
for all his swagger,
and there's more to soldiering
than gold braid and regimental dinners.
Amelia?
Amelia!
Oh!
If she means to be a soldier's wife,
she must learn to bear such things.
Now, I've been thinking about...
I must tell you.
I can put it off no longer.
We're ruined, Mary. Lost.
Everything is gone.
But we're giving a soiree.
There'll be no more soirees
or balls or dinners either.
That life, finished for us.
Oh, my God!
The debt that finished me, the man
who tipped me into the abyss,
is none other than
George's father, John Osborne.
By order of the trustees of the Sedley
Estate, this auction will now commence.
Lot 368, an inlaid ebony writing desk.
Shall we say... four guineas? Five?
Any more? Come on.
Going, going...
Sold.
Lot 369.
A Clemency
Drawing Room Piano.
I sang to that.
Would you like it?
We will start at three guineas.
Four?
- Five.
- Five at the back.
- Six.
- It's Captain Dobbin.
Seven? Eight?
I know him.
He's in the Ninth.
Nine? Ten.
Any more?
Sold to the captain.
Lot 370.
A landscape painting signed,
"Francis Sharp, 1801. '"
What? What's the matter?
My father painted it.
I gave it to Amelia.
- I'll get it for you.
- Shall we say, five guineas?
Six, at the back. Seven.
Eight. Nine.
Ten. Eleven. Twelve.
Thirteen. Fourteen.
Fifteen, at the back.
Going once. Going twice...
Leave it.
It doesn't matter.
Sold for 15 guineas
to the Marquess of Steyne.
Why would Lord Steyne
bother with a little auction like this?
He collects my father's works.
A true collector will go anywhere
to get what he wants.
An amboyna and rosewood
quartetto table.
- Captain Dobbin.
- Miss Sharp.
I beg your pardon,
Mrs. Crawley. Crawley.
Are you taking up
the piano, Captain?
I have a... friend who will
get some use of it, I think.
Any more?
- Indeed she will.
- Good day.
Going... Sold.
I saw Miss Sharp
at the auction this morning.
How is George?
George is well, I think. But busy.
Too busy to come here.
I'll fetch some tea.
When you next see him,
will you give him this?
I painted it.
It's not wrong, is it, to remind him
of the one who loves him most?
Of course not.
Oh, look what he's done!
Oh, isn't he wonderful?
I can't believe it!
Oh, thank God!
Thank God!
Mama! It's all right!
George has bought me the piano,
and he'll be here directly.
Oh, thank God!
I tell you, George, you must go to her.
She's dying.
Miss Sedley asked me to give you
this when I saw you next.
For God's sake, George.
You haven't even opened it.
No need.
They're all the same.
Georgy.! What are you playing at?
We're waiting for you.
Good day to you, Captain Dobbin.
I'm just leaving, sir.
Good.
There's a friend of Maria's
they want me to meet.
Ah, uh, may I present
my son, George?
This is Miss Rhoda Swartz.
Miss Rhoda was talking aboutJamaica
and her sugar plantations there.
Although I don't remember it.
I left when I was three.
Maria, may I borrow you
for a moment, please?
Can you forgive us?
Your father does not much
trouble to conceal his plans.
Which are?
For us to marry, of course.
Indeed.
Come. Sit by me.
Let us speak frankly.
My fortune is great, my birth is not.
So, I must choose
between a poor nobleman...
or a rich bourgeois like you.
Upon my word, you've
a very precise grasp of the matter.
I would have liked a title.
But my guardian says,
if you and I combine our fortunes,
we may buy one
whenever we wish.
I cannot believe you are
seriously suggesting Miss Swartz...
as the companion of
my heart and hearth!
Why not?
Well, to begin with,
she's not English.
Hoity-toity!
Less fastidious, if you please!
What's a shade or two of tawny when
there's half a million on the table?
Why, with that money, we'll have you
in the House of Lords in no time.
Just think. Dining at Kew,
dancing at Carlton House.
- And what of honor?
- Honor?
Yes. Honor.
You may buy a string of ancestors
to hang upon your walls,
but I see you have not bought
the breeding that goes with them.
- You made me give my word to Amelia.
- Be silent, sir!
You dare speak
that object's name to me?
"Dare," sir, is not a word to be
used to a captain in the British army.
For I am a gentleman,
though I am your son.
I'll say what I like to my own child.
And I say this:
I have not slaved for 40 years
to see you marry a beggar maid!
You made the match!
And I can unmake it!
You will marry whom I say, sir.
And I say you will marry Miss Swartz.
Either that or take your pack and walk
out of this house without a shilling.!
Do I make myself clear, sir?
As a bell, sir.
Georgy. Georgy.
Come on, you lads.!
War is come to Europe.!
My brother wants tojoin.!
If you're here to plead his case,
you've made a wasted journey.
Mr. Osborne, we're on the brink of war.
Should anything happen to George,
you'd never forgive yourself
if you hadn't parted in charity.
May I not take him
a message from you? Please.
Very well.
Let him only come home to his old room
and things will be as they were before.
They cannot be.
Why not, if I say they can?
Because...
George married
Miss Sedley this morning.
I go from here to
their wedding breakfast.
Will you not come with me?
Welcome, Mr. Sedley.
Sedley. Welcome home.
- Crawley.
- Righto.
Mrs. Crawley.
So,
have you found many changes
since your last visit from India?
Some.
And one in particular
that I regret very much.
Dobbin.! Osborne.!
There's news here for all of us.
It's the order for Belgium.
We embark next week.
Men need war like the soil
needs turning. I'll enjoy it!
You're surely not going
over there in your condition?
Of course I'm going!
Why should the men have all the fun?
And didn't Eleanor of Aquitaine ride
into battle pregnant and bare-breasted?
By Gad, if there's a woman alive
who could do the same, it's you.!
Be careful of the model, Mrs. Crawley.
Queen Eleanor was
locked up by her husband.
And emerged from her prison
to govern England.
Bravo.
What about you, Sedders? Will you
be joining us on our little excursion?
If it weren't for my duties in India,
I'd be over there like a shot. Oh yes.!
- I'll go.
- You cannot.
Well, why shouldn't she?
She can keep Becky company.
- To victory!
- Victory!
- To victory.
We won't know anyone.
Whose fault is that?
If you would only put yourself out
to be civil once in a while.
The Crawleys have been here
no longer than us, and Mrs. Crawley's
the talk of the town.
Is that what you would have me be,
the "talk of the town"?
Here comes the famous Mrs. Crawley.
Why she is famous
is a mystery to me.
Why does everyone receive her,
as for General Tufto?
He must find her
command of French useful.
- I know I should.
- A real lady wouldn't speak it half as well.
- Hush, my dear.
- Lady Darlington. Lady Bareacres.
Good evening, Mrs. Crawley.
Good evening.
You're making an exhibition of yourself.
Can I leave you in charge?
I see some sheep that need shearing.
Go. You manage our income,
and I'll see to your career.
Wait here a minute.
George, I feel... I feel sick.
General Tufto.
Mrs. Crawley.
Can I tempt you
with some refreshment?
That would be delightful.
Mrs. Crawley.
Yes, good evening.
I hope your dance card
isn't quite filled yet.
- Hardly. I've just arrived.
- I am the early bird, then.
And I, presumably, the worm?
General Tufto, this is
Captain Osborne of the Ninth.
That is Osborne with an "E."
Make sure you spell it right...
when you mention him
in dispatches.
If only spelling
was my forte.
My dear, please.
Thank you.
Would you like me to fetch you
some water? Or a chair?
Or a doctor?
Is Amelia all right?
I expect so. Dobbin's with her.
Shouldn't you have more care of her now?
You mean, now that yet another
rope has come to bind me?
You're not like Amelia, Mrs. Crawley.
Nothing will quench your fire.
Captain Osborne.
Will you fetch me
my shawl and my nosegay?
Of course.
I wish you'd let me come with you.
No. I mean it. Go back at once.
I'll tell George you're safe.
Don't.
It will only annoy him
that I've left the ball early.
But why did he bring you at all?
Just tell me you're happy.
We're happy enough.
How prettily the Duchess
has arranged things.
She always does. Or don't you go
to her parties back in England?
No matter. We won't
know her back in London.
- I see you've been busy.
- Very.
Osborne.
Crawley.
Ready for a hand
or two of cards?
- If Mrs. Crawley...
- Of course.
I'll leave you to it, gentlemen.
- George, don't drink anymore.
- Nonsense, Dobbs.
Come and have a drink yourself,
and light up your lantern jaw.
What's happening?
Your Grace. My lords,
ladies and gentlemen.
The enemy is past the River Sambre
and our left is already engaged.
We march in three hours.
- Becky!
- Rawdon! Rawdon!
I'm not afraid, but I'm
a big target for a shot.
And if I should go down,
I want you to know what there is.
I've had a good run here,
so you've a wad of money.
There's a horse left to sell, and...
well, those trunks
are worth 30 alone.
You mean, we owe 30 on them.
Yes.
Well, I'll wear me old uniform,
so you can sell the new one.
What with the saddles,
guns, rings and...
and this little lot...
you'll have enough
to keep you dry,
get you back to London before...
I'll manage.
Won't you just.
There never was a woman
who could manage like you,
Becky Sharp.
You won't do anything brave, will you?
Promise?
What?
Tears?
Tears from my strong little Becky?
I'm a woman in love, aren't I?
Oh, my darling.
If you should awake
to find me dead...
Shh!
You must be sure, at least, of this:
That you are a woman
who has been truly loved.
S'il vous plaît. Aidez-nous.
Somebody, please sell us a horse.!
Mrs. Crawley! Mrs. Crawley,
over here, if you please!
Lady Bareacres. What a surprise.
We sent our servant to the inn
to look for a horse,
but the only one left
is Captain Crawley's.
Fancy.
- What will you take for it?
- Nothing from you, my lady.
Don't be silly, my dear.
We've always been friends, haven't we?
- No. We have not.
- Now listen to me.
You can come with us if you wish,
but we must, and will, have that horse!
- Hmph!
- Why couldn't you be civil to the woman?
Mrs. Crawley.!
Mrs. Crawley, come back, please.!
Mrs. Crawley.! Discretion
being the better part of valor,
- I'm afraid it is time to quit Brussels.
- Are we really losing, Lord Darlington?
They say the enemy
has broken through the lines.
Which brings me to my point.
Did you sell Lady Bareacres your horse?
Doesn't anyone love me for myself alone?
You may buy it if you give me
a seat in your carriage.
- Done.
- Quickly! We must get it.
- Why must she come with us?
- First, because I like her.
Second, she's pregnant.
Third, it's the condition
upon which she gave us the horse.
Mrs. Crawley, hurry!
We must leave now!
Now! Please!
Please.! Help me.!
Has anyone seen George Osborne?
One moment.
George Osborne of the Ninth.!
Please.!
Amelia! What are you doing?
You shouldn't be out here!
Come along.
Mrs. Crawley.!
Come now, if you're coming.!
Lord Darlington, is there
room for Mrs. Osborne?
Only if you give up your place.
Don't worry about me. I'll wait
here for George, whatever comes.
We'll meet again in London.
Well, I do hope so.
Good luck to you.
Drive! Drive!
There must be news of my George!
Amelia, you must
take hold of yourself!
We're soldier's wives.
We live with uncertainty.
How would you feel if
you had spent last night alone...
while your husband danced
with another woman?
If you have stolen his last evening
from me, I shall never forgive you!
How could you say such a thing?
I won't listen to it.
If you must hear the truth,
your George is not...
What?
My George is not what?
Is not the man to see you risk
your health... or his baby.
Come inside,
and we'll wait together.
What would Miss Pinkerton
say of us now?
Two mothers-to-be
in the midst of a war.
Not quite what we studied
in etiquette class.
Are you frightened?
Of giving birth, I mean.
Hmm. You know me.
I'm tough as a nut.
I'll probably have my baby after tea and
then dance at a ball the same evening.
I'm not frightened, either.
At least, not for myself.
As long as George's child is well.
It's the bagpipes.
- But... that means...
- Victory.
Victory!
"My dearest father,
though we parted in anger,
I want you to know I will not disgrace
you in the challenge that lies ahead. '"
Mr. Osborne. Mr. Osborne.
Captain Dobbin.
Rather, I beg your pardon, Major Dobbin,
since better men than you are dead...
and you've stepped
into their shoes.
Better men are dead.
I wish to speak of one.
Make it short, sir.
You are aware his widow
has been left a pauper.
I do not know his widow.
Nor wish to.
And what of his child?
Will you not wish to know that?
It's just another consequence
of George's disobedience and folly.
She would have me give you this.
If it's a message from that woman,
I do not wish to read it.
It is a message from your son, sir.
She has carried it for you
from that day to this.
"Forgive me if you can.
"And try to remember
your loving and grateful son.
George. '"
Georgy!
My boy!
My darling boy!
- Isn't he an angel?
- An angel.
When George died I thought,
I will never have room in my heart
for anyone else.
We weren't expecting you today.
I've come to tell you
I've put in for a transfer.
- I embark next week for Bombay.
- Bombay?
Heavens. Why Bombay?
Because it is as far away
from here as I could manage.
I see.
But I will resign my commission,
and I will stay in England...
- if you ask me to.
- If I ask you to?
I will not go if you tell me not to.
You must seeJos
when you get there.
I can write to you?
Tell you how Georgy is doing?
William, l...
l...
The agents will forward any letters.
Well, good-bye.
We'll meet again one day.
Good-bye.
This one here stays.
Come, come, Rawdy.
This is your new home!
Scullery, dining room,
boudoir.
Oh!
I'm sorry to be the bearer
of sad tidings, Colonel.
You know how I esteemed your aunt.
There was no suffering.
Mr. Pitt and LadyJane looked
after her tenderly until the end.
I'll bet they did.
Right. Let me know if there's
anything more I can do for you.
She cut me out.
Pitt has swept the pool.
Oh, Becky,
it's you and Rawdy
I feel sorry for.
Don't.
It'll come right. You'll see.
I'm a governess, and you're a gambler.
We were never going to shoot into society.
It'll take time.
What will we eat in the meantime?
Oh, my dear, let me manage that.
We're Crawleys,
and Crawleys have credit.
You'll be surprised to see how well
we can live on practically nothing a year.
Excuse me, ma'am. Master Rawdy
has something to show you.
What is it, Nurse?
Walking.!
Well, if those aren't
the stoutest steps...
I've ever seen a young man take.
Why, you'll be marching
to the colors in no time, my boy.
- Come!
- Yes!
Ya-ha! Rawdy!
How are you today, my boy? Huh?
Fine, sir.
Good. Here we go.
- Yes?
- Are you a soldier, sir?
Yes, my boy. I am.
My papa was a soldier, sir.
He fell at Waterloo.
I'm sorry to hear that.
What was his name?
Captain George Osborne,
sir, of the Ninth.
Oh, but I knew him well.
Stop!
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
Oh, for heaven's sake, Maria.
Out with it.
It's just that I was driving in
the park the other day, and...
And?
And, and, and, and, and?
Father. I saw little George.
He was with Mr. Sedley,
and I knew him at once.
He's as beautiful as an angel.
And... And so like him.
Dash it, Becky.
Is this really the best we can manage?
There's my desk. Here's the key.
If you can find a spare penny piece
in it, I'll take my hat off to you.
Unless you mean for once
to make a contribution.
The whole animal
was made of scrag end!
If only the butcher didn't want
to be paid. How can he be so selfish?
Don't be hard on me, old girl.
I've had a run ofbad luck.
Things'll get better.
That Mr. Moss is here.
I've brought him up.
Take him back down again,
damn you. Until we've finished eating!
- Rawdon, please.
- Needs must, Colonel.
And I hope you've got
good news for me.
I'm sorry, Mr. Moss,
but we're not magicians.
We can't give you the money
if we haven't got it.
Why not? You can spend it
when you haven't got it.
Oh, you're wasted as a bailiff.
You should write for the stage.
And you should go on it.
You're a good enough actress.
That is enough! We cannot pay it,
and there it is. Now get out.
All right, I'll go.
But I'll be back.
Clear the way there!
Get out of the way!
Is this really your home then?
Yes, it is.
How is such a thing possible?
What do you want with me, sir?
I have a proposal to put to you.
Why do you do that, Mama?
It is so degrading.
I do it so we can eat.
Hunger is degrading too.
That is our food, Georgy!
It is not a toy!
I hate our food.
And I have no toys.
None that I want anyway.
How can you be so cruel?
Cruel?
When he might have had
the finest education money could buy.
When he could have been
as rich as a lord.
And his own mother
steals his future...
because she wants to
tuck him up in bed.
"A mother's love is worth
more than palaces in Mayfair."
Do you not remember
what Major Dobbin wrote?
- Pray don't talk about Major Dobbin.
- Why not?
What's the point,
now he's engaged?
What?
Oh, didn't you read Joseph's letter?
"How are you, my dear Amelia?
"And how is all your little family?
"If you did but know how brightly
your image burns for me...
"and how I dream of you
and Georgy hand-in-hand.
"Every detail of your daily life
is precious to me...
as I sit and write
beneath the Indian sun. '"
"Dear William.
"Thank you for your letter which took
three months to reach me... Mother?
But was very welcome when it did. '"
Mother, what are you doing here?
I was coming to see you on Saturday.
"Georgy is in good health...
I made Georgy some shirts.
And living with his grandfather. '"
I was going to leave them for him.
Oh, Mother. I couldn't wear
your funny old shirts now.
Good day to you, madam.
Come along, Georgy.
You are silly, Mama.
- Silly old Mama!
- "I am persuaded it is better.
So, for his sake, I must submit. '"
Listen, Dobbs, if you'd rather
leave it for some other time,
I can easily find someone else.
No. No, no, I'm coming.
"I confess it was with quite a pang that I
read Joseph's news of your engagement. '"
What?
Dobbs, I can't breathe!
Good Lord, Dobbs.
Have you lost your mind altogether?
It's time I returned to England.
Here's your medicine, Sir Pitt.
Take it away. There's no medicine
can cure what ails me.
I'm dying, Horrocks.
This is the end.
Oh, come, Sir Pitt.
Shall I fetch Mr. Pitt?
Or the doctor?
Or the lawyer?
That's the question, Horrocks.
Pitt's had Tilly's money.
Shall he have mine too?
Or should it go to Rawdon? Hmm?
And foxy little Becky?
I can fetch the lawyer
if you want me to, sir.
Uh? Oh, no.
No. Let Pitt have it all. Yeah.
He's a pompous beggar,
but he'll keep
this old place together.
And your piano practice?
I hope you've not been neglecting it.
No, Miss... I mean Mrs. Crawley.
I'm glad to hear it.
You must play for me.
And, Rose,
what is your best subject?
French.
No airs. No bid to bury
her governess's past.
You cannot dislike her for that, surely?
No. I agree.
Not for that.
Uh, Rawdon, after luncheon,
perhaps you'd like to see my pamphlet
on the emancipation issue?
Oh, God, help me.
Uh, Mrs., uh, Crawley,
when you told Miss Crawley
that your mother
was a Montmorency...
I never said that. I spoke once
of the Montmorencys, but that's all.
She must have misunderstood me.
My mother sang opera.
- Mm.
- Mm-hmm.
What shall we do after luncheon?
Well, we are in mourning.
Uh, uh, yes.
Y-You are right to say so,
but I don't think my father's death
should banish all social converse.
Then what I should like to do best
would be to play something
with our little boys.
Little Pitt has not been well.
W-Well, I gave Little Pitt
some tonic before lunch.
- I remember how your medicines
helped poor Miss Crawley.
- Mm.
Well...
L... We...
We're all, uh, family here,
so l-I feel we may speak openly.
L- I hope, um, Aunt Matilda's
final disposition...
h-h-has not...
Miss Crawley gave me the most
wonderful husband in the world.
How could I be angry with her?
I'm glad her fortune will restore
the glory of this place and this family,
of which I'm proud to be a member.
Ohh.
It is we Crawleys, madam,
who are the gainers by your marriage.
- Thank you.
- Mm.
Bye, Rawdy!
Bye, Auntie Becky.!
Bye, Uncle Rawdon.! Bye.!
I like AuntJane.
Don't you, Papa?
I do. Pitt's lucky there.
She's kind and good.
I could be good on 5,000 a year.
Oh, do you not care for her, then?
What does that matter?
Don't you see what this means?
We're back in the family.
At long last we've begun.
Careful of that table now.
That's valuable, that is.
Excuse me!
What are you doing?
I told you I'd be back, lady.
Here, look, you'd better wrap up
that cooker glass.
No! How dare you try and bring out
my things on the street!
Here, let me have that!
I'll call the constable!
You can call the King for all I care!
Give it back to me!
I'm takin' it!
You're not having this!
Give it to me!
I wonder if I might be of some help.
A pleasure doing business.
Just go.
We meet at last.
I know you, Lord Steyne,
you do not know me.
You will have forgotten, but you were
kind to my father once, many years ago.
I am seldom praised for...
for being kind.
What was his name?
Francis Sharp.
You are Francis Sharp's daughter?
He had a great talent
for painting, as I recall,
and none at all for life.
I'm attempting to redress that balance.
It is my challenge.
I've watched you in the lists.
I wish you luck.
It will not be easy.
Of course, it's the women
who keep the doors of society closed.
They do not like outsiders to discover
that there's nothing behind them.
Should you like to come
to Gaunt House?
Very much, my lord.
You will be bored there.
My wife is as gay as Lady Macbeth...
and my daughters-in-law
as cheerful as Goneril and Regan.
They will bully you and snub you
and patronize you.
But that's what you want, I suppose.
It is.
You should take this.
You don't want him
back tomorrow.
You're playing with fire, Becky.
Dearest, be reasonable.
You can pander all you like
to the great and the good.
We're not their type,
never will be.
Of course we are.
You have the best blood in England
in your veins if only you'd use it.
You know,
Lord Steyne's planning a dinner
next week with the Minister of War.
He promises to talk
of nothing but you.
The cards are in your hand, darling.
Must I show you how to play them?
So now you are to instruct me
in games of chance?
I just want you to think
on the winnings.
Oh, I know what we have to win.
I'm just afraid of what we might lose.
You're taking favors
from a tiger, Becky.
I'm not afraid.
Keep your eyes open.
♪ Come with me ♪
♪ And we will go ♪
Must I repeat myself?
You will write a card to
Colonel and Mrs. Crawley.
But Blanche writes them.
Not this time, I don't.
Lady Steyne, I cannot believe...
that I am compelled
to issue a request three times.
I will write it.
Then I will not be present.
I will go home.
Good! Stay there!
Let me be free of
your damned tragedy airs.!
Who are you to give orders?
You're here to have children
and you're barren!
My son is sick of you.!
There's no one in the house
that doesn't wish you dead.!
Besides, what's the matter
with Mrs. Crawley?
She's not well born, it's true,
but she's no worse than
Fanny's illustrious ancestor,
the first de la Jones.
- The money I brought to this family, sir...
- Purchased my second son as a husband...
whom the whole world
knows is mad.
Enough.
This is my house.
If I invite the trash from every prison
and brothel in London,
you will receive them
and you'll make them welcome.
Remember. You have no friends
beyond this door.
Lady Bareacres, what did you
make of the new Figaro?
I thought it was quite interesting.
I hear you sing
and play beautifully,
Mrs. Crawley.
I wish you'd sing for me.
It would be my pleasure.
What are you doing?
I've seen enough cruelty
in this house to want to inflict it.
"Now Sleeps the Crimson Petal."
♪ Now sleeps the crimson petal ♪
♪ Now the white ♪
♪ Nor waves the cypress
in the palace walk ♪
♪ Nor winks the gold fin
in the porphyry font ♪
♪ The firefly wakens ♪
♪ Waken thou with me ♪
♪ Now droops the milkwhite peacock ♪
♪ Like a ghost ♪
♪ And like a ghost
she glimmers on to me ♪
♪ Now lies the Earth
all Danae to the stars ♪
♪ And all thy heart lies open unto me ♪
♪ Now folds the lily
all her sweetness up ♪
♪ And slips into the bosom of the lake ♪
♪ So fold thyself, my dearest, thou ♪
♪ And slip ♪
♪ Into my bosom ♪
♪ And be lost ♪
♪ In me ♪
Bravo. Bravo.
You are through the door.
That boy of yours,
when does he go away to school?
Oh, when he's older, I suppose.
No, no. He must learn to stand
on his own two feet at once.
Miss that lesson in childhood
and you'll miss it all your life.
Well, I'm not sure Rawdon
could spare him yet.
And he's very spirited.
I shall arrange it.
No need to thank me.
Perhaps then we could
see a little more of each other.
Aren't you forgetting my husband?
I never forget anything,
Mrs. Crawley.
Least of all an unpaid debt.
She hasn't been at all well, has she?
Must I go?
Must I really?
Can't I stay
if I promise to be good?
It won't be for long, old chap.
Yes, it will.
Come here.
It's time, darling.
Bye.
Tonight, Lord Steyne will unveil
his mystery performance...
directed by himself
and performed by the Duchess of Lancaster,
the Countess of Slingstone
and other great ladies
ofhis lordship's acquaintance.
Your Majesty, my lords,
ladies and gentlemen, please be seated.
The entertainment is about to begin.
What has Steyne got planned,
Lady Steyne?
I wish I knew.
Extraordinary.
- Steyne the Pasha and his nautch girls.
- I give you the ballet Zirnana.
It's Mrs. Crawley.
Well done, all.
Bravo.! Bravo.!
Extraordinary.
- Yes.
- Bravo.!
Ah, Mrs. Crawley.
To the victor the spoils.
You have carried off
our hearts in triumph.
If that is so, Your Majesty,
then you may rest easy
that your heart will be
well looked after.
That is a relief, for it has been
bruised in its time.
You must tell me at dinner
how you mean to treat it.
You will sit next to me.
Precedence would make that
a little difficult, sir.
I am the King, Lady Gaunt.
I confer precedence.
Well, are you happy?
I said that I would make you
queen of the night and I have.
I'm certainly grateful, my lord.
But not happy?
Well, which of us is happy?
Not you? Surely you take
pleasure in your pictures.
Yes.
I can hide behind them.
You, my lord, hide from what?
From the simple truth that is known
to every shepherd and footman...
that the only thing of value
in this life is to love...
and be loved.
I've hidden from it because
I didn't think that I would ever find it.
Now I believe I have.
You jest with me, my lord.
I make a poor companion with
the splendors that surround you.
The chief advantage
of being born into society...
is that one learns early
what a tawdry puppet play it is.
You remember the child
who set a high price on this picture...
before she could bear to see it go?
Not high enough.
The trouble is, Mrs. Crawley,
you've taken the goods.
It's too late to query the price.
Colonel Crawley.
May I walk with you?
By all means, Wenham.
Good evening, Colonel.
Oh, Lord!
It's a small thing, Colonel.
£165 you owe Mr. Nathan.
For God's sake, Wenham, lend me 100.
I have 70 at home.
I'm sorry. I don't have £10
in the whole world,
my dear fellow.
Don't worry.
Mr. Moss will take good care
of you, won't you, Mr. Moss?
I run the most comfortable
debtor's prison in London.
Come on.
Unhand me!
Good night.
You sure I can't get
you anything, Colonel?
My wife will be here
at any moment.
If you say so, sir.
Ring the bell when you
want something.
- You did deliver my letter, yes?
- I delivered it myself, sir.
Is there no one else
I might call on?
My brother, I suppose.
But I hardly like to trouble him
when I know that Becky will be
on her way before too long.
Even so, sir.
Poor Rawdon. He's in prison.
I know.
I'll send my man Wenham
with the bail tomorrow.
One night won't kill him.
Heaven knows
he's on familiar territory.
Oh, Becky. Thank God.
It is I, Rawdon. It's Jane.
When your note came, I read it.
I've paid Mr. Moss.
This is no place for a woman like you.
You should not have come here.
I'm not worth it.
Yes, you are.
You are worth it.
I want to change, Jane.
I mean to make a different life
for Rawdy and I.
At least I mean to try.
Then you will succeed.
Now, get your things
and I'll take you home.
I must apologize...
for my excessive zeal.
You need no forgiveness from me.
Oh, but I do.
I need your forgiveness.
And your love.
Suppose my wish is to finish now,
if I ask no other favor?
You've had your wishes,
Mrs. Crawley.
Crawley. What kept you?
Nothing happened, Rawdon.
I beg you to believe me.
I'm innocent.
What are you two scheming about?
Tell him I'm innocent.
You, innocent?
When my money has bought
every trinket on your body?
Let me pass, sir.
You cowardly, villainous liar!
Rawdon! Rawdon, don't!
What are you doing?
Come here!
Take off that necklace.
Now get out!
Open it! Open it.
I want to know
if you or he are lying.
Open it!
A thousand pounds.
You might have spared me
a hundred, Becky.
I always shared with you.
Rawdon! Rawdon, wait!
Please.! Forgive me.
Wait! Wait!
I made a grave mistake.
I'm sorry.
You cannot know
the journey that I have made.
Oh, I should.
I traveled with you.
Not from the beginning.
Please, Rawdon.
In my way, I've loved you.
Then that is your misfortune.
Good-bye, Rebecca.
"Following the premature death
of His Excellency,
the Governor of Coventry Island,
"we hear the post is to be offered to
the distinguished veteran of Waterloo,
Colonel Rawdon Crawley."
Well, this is excellent.
Excellent be damned!
The place is a graveyard,
and it is Steyne who sends me to it.
Well, whatever the reason,
this is a chance
and you must take it.
Good boy. Steady now.
My life has not been much.
Everything I've touched
has turned to dust,
except that boy.
Would you take care of him for me?
Rawdon, I promise you
I will love him as my own.
I do already.
God bless you.
Brother.
Him.
Who? Who said that?
Of course.
Madame de Crawley.
Off to work.
Place your bets.
I'm sorry, I don't speak...
Is this your first time in the casino?
And if it is?
You must use
your beginner's luck wisely.
The chance will not come again.
George. What would Amelia say
if she knew you were here?
Not now, Dobbin.
May I present...
But I know the major very well.
Mrs. Crawley.
Don't tell me it is
the infamous Mrs. Crawley.
George.
It is, sir. So your mother must
be traveling on the continent.
Your grandfather
forgave her in the end?
He did, God bless him.
He left her well provided for.
We've been traveling
with my mother's friend.
Alas, Major Dobbin,
are you still only her friend?
Come.
You must see Mama.
Come tomorrow.
We're at the Erbprinz Hotel.
She won't want to be disturbed.
Major Dobbin, I don't
remember you for a tease.
I would love to.
Tell her I'll be there
in the morning.
You must have known my father.
Do you think I'm like him?
Very.
It is not your place
to issue invitations.
But if she's an old friend...
She's an old acquaintance.
It's not the same.
Your mother won't wish to see her.
Of course I want to see her.
Becky. How could I not?
That little devil brings mischief
wherever she goes.
She killed her husband.
He died of tropical fever.
You can hardly lay that at her door.
Can't I?
They took her son from her.
Rubbish.
Rawdon took the boy away
because cats are better mothers.
And what do you know of motherhood?
You have no child.
Don't I know it?
And if I have any authority
in this house...
Authority?
You have none, sir.
Who do you think you are?
My father?
My husband?
You're right.
I know what your heart
is capable of.
It can cling faithfully
to a misty memory
and cherish a dream,
but it cannot recognize
or return a love like mine.
- L-I have been your friend.
- No.
You have allowed me
to be your friend.
We have spent enough of our lives
at this play, Amelia.
Let this end.
We are both weary of it.
When his cousin died, I knew
Rawdy would spend his life
at Queen's Crawley.
He belongs there.
But you must see him.
Why don't you?
Does LadyJane prevent it?
No. Jane would not
keep me from him.
But Rawdy has
become a great man.
I love him and I wish him well,
but my place is no longer with him.
Tell me, how is Major Dobbin?
I passed him as I came here,
looking very fierce.
We have fallen out.
Over me?
Over you, yes,
but over other things as well.
Amelia Osborne, you're a damn fool.
He is your dearest friend.
It matters not what he thinks of me.
You should go and fetch him.
I cannot, Rebecca.
You don't know what lies between us.
I do.
Ever since I saw him buy that piano,
I've known how it stood between you.
That was George.
It was Dobbin.
- I saw him with my own eyes.
- George loved me.
George Osborne loved
no one but himself.
He'd have jilted you but for Dobbin
and left you if he'd lived.
Stop! Silence.
Dobbin was right.
Wherever you go, you trail wickedness
and heartache in your wake.
I came prepared for this.
George gave this to me at
the Duchess of Richmond's Ball.
Whatever it is, I will not read it.
"My darling, Becky, won't you save me
from a life of dreary toil?
Fly with me.
We will dance our way
across Europe. Your George. '"
That is the man you have
made your life a shrine to.
I've been a fool.
We have all been fools.
But you may still
remedy your folly. Go.!
Hurry.
In the back.
Wait! Wait!
My Angel, take compassion upon us.
Dine with Fritz and me at the inn
in the park. We'll die if you don't.
Tomorrow maybe.
Ask me again tomorrow.
Today I'm a little tired.
I'm looking for a Madame de Crawley.
Can you tell me
where I might find her?
Mr. Sedley?
Mr. Joseph Sedley?
What are you doing in Germany?
ByJove.
Have I found you?
Amelia said you were here.
Is it truly the beautiful Mrs. Crawley?
I'm on my way back to India.
India.
My gad, Mrs. Crawley.
What a turn up.
I do hope that traveling
will not tire you.
Oh, no, Mr. Sedley.
You know I love to visit new places.
It's so beautiful.