Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Nam...
What are you doing?
Nam...my memory comes back.
What happened?
Nothing.
I make this breakfast especially for you.
See, Chinese style, Western style.
Want any strawberry jam?
You want me to buy you something?
I want to have a baby!
Are you serious?
But we have to get married first.
Ask grandma!
No, she always mistakes me for Smartie.
By the way...
Comparing Smartie with me...
Who is more attractive?
Is she more lovely?
Or, am I more elegant?
Or, my character is better than hers?
She has a bad temper.
Or, I look more like a lady.
And she looks more like a rascal?
Overall, who is better?
You really want to know?
Tell me!
Go ask her in the underworld.
Don't ask me these kind of questions.
Democratic Progressive Party's candidate
Chen Shui Bian has swept a victory.
Defeated Nationalist Party's Lien Chen
and independent James Soong
with nearly 5 million votes,
becoming the new leader of Taiwan.
Taiwan department of
the Communist Party's Central Committee
and The State Council's Taiwan Office
issued a statement
reiterating that the result of
the recent election cannot change the fact
that Taiwan is a part of China,
and warn that China will not tolerate
any form of "Taiwan independence".
To judge the new leader of Taiwan...
Just came back from Taiwan?
Yes, the presidential election was finished.
It is none of your business.
Cousin and I joined the election campaign.
Really?
Chicken, which team did you support?
Lian Zhan, Chen Shui Bian,
or French soccer team?
San Luen Gang used to
support the Nationalist Party.
We thought our candidate would win, but...
He lost big. What can I do?
It is always true, the winner is the king.
No fun, so I came back. Play something else.
Like what?
Marriage.
Are you serious?
Of course, I don't want to though.
A political deal!
Who is the youngest in San Luen Gang? Me.
Who is the most handsome? Me.
But, you are used to fooling around with girls.
What is her name?
Kusakari Nanako!
Nanako? Is she the girl in the porno VCDs?
The one moaning so loud?
No, that one is the famous cook, Ms. Fong.
Chicken, you can't speak Japanese.
How can you communicate with your wife?
We use body language.
How...
How to communicate with her?
It is simple. You know.
In fact, her father is Kusakari Ichio.
He is...
the fifth generation chief
of Yamada Gang in Japan.
The fifth evolution?
No way...what does it mean?
He is the fifth generation leader in the Gang.
San Luen Gang assigns me
to marry his daughter.
An arranged marriage?
Marriage of convenience?
If it is true, we will all go to Japan
for your wedding.
Great, let's go now.
But you have to stay here.
I need to make a trip to Japan.
Willi, make an appointment
with Mr. Chiang for me.
Yes.
Chicken.
This is uncle Hing's son.
Brother Chicken. Willi.
He studies law.
Is it boring?
Shaking hands is outdated.
Money back!
No way! In your face!
Bastard!
Stop fighting, boys!
Why does watching a soccer game
turn into a violent fight?
No sports spirit at all.
Who are you?
I am a priest.
But I love watching soccer games.
Don't make a mess here.
Get lost! Jesus Christ!
What's wrong? A duel or what?
Brother Peel, you saw what they did.
They make trouble here.
Hey, weird heads.
We are all from the same gang.
We shouldn't fight against each other.
Brother Big Head, I give you face.
Oh really? You give me face.
Come on! Fight with me?
Scared?
Who is your boss?
Tai Fei.
And you?
Hon.
Don't be mad. Just call their bosses.
Talk to their bosses.
Thanks for reminding me.
Please don't...
I was quite drunk, so I said stupid things.
Sorry...
Well...
No next time, really...
Sounds polite?
Only dogs wear this kind of choker.
- All right?
- Okay.
Then shake hands and be friends.
All right? Go back to your seats to watch the game.
To dance, go...
Let's have fun, be happy.
It is settled, dances.
Let's have a drink.
Want a young girl to keep you company?
Nowadays, the young are badly behaved.
So, I get you a girl to listen to your lecture.
Priest, sit down and relax.
Give me some whisky.
By the way, Nam, Chicken...
You should lecture your men.
They have no respect to anyone at all.
They fight against one another.
Priest, what do you think?
Would Royal Madrid win this year?
Probably.
My dad adores Nanako.
This wedding joins Yamada Gang
and San Luen Gang together.
San Luen Gang's Lui and
other senior lieutenants have arrived.
Mr. Chiang from Hong Kong
and other Hung Hing leaders
have already arrived.
He speaks Cantonese.
Director Kusakari is my foster-father.
I am Chinese.
I see.
I have seen many Japanese TV soap operas.
I love Tokyo the most.
Tourists from Hong Kong
and Taiwan come to Tokyo...
Like to visit the Rainbow Bridge.
Yes! Rainbow Bridge!
Go with me.
- Thirteen Sister!
- Brother Black!
Mr. Chiang.
How are you doing?
This is one of the senior leaders
in Yamada Gang.
Where is Chicken?
Japanese-style wedding is very complicated.
Too many rituals, how can he find time?
I want to see his wife?
His wife...
Looks like an AV girl,
her look sexually arouses me.
How rude?
The Japanese don't understand
what I am talking about.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Black!
Come say hello to Lui.
You are the son of San Luen Gang's chief?
A big boy now.
You came all the way for the wedding?
I just came back from the U.S.
I heard Chicken is getting married,
so I asked Kam to bring me here.
This is Michael, my friend from the States.
How do you do, man?
Man...
I am on vacation, so join in.
Are you Cantonese?
I am from Hong Kong.
Please come...
This is Mr. Chiang.
We met last time in Thailand,
and had shark fin soups in Chinatown.
Lui senior's son
just graduated from the States.
He is your junior.
Mr. Chiang, chief of Hong Kong's Hung Hing Gang.
You are a big-name.
Nice to meet you.
Great!
Smart, have potential.
So handsome, must be popular with girls.
Sorry?
Popular with girls.
You must be Thirteen Sister from Hung Hing Gang.
Right! Right! Exactly...
Where is Ho Nam?
He is here.
Come over here.
"Marriage Vow"
I solemnly declare...
On this wedding date.
From today,
we must respect and love each other...
From a family.
Share our sweetness and bitterness.
Forever.
May we
be blessed forever.
Together we make a solemn pledge.
In this year...
1 - April
Husband, Chiu Shan Ho.
Wife, Kusakari Nanako.
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for coming.
Today is my daughter's wedding.
I am appreciative of your attendance,
coming all the way for her wedding.
I am deeply grateful! Thank you!
Mr. Chiang, after the ceremony
We should sit down and talk about business.
Now, we are one big family.
We should communicate more with each other.
The cutting of your suit looks funny.
Like a flying cockroach.
Behave...take a picture, quick.
Chan Ho Nam.
Lui senior's son.
Nice to meet you!
This is Kam, the think-tank of San Luen Gang.
How are you?
Kam and Brave are our most senior lieutenants.
Glad to finally meet you!
Nice to meet you.
Before, Chicken is kind
of half-Hongkonger and half-Taiwanese.
Now, he becomes one-third Hongkonger,
one-third Taiwanese,
and one-third Japanese.
Absolutely right.
Like an all-purpose clip?
The bride's hairdo is pretty, like a fountain.
Let's take a picture.
Mr. Hidari, thanks for coming!
This is my son-in-law, Mr. Chicken.
How do you do?
Good afternoon.
I like Japanese style weddings.
Me too. Her skin is white as snow.
I wish I could try one more time.
Then get a divorce and get married again.
- Sure.
- No way!
Once is more than enough.
When is your turn?
When?
What?
As a married man,
you shouldn't fool around anymore.
Today is my happy wedding, don't say bad things.
- About fooling around...
- Tell them...
- I am an expert.
- Right...
I am a local here in Tokyo.
- Really?
- Yes.
I'll show you some great places tonight.
For what?
First, we try the Turkey...
Turkish Bath, right?
Yes! Then, we play dices...
Dice?
Let's take a picture!
Finally, we are at Rainbow Bridge!
Isn't it romantic?
Romantic? Look at yourself!
Look over there, it is not romantic!
Just like the Ching Ma Bridge in Hong Kong.
Did you know,
many Japanese soap operas are filmed here?
Like famous actress Takako Matsu...
I know. I saw it before.
Many couples make a pledge here. You know?
Also, men propose to women...
Here they propose to women at this place.
If someone proposes to me now,
I will certainly say yes.
What is it?
Ho Nam's career...
Ho Nam's love...
Please.
Ho Nam's career...
Good luck!
Good fortune!
Will he marry me?
"Number 54 - bad luck"
No way, it won't be true.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Let's go.
What is that?
See for yourself.
Not bad.
You understand what it means?
No.
Nice to have all of you here.
Cheers...
Chicken...
Even after he got married...
He still fools around.
Why?
Because his cousin, me, likes to fool around.
So, he likes it.
Like you.
Of course. Cheers!
Cheers...
Right, brother Hon.
What kind of restaurant is hot in Japan?
We can open one in Hong Kong.
We are considering to do so.
I'll think of a name for your restaurant.
Gosh, I am hungry.
Call it "Hungry Man".
Great!
Name it after Japanese stars,
like Takuya Kimura or Sorimachi Takashi.
Takuya Kimura again!
Forget it!
Your English name is Philip, and yours is May.
Putting together, sound like "Filipino Maid"
Right, then call it "Filipino Maid Restaurant".
Cheers!
Everybody.
To celebrate the homecoming of
the son of San Luen Gang's chief.
Back from the U.S.
Let's cheers!
Brother Black, it is okay!
All of them are high-ranking leaders
of Hung Hing Gang.
You are their junior and
should pay respect to them.
Bring your glass.
Come on, cheers...
Cheers...
For our new president Chen Shui Bian.
- Cheers.
- Again?
But it is nothing to do with the new president.
Of course, it is related to him.
Chen Shui Bian will inaugurate on May 20th.
He will present his inauguration address.
If he provokes China...
China will certainly bomb us.
Would it pass through Hong Kong first?
It depends.
The bombs fly really fast.
Who knows?
Let's enjoy ourselves tonight!
Look at me.
Let's enjoy ourselves tonight
"Life..."
"Is like the waves in the wild seas."
"Sometimes it is vigorous,
sometimes it is tranquil."
"My dear friends, take care."
"In our lives,"
"even the poorest may have their day."
"No complaint."
"It is life."
Damned Taiwanese!
What the hell is he singing?
"A glass of wine, some changes..."
They know nothing but fighting
for independence from China.
"Come at midnight."
"Get sentimental."
"I am the number one in the world!"
Damn you!
Don't fight...
We are all Chinese. Stop...
We are Chinese, but you are not.
You are Hongkongers and Taiwanese...
Don't be so cocky!
Why do the Chinese fight against each other?
Who knows? What a show!
Hit him! Damn!
Should we help?
We can't do anything.
What's up? Having a party?
Has just opened fire: Beijing vs Taiwan.
Stop!
What's wrong? Today is my wedding day.
I know.
The Beijingese incite the fight.
- Sorry.
- What?
- Wait.
Calm down.
Yamada Gang...
Isn't it good enough?
All right?
It is my treat tonight.
Sit down.
So?
My wife slept.
Great!
Let's have some fun tonight.
First, get a Turkish bath.
What is the girl's name?
- Like the cartoon girl, Maruko.
- Maruko?
Or, the hot babe, Noriko Sakai.
Noriko Sakai? But you can't go.
No way! I'll go with you!
Let's go together...
Under the leadership of Mr. Chiang.
Hung Hing's business is
well-established across Asia.
It's a big success.
I am interested in doing business with you.
With the power of Yamada Gang in Japan,
plus the power of Taiwan's San Luen Gang,
and Hong Kong's Hung Hing Gang,
we join force and form alliance.
Absolutely, it will become a dream team.
In fact, Hung Hing Gang.
Glad to cooperate with Yamada Gang.
But, I decided to retire.
Sit back and relax in Thailand.
So, I decided...
to pass all the Hung Hing business
to Chan Ho Nam.
Director Kusakari, for any future business plan.
You can directly contact Ho Nam.
Yes.
The 21st century is the age of the young.
I agree.
I'm also considering retiring and enjoying life.
Listen, Chicken.
After my retirement...
Could you come to Japan
to take care of my business?
Yes!
Take time to think about it.
Go back to Taiwan and give it some thought.
I will wait for your good news.
I heard
that Hung Hing members are great fighters.
Fighting is their routine.
Kind of.
How about a friendly sword fight?
Teach them a lesson.
Sword fighting is
a traditional Japanese martial arts.
Each type has its own way of breathing.
Rituals, action, and movement.
Taoism is a way of living and thinking.
It requires hard work and long-term commitment.
I don't quite understand.
Since Lui senior passed away,
Black Dragon Gang have been against us.
They want to destroy us.
Now you are back.
I should give the chief position back to you
to avoid suspicion.
I am not that kind of ambitious person!
Although my father founded San Luen Gang,
it is not necessary for the Lui to be his heir.
Most importantly...
I don't want to be dragged
into triad power struggle.
Mr. Lui.
Gang's operation is very different
from the old days.
Your father
led us to develop a successful
and legal business,
like this golf mansion...
Today, the business is
well-established and prosperous.
It is natural to hand it down
from father to son.
You are the best person to take his place.
In year 2000
people talk about democracy and freedom.
Even our president is elected by popular vote.
As for the position of gang chief,
I think it should be given to a capable man.
Mr. Lui, you are right.
Our chief should be voted democratically.
One person, one vote?
I Object!
What do you object to?
Mr. Lui, since you came back,
no matter what,
I will pass the seat to you.
Maybe we should go back
and give it some thoughts,
Whether we can recommend an able man.
Brave and Kam...
Are the most senior lieutenants
in San Luen Gang.
Kam can take the place.
Absolutely not!
I can offer good advice, but not a good leader.
And offer recommendation from my experiences
Absolutely...
I can't be the gangster chief.
Panther unit head, any suggestion?
I have a great person in mind.
Share with us.
Chicken is the unit head of Poisonous Snake.
He has contributed a lot
to the success of our gang.
Also, he is the son-in-law of Yamada Gang chief.
If he becomes the chief of San Luen Gang
and these two gangs unite,
they will become the largest gang in Asia.
Objection!
Chicken is an outstanding unit head.
But he is from Hong Kong, not Taiwan.
How can he lead San Luen Gang?
Most of its units are formed by the Taiwanese.
Why not? As long as he is San Luen Gang member.
And is competent and has gut,
regardless of his nationalities.
I disagree!
Then what?
We Taiwanese have our own traditions.
- He can't even speak our dialects,
- What he can do?
how can he lead us?
- How can he think like us?
- He said
you can't speak Taiwan dialects.
And unqualified to be the chief.
Understand?
Some say ex-president Lee Teng Hui is Japanese.
But he could be the president.
Why can't Chicken be the chief?
You must be kidding.
Although I am Taiwanese,
I left Taiwan at 12 for studying in the US.
In terms of knowledge of Taiwan society
and gang operation, Chicken knows better than I.
Chicken, what do you think?
I appreciate your praise.
In fact, I have never dreamt of
being the gang chief.
Don't be too humble!
Whether I am a Taiwanese or speak local dialect
is not important.
Capability, open mind,
and long-term vision
are the most important attributes.
No more nonsense! I object!
Absolutely, I object!
What is your point?
Objection! Objection!
What do you actually object to?
You appeared to be loyal.
You want to be the chief!
- Nonsense!
- I am not!
I have said it loud and clear,
I don't want to be the chief.
Absolutely not!
Hypocrite!
We can read your mind.
You want to be the chief!
You want to pick a fight!
So what?
Anything else to say?
If you want to fight, I am ready!
Come! I am not scared of you!
All right! Stop!
What a joke!
In fact, we all understand.
Yes, this is true.
What is it?
Yes.
Garlic?
- Let's eat.
- Yes.
Can we eat now?
It's enough. Sit down to have a dinner.
Yes.
Yes...
- It is okay...
- Yes!
- You don't need to...
Do you understand me?
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
- No!
- Yes!
No...yes!
Yes...Eat...
Yes!
After dinner...
Yes
Eat...
As your wife, it is my duty.
- Eat...
- Yes!
A macho man sits this way.
Good night.
Good...night
Good afternoon.
Good...afternoon.
Good morning.
Good...morning.
Work hard.
Work...hard.
Stop...
Yes!
Stop? Yes?
Yes...
Faster...
Stop!
Faster!
With my wife...
Seems like a stranger.
With other women...
No...
What is missing?
Passion.
Next time...I should be more passionate.
Stop...Faster...
Hello?
Something happened.
Lui was attacked.
Really?
He is now in the hospital.
I'll come right away.
- You'd better now.
- Why?
Rumors say you eye is on the chief position.
So, you hired a hit man to kill him.
Bullshit!
If you show up, you will be in danger.
If I don't go, I look more suspicious.
Chicken, how dare you come here?
Why not?
Some people say you plotted the assassination.
Bullshit!
Stupid!
Why would he kill him? What for?
Show me your evidence!
Nonsense!
You bastard!
You are bitter, so you hit him on the back.
A conspiracy to take over his place.
Nonsense!
He said you plotted the assassination.
Damn you!
You accuse me!
Lui and I are good friends.
He came all the way from the States
to attend my wedding in Japan.
So what?
If I would ever hire a hit man,
you would be my first target!
Shut up!
We are on the same boat!
Mr. Lui wants to see Chicken, Brave comes in.
Take care.
Damn you!
What the hell?
I swear, I didn't do it.
Or I would be punished brutally.
I trust you.
Yeah, a convicted criminal is caught red-handed,
but he still says he is innocent
Mr. Lui, you must have a thorough investigation.
You can't trust him.
Of course, I will probe into the case.
But you all should calm down.
There may be some misunderstandings.
I don't want to see
any power struggle within our gang.
Otherwise, outsiders will take advantage of us.
Especially Black Dragon Gang.
Their chief, Dragon, is highly suspicious.
To tell you honestly,
I have no doubt about Chicken's integrity.
Brave, I know you suspect Chicken.
But until he is proven guilty,
you'd better leave him alone, all right?
All right, I'll keep my mouth shut!
But if I find any evidence against you,
you will be a dead man!
Come with me to a place.
Where?
To a very important meeting.
Lui should have attended the meeting on
behalf of San Luen Gang,
but he is in the hospital,
and Brave is too radical.
He may make a fool of himself.
So you are the best choice.
What kind of meeting is it?
Have you heard of Eagle?
Yes.
He was the real triad boss in Taiwan.
I thought he was retired.
People from both the government
and the triad give him face.
He calls the meeting.
What can you say?
Go to a rave party...
Make a mess!
Rave party!
Why do you have so many drugs?
Are you a drug dealer?
I told you, they're not mine.
Sin and Kay were high on drugs.
I drove them home.
Unexpectedly, we were stopped by the police.
I didn't realize they carried so many drugs.
Did you take any?
Don't you love me?
You don't love me! Don't trust me!
I have been living with you for three years.
Together with Ricky, Bobby and Lily.
I take care of them and clean up their mess.
But I have never complained at all.
Those are your dogs.
That's right!
Do you remember,
when I first came to Hong Kong...
I used counterfeit bills.
You came to bail me out at the police station.
Like this time.
Do you remember, we were on the highway...
I opened the sunroof...
and threw off the bills like this..."whew"
Flew like the wind.
Wasn't it romantic?
If I didn't come, you would feel
more romantic sitting in jail
I knew you would come.
Don't you kiss me?
You don't love me!
Hold me tight.
He is the chief of Black Dragon Gang?
Yes, when our chief was here,
he was just a small potato.
Look at him now...
Kam, long time no see.
Brother Dragon, how are you doing?
Let me introduce.
This is Dragon from Black Dragon Gang.
This is Chicken,
unit head of Poisonous Snake Sect.
Chicken.
Your name is getting big in the past two years.
I heard you have become the son-in-law of
Kusakari Ichio, the chief of Yamada Gang.
What a pity! In San Luen Gang...
No one can barely succeed.
Brother Dragon, you are too direct.
Yet, I believe only coward dares
not to stay at San Luen Gang.
I heard you were Lui senior's assistant...
Running errands for him.
Lui's son is in hospital
And San Luen Gang is in chaos.
It is not because of you, right?
Long time no see.
Sit down...
Have some tea...
Make yourself comfortable.
I call this meeting to get together.
Since
the March 18 presidential election,
there have been lots of changes in society.
I think we should get together
and discuss
how to manage the changes.
I think
we should wait and see.
Whoever is the president or the ruling party
only cares for money.
Money can buy off god, political parties,
and even the president.
In the past,
we dealt with the Nationalist Party.
Now, we can do the same
to the Democratic Progressive Party.
But, the new president declares
an end to political corruption.
His first priority is
to establish a stable cross-strait relationship.
Then
he can deal with the triads.
To make peace with the triads
he needs our help.
Brother Eagle, what is your comment
on the new government policies?
Political wisdom tells us
suppression or purge doesn't work.
Political wisdom tells...
We know.
Suppression or purge.
I believe the best way is...
I believe the best way is to "pacify".
Pacify?
What does it mean?
Like the ancient story about the 108 heroes.
They revolted against
the imperial court for years.
At the end, they complied with the emperor.
You meant...
Our government should transform
all triad members
into civil servants.
What is his theory?
Damn, I don't care.
It doesn't apply to the traids.
The means may be different,
but the end spirit is the same.
I guess they want us to cooperate
and under their control.
Then we can make profit as usual.
Anyway, just play by the rules.
The world is constantly changing.
We should go along with the trend.
Long live the president...
Upon the president's arrival,
supporters are extremely emotional.
This is his first speech since the election.
The crowds are hailing him.
From tonight onward,
the President, Vice President,
and the Democratic Progressive Party...
In the coalition meeting
we discussed about government's demand
for our cooperation.
To be pacified
Eagle implied that
we should reach a consensus and be pacified.
He even used an ancient story
to illustrate the case.
Damn it!
Brave, what do you think?
Brat, you want to quote me?
You are smart. Don't need to ask for my advice.
I am a stubborn old man.
You are a senior lieutenant in our gang.
Have a good grasp
of Taiwan's party politics and triads.
You were right last time.
Coming from Hong Kong, I am an outsider.
Unfamiliar with Taiwan's party
and gangster politics.
That's why I came to see you.
Trust me or not. Wholeheartedly...
I want to learn from you.
What did Kam say?
He didn't take any side.
He is smart.
How about you?
Of course, I oppose to pacification.
But the Democratic Progressive Party
declared to end corruption.
The old formula wouldn't work.
Are you stupid or what?
To end political collusion?
Nothing is absolute.
Before the election, the new president
always advocated independence.
But now, he doesn't mention it anymore.
Politicians always pay lip service.
Don't trust their words.
It is all political nonsense.
You are insane.
Right.
The politicians take advantage of us.
They come to us for favors.
Otherwise, they don't want to see us.
They bad-mouth us.
Look down upon us, yell at us...
Just want to kick us out.
We can't be controlled by them.
If we are under their control,
we will be vanished sooner or later.
Understand?
Yes.
If we give in, we will lose power.
Without power, we are like used a battery.
Ending up in the trash.
You look stupid, but you are quite smart.
Thanks for you.
Lui just came back from the US.
Not familiar with Taiwan's situations.
I should give him a thorough analysis.
All right, I am leaving.
Enjoy your fishing.
Chicken...
I'm asking you
about Lui's attack.
Did you do it?
Damn...I have said it many times...
Don't get mad.
All right, go back...
Brave, I want to ask you a question.
How do you become a real Taiwanese?
Learn to eat betel nut.
I tried it before.
It has a strange aftertaste.
My mouth stains with artificial red, like blood.
Then, how can I kiss girls?
You are a great unit leader.
But your weakness is too lustful
That's why I don't want to be the chief.
It will occupy too much of my time.
Then I won't have time to kiss,
to fool around with girls...
All right...bye
Don't tell me your juicy story.
All right!
It takes a lot of hard work to become a leader.
Like me, I was a chauffeur before.
But now, I am the unit head of Panther Sect.
Yes.
Work hard.
Let's go.
What did you talk about with the old man?
Anyway...
He is a stubborn old man.
But he is my senior, I have to respect him.
It depends.
Some old people are open, but some aren't.
Understand?
Your phone call.
Hello!
Chicken? This is Nanako.
Do you come home for dinner?
Dinner?
No home dinner.
You eat yourself...
Sleep yourself...
Yes.
Wait...
Goodbye.
What are you talking about?
A wife makes you speak English and Japanese.
With one more,
you can speak French and Russian...
What a deal!
Only do, no talk.
What's mean "only do, no talk"?
Cousin, tonight...
- You bastard.
- I'll bring you
to enjoy love and sex.
What is it?
A blue triangle.
Viagra.
Men's savior.
Is that right?
Yes.
Very powerful.
Only one pill can do...
Shoot high.
So potent.
I don't need it.
Why not? You can take half a pill...
Careful!
It hurts!
I'll show you a new hang-out tonight.
Don't take too many, it may kill you.
I am not kidding.
All right.
Come on. Have fun...
My dear, come over!
Cousin.
What?
After I got married, my hands get so stiff.
Is it a problem?
Of course.
You need practice to soften your hands.
Be gentle...
Massage this one gently...and that one...
Feeling great.
Let me lie down...
Come over...
Not this way.
Show time.
Go!
Akira.
Please don't go.
What is the matter?
I miss you. So, I came here.
You knew I loved you!
I am married.
You should have married me!
That damned old man, he did me wrong!
Siu Mo...
Siu Mo!
Run!
Hurry! Run!
Chicken, get into the car!
Cousin...
Cousin!
Damn! You are all rubbish!
One dead, one ran away.
You traitor, go to hell!
Eat some more.
Don't go, I'm scared.
Bastard Akira.
I thought my father-in-law
would let his daughter marry him.
And succeed his place.
I ruined his plan.
He raped my wife.
How is she?
Getting better.
But she has nightmares every night.
If I didn't go out that night...
You should stay home with her.
I don't have a home now.
He wants to nail you, you can't hide anywhere.
San Luen Gang back you up?
San Luen Gang?
Lui is in the hospital.
He has insisted on not getting
involved in gang affairs.
Earlier, I had a fight with Brave.
Brave and Kam argue
over the new government policy.
They don't talk to each other.
Now, San Luen Gang is...
Like presidential election, in a big mess.
Anyway, we are always good brothers.
We help each other out.
Where is your girlfriend?
In Taipei.
Do you want her to keep your wife company?
No thanks.
I can solve my problems.
Come over...
This is Siu Mo, he worked for my cousin.
He helps me to hide out here.
Willi, call my contacts in Taiwan.
I am sorry. I went shopping and forgot the time.
Have a look. Isn't it beautiful?
Shopping for this watch?
I was half an hour late because of it.
It took me a long time
to bargain with the sales.
He could less 3,000 at most.
Like it?
You have no sense of time.
It suits you more, keep for yourself.
Next time...
What's wrong with you?
You don't appreciate my gift.
I am leaving!
What are you doing? Get away!
Help...Doctor!
Help!
You are...so ugly.
Hello, teacher!
"Butterflies are so beautiful."
"Wearing pretty crowns,
Wearing flowered dresses."
"You love flowers, flowers love you."
"You dance, flowers are pretty."
"Butterflies are so beautiful."
"Wearing pretty crowns,
wearing flowered dresses."
"You love flowers, flowers love you."
"You dance, flowers are pretty."
Why do you keep following me?
I am sorry.
Because...
I follow you...
Because...you look like my friend.
You can speak Cantonese, I understand.
I was born in Hong Kong, studied in Taiwan.
You speak Cantonese?
You really look like my friend.
I thought you were her, so I followed you.
You are very straight forward.
But she passed away.
My name is Chan Ho Nam.
I am Tuan-Mu Ruo Yu.
You look exactly like her.
Anything else? If not, I have to go inside.
Can we be friends?
Chicken...Something happened!
Peel, Big Head.
A car is coming, never seen it before.
Chicken!
- Chicken!
- Chicken, watch out!
Look after her.
Yes.
Father?
Chicken, are you here?
This is your father!
Father!
Chicken!
Glad to see you all right!
I am fine.
How are you?
Don't worry about me.
Is Nanako okay?
I am sorry. I got you involved.
I am sorry.
Akira not only works against us,
he even discloses our secrets to the police.
It's probably him...
Putting me into this situation.
Bastard!
As a triad chief,
I have handled many tough gang fights...
Fought against many enemies...
It's not easy to reach where I am.
But, I have never imagined
my adopted son would betray me.
I treated him as my own son.
I lose my mind.
I was once betrayed by the woman I loved most.
That feeling...
I am heartbroken...
This disaster happened to Nanako.
Father, she is my wife.
I should have taken good care of her.
I am sorry.
But I promise you...
I will kill Akira with my very own hand.
Do you know you are so rude?
Your phone was busy all day long.
You left without telling me.
I couldn't find you at the hotel.
Do you know you worry me?
I thought you had been chopped into pieces.
I almost went to the squatters to find you.
I am hungry, let's go for dinner.
Let's go?
No!
Why?
From a woman's intuition.
Something happened to you?
I came back right after the business.
No!
Did you go out with a woman?
No.
Yes!
- You did! Your face told me so!
- No, I didn't...
You did!
Yeah, I just fooled around with girls.
Are you happy now?
That was not true.
Why did you hide your secrets from me?
What secrets?
Even if we were married,
we should have our own privacy.
That means, if we are not married,
I have no right to ask you questions, right?
- Where are you going?
- Leave me alone!
May I talk to Tuan-Mu Ruo Yu?
Who are you looking for?
Miss Tuan-Mu Ruo Yu...Yes.
I am sorry, she is not here.
Thank you!
- Brother Nam!
- Hello. Willi.
Yes, what's up?
I am calling my men from Hong Kong to here.
No problem?
No problem.
I called my friends in Taiwan.
Okay.
Where is Brave?
We lost touch.
Recently, he opposed to complying
with the new government
and argued with you several times.
Maybe he is still mad.
This stubborn old man.
In no doubt, he is loyal.
But he is too stubborn and conservative.
This time, Chicken and Wah were attacked.
People rumor that he is behind the scene.
It is hard to say.
For long, he has suspected
Chicken of assassinating you.
Have you found Chicken?
Not yet.
Go to find him!
Okay.
Do you hear me? Hurry up?
Yes!
I am sorry to hear your bad news.
But don't worry.
I will track down Akira.
Tell Chicken not to hide anymore.
Ask him to come back.
San Luen Gang will certainly back him up.
We, San Luen Gang, lose face.
Getting you involved
in our own internal matters.
I heard lots of rumors
that Chicken wants
to take over the chief position
and someone will purge him.
I have never suspected Chicken.
We found out that
the chief of Black Dragon Gang
Dragon masterminded the attack.
As for whether Brave tried to kill Chicken,
we will investigate it.
It's possible that
Akira colludes with the Black Dragon Gang.
In fact, I shouldn't get involved
in your gang affairs.
But I must tell you,
Chicken has been my best friend for years.
Chicken is lucky to have...
A great friend like you.
Today, we are in the era of global village.
San Luen Gang and Hung Hing Gang
have established a good relationship.
So, we should join forces
to fight off our common enemies.
Taiwan's Black Dragon Gang
and Hong Kong's Tung Sing Gang.
I have no idea what  global village is.
But, I believe righteousness.
And trust
is the most important.
Honestly, San Luen Gang
has many internal conflicts.
So, I am forced to try to apply
my management knowledge to run San Luen Gang.
In terms of capability and experience,
Chicken and Brave are the best candidates.
If Chicken wants to take over the seat,
he will do so in a proper way.
To avoid San Luen Gang from collapse,
I recommend Brave to be the new chief.
Good decision.
Have a great working relationship.
Lui senior's son...
He studied in the States and
is used to the American culture.
Now, he wants reforms.
It will be a disaster.
Kwong, Six Packs hasn't come back
from the doctor appointment yet?
Yes.
So look alike.
Exactly the same.
Is she my twin sister?
Just kidding.
She is your wife?
You...have been engaged.
We planned to get married.
Are you Japanese?
Tuan-Mu is a Chinese surname.
It sounds like a Japanese name.
Have you heard of Confucius?
Yes, in high school.
We got a holiday to commemorate his birthday.
Confucius had a student called Tsu Kuang.
His original family name was Tuan Mu Ci.
He was the Tuan-Mu's first ancestor.
A politician during the Spring
and Autumn Period (700-403 BC).
Am I boring you?
That's fine.
What's wrong?
Nothing...Smartie spoke with a stammer.
But you speak clearly.
Really?
By the way, what brought you to Taiwan?
Business.
About time, I have to leave.
I'll walk you out.
No thanks.
No, I'll walk with you.
You came to pick up children?
No, I came to talk to you.
I knew Chan Ho Nam for only few days,
just an acquaintance.
Please don't mistake me.
Not really.
I know he could never forget Smartie.
He even calls her name in his sleep.
No one can ever replace her in his heart.
My three year relationship with him
is no better than your one minute with him.
I...
I enjoy chatting with him.
But I have never thought of staying with him.
Especially after you told me
your relationship with him.
I didn't come to protest.
No.
I just want to see.
To talk to you.
Do you know...
I believe in destiny.
When it comes, you can't resist it.
When it leaves, you can't make it stay.
All right, I am leaving.
Pay homage to family.
Please accept my condolence.
Don't worry, I will take care of your living.
First bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
It is my fault...
If I were there...
You shouldn't have died.
- Brother, I am sorry.
- Present flowers.
Where is Chicken?
Bring him here!
He must be linked to Brave's death!
Today, I come to pay respect
on behalf of Hung Hing Gang.
But I can tell, we are not welcomed.
Of course not, we appreciate your coming.
The other day
Lui told you about appointing
Brave as the chief.
Two days later, Brave was killed.
What a coincidence.
What do you mean?
Chicken is your buddy.
You want your best friend to be the gang chief.
It is understandable.
It is unfounded accusation.
Nonsense.
Kam, watch your words.
Who killed Brave?
I will investigate it.
Please.
Thanks.
First bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
Chicken, good timing!
I'll cut your head and
take your blood as sacrifices to Brave!
Avenge for Brave's death!
- Are you crazy?
- Calm down...
How dare you cut my head and take my blood!
Come, if you have guts.
Don't trust him! He is the traitor!
Brave opposes to his succession,
so he kills him!
When he knows Brave is going to be the chief...
He murders him!
- Yes!
- Who told you that?
We all knew about it!
Come on!
Who ever saw him kill Brave?
Who? Any proof?
Don't be so exaggerated, buddy.
What should we do?
They collude with one another.
Save us trouble.
Right!
We live in a civilized society.
Evidence matters.
Without any evidence, we can't accuse Chicken.
Please be patient.
Director Kusakari.
Mr. Lui.
Chicken is my son-in-law.
San Luen Gang and Yamada Gang
are on the same side.
And Chicken is my family.
If enough evidence is found to prove him guilty,
I will kill him with my own hands!
Director Kusakari is a reasonable man.
I admire you.
Before we find any evidence,
Chicken will be in my hands.
I will send my personal apology to you.
Today is Brave's funeral.
Even if we want to purge the traitor,
we should wait after the ceremony.
Although Chicken is the most suspicious,
I will investigate it.
And won't wrongly accuse him.
Everybody, listen up.
Before he is proven guilty,
no one can touch him.
Or, I will take it as a challenge against me.
Same to Hong Kong's Hung Hing Gang.
- Chicken.
- Yes?
Go pay respect.
Yes!
Brave.
I believe you don't want to
see our gang collapse.
"What a romantic breakup
Mei Ling"
Where are you?
It is me, Tuan-Mu Ruo Yu.
I've come to tell you
I'm getting married.
I don't want to give up my marriage...
simply because of a touching fairy tale.
I am not Smartie.
Sorry.
Goodbye.
In view of the current situation,
I accept to be the chief and lead San Luen Gang.
Mr. Lui.
You deserve it.
San Luen gang members all support you.
All members will follow your directions.
About our government's offer.
It shouldn't be a problem.
Absolutely fine.
But I have a request.
Request?
I determine to unify all the triads in Taiwan.
All the triads will be under my control.
Or, they will die.
Even the old San Luen Gang will be eliminated.
I will set up a new division.
Smart and bright.
Ambitious. Great!
Have a great working relation.
Father.
I want to read my wedding vow
once more before you
and Nanako. May I?
From today onwards...
We must love and respect each other,
form a family.
Share our sweetness and bitterness forever.
No matter what happened in the past,
or will happen in the future,
you are my wife.
I will take care of you for the rest of my life.
Harder!
Chicken, I am sorry.
It is Lui who ordered his men to kill Brave.
Kwong told me
Kam followed Lui's command.
Hired Kwong as hit man to murder Brave.
He promised to pay him a large sum of money.
But, after Brave's funeral,
Kam didn't pay him the money.
Even tried to kill Kwong.
Kwong told me the truth before he died.
Brave was loyal to San Luen Gang...
But ended up being killed by Lui...
Because he strongly opposed
to complying with the government.
Strongly against pacification.
Because of this issue,
he argued with Lui for several times.
Their relationship was in a deadlock.
I also heard that
Lui accepted the post of gangster chief.
He chooses to inaugurate on May 20th...
And renames San Luen Gang.
Also, Kam has sent out a secret order.
After Lui's inauguration,
all the gangs must follow his order.
Or, they will be annihilated.
Annihilation?
Is Lui capable of doing so?
Rumor has it that
Lui has reached an agreement
with the government.
The new government will back him up in secret.
Lui always said
he was not interested in gang affairs.
But it was all part of his conspiracy,
making me the scapegoat.
You are his sworn enemy
and the son-in-law of Yamada Gang's chief.
I have never thought of fighting
the seat against him.
But he feels threatened by you.
He provokes internal conflicts
to get rid of his rivals.
Obviously, you are framed.
Then, he pretends to be understanding...
And widely supported by different units.
He is deadly ambitious.
Eliminate all his opponents and
unify the underworld.
He must see himself
as the Chinese First Emperor Qin?
Brother Nam, all of our Hung Hing members
are refused entry into Taiwan.
Same as Yamada Gang.
With the government backing him up,
he can do whatever he wants.
Thank you! Come again!
Hello?
Listen, this is Chicken.
I am at your house
holding your wife and children hostage.
If you cooperate with me, they will be fine.
All right. I understand.
What happened?
Nothing.
The preparation for the inauguration
is almost ready.
Most of the guests have arrived.
Bow to our national flag and founding father.
First bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
Bestowed with Presidential Seal
and Presidential Stamp.
Vow.
With the most solemn respect and sincerity.
- I declare...
- On 2000...
May 20.
At an important and meaningful historic moment,
I, Lui Fu Kwan, am inaugurated
as the chief of San Luen Gang
Our new government and political party
will be inaugurated today.
With the end of the old century,
we welcome the new millennium.
We will certainly look forward to reform.
To lead our gang to a rich
and successful new era.
Also, I have devised
a new set of foreign policy
to join force and establish
good relation with overseas gangs,
to achieve peaceful co-existence.
On this occasion, I would like to announce that
Panther unit head, Ko Chi Wah, was killed.
Poisonous Snake unit head Chicken betrayed us
and was expelled.
Therefore, I decide to merge
these two units into one.
The new unit head is
Mr. Kusakari Akira from Japan.
Although he has a Japanese name,
he is one hundred percent Chinese.
Although he is the adopted-son
of Yamada Gang's chief,
he disgusts the collusion
between Ichio and Chicken.
As they scheme to annex San Luen Gang,
for the sake of righteousness,
Mr. Ichro joins our camp.
I very much admire him.
May we greet him with our warmest applause.
Welcome to join San Luen's big family!
I am sorry, I am late.
Traitor! How dare you show up here?
Old men, shut up.
You are right, it is time to purge our enemy.
But this person is not Chicken.
He is Luis Fu Kwan!
I can prove that Chicken is innocent.
Brave was not killed by him.
But by you, Luis Fu Kwan!
Chicken taught you
to talk to me like this, right?
What favors did he give you?
We all know Brave is loyal to San Luen Gang.
I respect him...
And even recommend him to be the chief.
Help me! Dad...
It is impossible that I would kill him.
Why not?
Because you want to be king of the triads.
To unify and control all the triads in Taiwan.
Am I right?
Would you believe in the traitor?
You may not believe in Chicken.
But, if...
Kam, please explain.
Chicken and Six Packs told you the truth.
Lui ordered the killing of Brave
in order to frame Chicken.
Before that...
Lui masterminded the assault of himself.
He did it on purpose...
To turn Chicken into a suspect,
an outcast, why?
Because Chicken is the son-in-law
of Yamada Gang's chief.
Luis feels threatened.
Kam, you also take bribes from Chicken.
Betray me and San Luen Gang.
Please continue.
Liu...
Luis Fu Kwan is
the real power hungry, ambitious man.
He has reached an agreement
with the new government.
After his inauguration,
he will totally comply with the new government.
In return, the government helps eliminate
all the triads for him
so he can become a dictator.
Chicken taught you to fabricate the story?
Did he bribe you?
Or threaten you?
I can prove if
Kam is telling us the truth.
I negotiate with Luis
on behalf of the new government.
I am sorry, Mr. Lui.
You demands are too harsh.
The President and his chief of staff
discussed the issue.
They can't accept your unreasonable demands.
Okay!
Dad, please forgive me.
Answer me.
You are behind the conspiracy?
Help yourself.
I appreciate it.
This one is for my wife!
Dad!
Shit!
Chan Ho Nam, let me go!
In the triad, righteousness is important,
especially to our brothers.
Come on!
You set me up.
I tell you...
Our new government determines
to end political corruption.
To annihilate the triads!
Bullshit!
Take him away!
Go!
Are you Chan Ho Nam?
Thank you for your help.
Not at all.
I just do the right thing.
- Goodbye.
- Thank you, goodbye.
Father, you speak Mandarin?
Of course.
He studied in Japan. We were classmates.
So was Taiwan ex-president Lee Ten Hui.
I see!
What did you father say?
He said both the politician
and the ex-president
were his classmates.
Thank you.
Today is May 20th.
The president gave his inaugural address.
Would China attack Taiwan?
Guess not! We are all Chinese.
Chinese fight Chinese?