Every night, the same dream.
The same strange planet.
But why?
What are they trying to tell me?
It's been 34 years since
they arrived on this planet.
And now the days passes,
the survivors forced
to live in barrier cities,
do not live in fear.
I have vowed to end that fear.
I believe my dreams hold the key.
The question is,
Will I be in time to save the Earth?
Where are you?
This is a restricted area.
Do not move!
What is she doing here, captain?
I don't know,
but we are getting her out.
You're coming with us.
Behind you!
Hold it right there!
Damn it!
Let's move, people.
Two, coming through the wall.
Alright, hold your fire.
Ryan, Neil, let's go.
Just what the hell do you think you are doing?
There is a life form in here.
There hasn't been life here in years.
Well, there is now.
Life form or not,I'm taking you in
Fine, arrest me, but I'm not leaving without that life form.
Gonna be one of those days.
Captain, principal is not going to
wait for us much longer.
I understand that.
It's in bad shape.
Please. Tell me when I risk my next
for this plant.
I won't even call it a plant.
It's wheat.
I won't even call it a wheat.
I need a minute to extract it.
Miss, that's the minute
we do not have.
I'm afraid he is right about that, ma'am.
Captain, we have incomings.
Captain, we need to get out from here.
Understood, sergeant.
Could you hurry please, miss?
Done, captain.
Yes, Neil.
Just all you know, I agree with.
Let's get out from here.
Can I have this please?
Thank you.
We're surrounded.
No! Shit!
Alright, everybody.
Just relax.
Captain, we got to get to higher
ground.
Everyone, up to top.
Go! Go! Go!
Transport requesting immediately evac.
Confirmative.
Up here!
Captain!
We are right behind you.
I got you.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Alright, everybody. Here they come.
Are you okay?
Can you give me one good reason
why I shouldn't arrest you?
I am Dr. Aki Ross.
I have clearance to be here.
Not unlimited clearance.
And not without authorization.
Captain, I don't have time for this.
Do you realize you've just risk
the lives at my squad and me?
Look.
I don't want to talk about it.
The fact of the matter is,
it was worth the lives of you and your men.
You and your men?
She thinks you are a man.
I think she's an idiot.
I know you are not a man.
I think you're an idiot too.
Very funny.
But I do want to talk about it.
Did it ever occur to you that maybe we
would volunteer to risk our lives?
Have we been given a choice?
Nobody asked you to save me.
I don't believe this.
You have not changed a bit.
Gray?
Yeah, nice to see you too.
Welcome back, captain.
We're cleaned.
Let's make sure of this, shall we?
I hate getting scanned.
Sir, this scan is probably worse
for us than the phantoms.
I'll probably about it, captain.
These machines are suspected
of causing sterility.
And I want to have a little new
junior calling me daddy someday.
That's a spooky thought.
Why are you always busting my chop?
People, let's just do this thing.
Alright.
- Yes, sir.
Okay, next.
Looks like you gain some weight.
It's called body strength, Neil.
Get a girlfriend.
I'm working on it.
You know my security rating allows
me to bypass this.
Not today, it doesn't.
Something's not right.
About this mission?
- Or that woman?
- Both.
Next.
Listen, captain. I think...
I don't care what you think, doctor.
You're getting scanned
just like everybody else.
Oh shit!
Captain!
They got him.
There must be a mistake.
You came in contact with the
phantom, sir.
Please remain calm.
Administering treatment shield.
What level is he?
Blue.
He will be code red in 3 1/2 minutes.
We have to treat him now.
I'm sorry.
That's impossible.
We'll transfer him to the treatment center.
There's no time for that.
Take him to the table.
Hang in there, captain.
Locating pathogens.
Jesus! Look at that thing.
How much more time?
Not enough.
When he reaches code red,
the treatment shield won't be
able to hold the aliens particles
Engaging bio-etheric laser.
- What's going on?
- Where does it go?
What the hell is going on?
We lost contact.
infestation is moving deeper.
- Tracking.
- There is no time.
- There is no time!
You're gonna lose him.
Found it.
It's alright.
Don't worry.
You'll be back to normal in no time.
Doctor, we need to scan you
for infestation.
That won't be necessary.
I'll take responsibility.
Hey, Doc. Thanks for saving him.
Are you alright?
Yeah, but the military has
impounded my ship
What's with her?
What's with her and the captain?
What's with her and that stupid plant?
What?
Forward me the phantom data and everything
we got in the file spirits collected so far.
Yes, Doctor.
Spirits? I thought we weren't
supposed to use the S word.
Don't get smart with me.
Let's see if that plant does the trick.
It's a match.
We've found it.
Yes, the 6th spirit.
A little scene today brought
me every protocol
How long do you think this would
have survive outside the barrier?
Aki, you know there are elements in
the Council military just waiting
for an excuse to shut us down.
Look. 20 years ago, who discovered
this energy in the phantoms?
You.
And who proved the same energy source
existed in humans and every life form?
You.
You made the possible to harness that energy
for overpacks, scanners, even the barrier.
The Council knows that.
They trust you, Doctor.
We are so close to proving...
We still need this part and this one
here.
Exactly. Two more pieces
and we've solved the puzzle.
We need to be free to find those pieces.
I want to show you something, Aki.
- What is this?
- Read.
All life is born of Gaia and each
life has a spirit.
Each new spirit is housed in
a physical body. Doctor...
Go on.
Through their experiences on Earth,
each spirit matures and grows.
When the physical body dies,
the mature spirit enriched by it's life
on Earth returns to Gaia.
Bring in with it the experiences,
enabling Gaia to live and grow.
It's my old diary.
I wrote that 43 years ago when I
was the age you are now.
Dr. Sid!
I know what happen to Galileo.
They threw him in jail because he said
the Earth was not
the center of the universe.
That could happen to us.
Our ideas are unpopular, Aki.
If you have any notes or records,
it could
be used against you.
Destroy them.
Keep them up here.
Right.
And stay away from your friend,
the captain.
He saved your life,
you saved his life,
This leads to that.
I was young once too,
you know.
Doctor,
there is a war going on.
No one is young anymore.
Ladies and Gentlemen of the Council,
Could you please explain why?
Zeus was completed a month ago.
If we attack the meteor with this,
we will eliminate the phantoms
at their source.
General Hein,
calm down.
At our last meeting,
we voted 6 to 2 to postpone
using the Zeus cannon
to attack the alien meteor.
We have reconvince today to vote
on that very issue again.
Now, I'd like to ask the director
of the bio-ethereal center to speak.
Dr Sid, please.
As you all know,
the phantom's nested in the alien meteor
that landed here 34 years ago.
What you see now,
are the records of every assault
on the meteor to date.
Physical attacks have had utterly no effect.
This seems to place 3 months ago
during a full scale bombard.
And please note that the phantoms outside
the meteor are indeed destroyed.
However inside, many that ??? come to live.
And as you see over all phantom
density remains the same.
The newly recent aliens respond
to the attack.
By bury, even deeper into the Earth.
Now this is very interesting to me, Dr. Sid.
Because we see the same thing during surgery.
When using bio-etheric lasers
on phantom particles.
- Do we not?
- Yes, indeed we do.
You see the injured particles escape,
burying or digging themselves
deeper into the patient's body.
And when we increase the laser power
to destroy these deeper particles,
we have had incidents resulting and
further injury to a patient.
And in some cases, death.
And what exactly does that mean, Doctor?
It means there is a very good chance the
beam from the Zeus cannon will burn
the phantoms in the meteor.
Exactly. Thank you.
However,
it also means that the beam energy
may be too strong injuring the Earth.
Injure the Earth? You mean the Gaia,
You mean the spirit of the Earth?
Yes. The spirit of the Earth.
???I need to see whatever it is said.???
What are you doing?
-I know what I'm doing
and whatever you do,
keep you mouth shut.
This is ridiculous.
Doctor, with all the respect.
Did you come here just to talk
about some Gaia theory?
To tell us the planet is alive?
That it has a spirit?
That's a fairy-tale, Doctor.
And I'm sorry, but we don't have time for that.
It's not a fairy-tale, it is true.
So, if I point a gun to the Earth and fire,
I'm not just making a hole on
the ground, I am killing the planet.
Dr. Sid, the Gaia theory has
not been proven.
Even if Gaia does exist,
won't we still have to remove the
phantoms.
I think if there's any chance of
success,
we should take it?
- Don't you agree?
- Of course I do.
But there is an alternative to this
space cannon
Another method?
Yes, I mean of disabling the
phantoms.
Please.
As we know the aliens display
a distinct energy pattern
Now it is a fact that two opposing bio-etheric
waves placed one over the other
will cancel each other out.
It's theoretically possible
to construct the wave pattern
in direct opposition to the phantom energy.
We are currently assembling...
- Doctor....
- such a wave in a nearing completion...
Members of the Council,
gathering plants and animals
from around the world to fight
the phantoms is other nonsense.
The Zeus cannon is a
proven effective weapon.
It will kill phantoms.
Can we afford to wait for some
crazy inventions
Some army of touchy feeling
plants and animals
An invention that offers no solid evidence
that will destroy the aliens.
There is evidence.
Our partially completed energy
wave has
successfully
stopped phantom particles
from spreading through a
terminally infected patient.
Doctor, do you claim to have evidence
that terminal patient has been cured.
Not cured. The wave is not
completed.
But we have succeeded in containing
the particles safely inside the patient.
Where is the proof?
Here.
You may have bought us some time, Aki.
But I wonder at what cost?
Doctor, I can't keep hiding in the
background while you protect me.
I want what life I have left
to mean something.
You listen to me.
When we find the 7th and 8th spirits...
If we find them,
what we need now is some luck.
Luck has nothing to do with it.
Fate and hard work, girl.
Cause I'll be damned if you going to die before me.
The Council decided to postpone
firing the Zeus cannon.
I guess I put on a good show.
Mind if I take a look?
You'll probably get bored.
So what are you doing?
Oh, I see.
Giving me the silent treatment.
I am scanning the city for the 7th spirit.
Hurry up, Neil.
Relax serg, I almost got it.
What do you think you are doing?
We just gonna strengthen them for a while.
Hey, don't look at me.
It was his idea.
This was your idea?
We just help the captain up a little.
Come on, Jane.
Where's your sense of romance?
You see how the captain looks at her.
It's amore, baby.
What's going on?
It's probably just a glidge.
- Listen, Aki...
- I'm still mad at you.
You are mad at me?
Leaving your helmet on and not
telling me who you were?
That doesn't seem a little childish.
I was just a little upset when you just packed
and left for the Zeus station without saying a word.
Well, now you know what's going on,
alright?
Yeah, now I know.
My operation had to be done
in zero graph, okay?
Fine!
how about the fact that
I was sent there on the job
And you wouldn't even see me?
I was probably helping Dr. Sid
collect spirit wave.
Now I know.
So I'm sorry.
Well, me too.
So we are both sorry.
So would you tell me about them?
About what?
About the spirits you've collected.
I was infected by a phantom
during an experiment.
Normally no one could have survived.
How did you?
Dr. Sid created a membrane
around the infection
Keeping me alive.
So the first spirit wave was me.
The second was a fish.
A fish?
The third was a deer I found in a
wildlife-preserve outside Moscow.
The fourth was a bird.
Ever try to track a sparrow from outer space?
It's no fun.
What am I saying?
You probably would love that.
You are right. I probably would.
And then there was that plant
I collected from Time Square.
I thought that was number 6.
- What?
- You skipped one.
The fifth was a little girl dying in
a hospital emergency room.
I retrieved the sample in time,
but she...
I told her everything has a spirit.
Dogs, cats, trees, little girls,
even the earth.
I told her that she wasn't dying,
just returning to the Earth spirit.
The Gaia.
She... told me that she
was ready to die.
She said I didn't have to make up
stories to make her feel better.
Only 7 years old and ready to die.
I'm sorry.
I have work to do.
I have to find the 7th and the 8th spirits.
Don't... please....
You don't believe any of this, do you?
I just... don't know, Aki.
Is this why you shut me out?
You should have told me.
I don't know how much time I have left.
Who does?
I better get back to scanning.
Captain Edwards, you extracted Dr. Ross
from old New York several days ago.
Did you not?
What were your impressions of Dr. Ross?
She seemed very capable and determined, Sir.
You and the Deep Eyes are being
temporary reassigned.
You will guard Dr. Ross when she
re-enters the waste land.
Understood, sir.
You don't understand yet, Captain.
Report any ebullient behavior in Dr.
Ross to the Major immediately.
Ebullient behavior, sir?
The woman carries an alien
infestation, captain.
We don't know what it maybe doing to her.
The aliens presence could be
effecting her judgement.
And maybe manipulating the Doctor
for their very own purposes
Is the General suggesting that
Dr Ross is a spy?
The General is wondering why he is
explaining himself to a captain.
She's had a long exposure
to phantom tissue
If this begins to manifest itself in
anyway,
Dr Ross is to be placed under arrest.
And transport here for observation.
It is, in fact, for her own good, captain.
Of course, sir.
Major, send some of our man
to keep an eye on the good captain.
I'm convinced that these dreams are
some form of communication.
The message still eludes me.
But they are coming faster now.
And that can only mean one thing.
The phantoms inside me are
beginning to win
Our target is to ??? at two sign.
Roger.
Phantom concentration.
Not good.
We got big mammoths everywhere.
So it's gonna be a real picnic.
Stick close to me.
No heroics today, okay?
Everything by the book.
By the book, right.
If we drop energy baits here,
here and here,
we should be able to land, acquire the target
and get out before the
phantoms even know we were there.
And the baits will attract the phantoms.
Yeah, For a while.
So you are from the 307s, right?
Under General Hein?
Have you done any wasteland recon before?
And get pretty ugly.
Captain, rendezvous evac at
sector 6 code at 279.
Roger that. Stay out for hard tiles.
Looks like they are taking the ????.
The 7th spirit should be just
beyond that line of wreckage.
I don't see how any living thing
could survive out here.
You'll find out soon enough.
This was the phantom cleansing mission.
It was supposed to end the war.
My father is in here somewhere.
Alright. Let's move out, people.
I'll be damn.
A survivor.
What is it doing out here?
Hoping for life to return.
- Is that our spirit, Doc?
- No.
We've closing in on a life form.
Distance?
Hard to say.
We are very close.
I don't see anything.
You're not gonna tell me it's him.
That's impossible
It's not the soldier. It's his overpack.
How do you explain that?
Packs? Power or weapon?
The barrier cities?
I mean it's just bio-etheric energy.
And to create that energy,
we use living tissue.
Single cell organism.
You're telling me his backpack
is the 7th spirit.
Yes.
Captain, do you read me?
Once say again.
Captain, we have incoming.
Ryan, get the soldier's pack.
I need a hand, sergeant.
- Those baits....
- Yeah.
They are not working.
Thank you.
Are you alright?
Of course I am.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Something is not right.
It shouldn't be happening.
Something's attracting them.
Aki...
There are right on us, sir.
Closing in fast.
Jane, take the lead.
Fire the whole!
Get us out of here, Neil.
Sir, I would love to
but...
- Just do it!
- Sir?
- Ok, that's it.
That doesn't look good, captain.
We have to get her to a hospital.
You have your orders, sir.
What the hell is going on here?
Dr. Ross is to be taken
into the custody now, sir.
Lower your weapons.
That's an order.
Sir, We have no choice but to re-leave
you of your command.
I won't let you do this, soldier.
You gonna have to shoot me.
Bend down, captain!
Aki!
Hang on, everyone!
That's enough!
Hands up, so I can see them,
everyone, down.
Neil, get us back to New York.
Fast.
The "Deep eyes" are returned
from the wasteland, sir.
Apparently there was an incident.
It would seem the phantoms
were attracted to Dr Ross.
The crew barely escaped
with their lives.
And sir... Captain Edward
is still in command.
Issue an order.
I want Edward and Dr. Ross
placed under arrest.
All research materials pretending
to Dr Sid wave theory
are to be confiscated immediately.
That might not go over too well
with the Council, sir.
What a tragedy that would be.
This is perfect, Major.
The good captain
has opened the door for us.
By tomorrow morning,
the Council would bear our feet.
Thanking us for exposing the
traitors and ???? imploring us
to save them from the phantoms.
How is she, Doctor?
She is dying.
There must be something you can do.
Aki is fighting with only
6 of the 8 spirits.
We have to implant the 7th
directly into her chest plate.
It took a bullet.
I think it might be damaged.
We have to repair this panel quickly.
Her vital signs are dropping.
Aki is slipping away from us.
She needs a sympathetic spirit to
help hold her in this world.
And I can think of no spirit better
suited for that task than yours,
captain.
I don't understand.
You don't have to understand.
You just be with her now.
You'll keep her here with us.
Aki, where are we?
On an alien planet.
How is that possible?
I'm not entirely sure.
You seem pretty calm.
I have been having this dream
every night for months.
Dream?
Well, whatever it is.
You're really here, aren't you?
What's happening to me?
Dr Sid is implanting the 7th spirit
directly into your body.
Then you are my spiritual support.
Gray, how sweet of you.
Look, I don't think you realize how
serious this situation is.
Something you should see here, sir.
And I am watching... what, major?
It seems Dr Ross has been
recording her dreams.
And why would I be interested in...
her dreams?
This is it.
This is our evidence.
She's under the influence of the phantoms.
Dr Ross's dreams should be
all the Council needs to authorize
the firing of the Zeus cannon.
The Council is contempt to hide
powering inside this barrier
while the world dies a little more everyday.
I believe they need a push in
the right direction, major.
Get together a group of
your most trusted men.
What are they doing?
Why are they staring at us?
Not at us.
Welcome back, captain.
Is it over?
How is she, Doctor?
She is gonna be fine.
But this is only temporary.
We need to find the 8th and
final spirit to cure her.
Aki, can you hear me?
I finished it.
I know what it means,
I know what the phantoms really are.
Nobody move!
You are all under arrest!
We have them, sir.
Sir?
My wife and daughter.
Were killed by phantoms in the San Francisco
barrier when the city was attacked.
Did I ever tell you that?
I try to imagine what...
???  ??? , seeing everyone
around you,
fall over dead with
no apparent reason.
And then at the end,
feeling something next to you.
Invisible... touching you.
Reaching inside your body.
You've lost family, haven't you?
Yes, sir.
That's why I trust you.
All of you.
You know what must be done.
Major, arrest these men.
Reduce power to sector 31.
Sir, you do realize that the phantoms...
What I realize,
major is that we must force the Council
to take action against the enemy.
25% of energy ??? redirect.
Lowering power output to sector 31.
Barrier breach in sector 31, General.
They're coming through now.
I think we can easily handle a few
phantoms in a contain space.
Relax, major.
When this night is over,
you are going to be a hero.
Aki, I don't think...
You were in my dream, Gray.
You saw it.
That's just it.
I'm not sure what I saw.
How can you be?
Captain, please.
Let her continue.
Why do you think,
we've never been able to
determine a relationship
between the human size phantoms
and the giant one's roaming
away slants?
Excuse me, Doc.
But what ???? relationship?
I mean you got your human size phantoms
and your creepy caterpillary phantoms,
and your flying phantoms,
and let's not forget
my personal favorite -
the big fat giant phantoms...
- Down, boy.
- He's right.
If you spend as much time in
the field as we have,
you know there is no relationship.
It's like a zoo out there.
-Precisely,...
I think the giant ones are like our whales or elephants?
-But why will an invading army bring a bunch
of whales or elephants along for the ride?
???That must be ship of some kind of a crazy known as ark.???
We always assume that the meteor was
intended as a form of transportation.
Perhaps it wasn't.
The meteor is a chunk of their planet.
They got thrown into space
when they destroyed their world.
But how could they survive the trip across
outer space on a hunk of rock?
They didn't.
This is all beginning to make
a creepy kind of sense.
What do you think about all this, captain?
I think that explains why we
never had a chance.
All our strategies are based
on one assumption,
that we were fighting alien invaders.
Think of the dream, Gray.
How they died?
Since then,
all they know is suffering.
They are not an invading army.
They are ghosts.
How many phantoms?
More than enough to
convince the Council, sir.
Excellent. Sound an alert, send
the squad out to eliminate them.
Yes, sir.
Sir,
I have numerous phantom contacts.
Well, of course you do.
Outside the sector 31, sir.
And moving in incredible speed.
Major,
what the hell is going on here?
They are in the pipes.
They are moving with bio-etheric energy flow.
That's impossible.
No living thing could survive
in those pipes.
Well, we got a big one heading this way.
Meta class, sir.
Oh my god...
Hold your fire!
What have I done?
Come on, Neil.
We need to find a way out.
Now you are on man, think.
Captain, these wall are titanium alloy.
And the bars are pulse-sonic lasers.
I mean is not like I can just wave
a magic wand and...
Well, Neil, I'm impressed.
That makes two of us.
Proceed to the nearest evacuation
facility.
I think we should proceed to
the nearest evacuation facility.
Proceed to the nearest evacuation facility.
Here they come.
But the others... Dr. Sid!
Deep Eyes will take care of him.
Come on!
What's happening?
Why can we see them now?
Must be carrying residium charge
passing through the barrier.
Behind you!
On the board, captain.
We need to find my ship.
If it was towed inside the city,
it could be in the military hangar.
That's a big "If".
Look out!
- Get us out of the platform.
- You got it.
Okay, now what?
- We're going through the station.
- What?
- Captain, with all due respect...
- Excuse me, captain...
The station, we're going through it.
It's the only way.
Shall I gather this will
be somewhat of a rough ride.
Doc, you've got a talent for
understatement.
Hang on, everybody.
Doc?
Interesting.
Anybody hurt?
Captain!
Oh God! Talk to me, serg.
-Ouch!
- Give me a hand, Jane.
- No, wait!
We're risking further injury.
We need the proper tools
to cut him out.
They are in my ship.
No! No, Doc.
No drugs.
- Captain...
- You heard the man.
We'll find the ship and
we'll be back for you.
- I'll stay with him.
- Me too.
Nobody's staying.
Just give me a gun.
You got it.
Give him a weapon.
Do it!
We'll be back for you, sergeant.
You hear me?
I hear you, captain.
Now get out of here.
Let's move out.
A quad ???.
This is good.
It can be used to retrieve Ryan and
transport him safely here.
However we need to replace
this panel's fuel cell
There could be some live
overpacks in the hangar.
Alright, Jane.
Check the hangar.
Neil, get us ready for take off.
Aki and Dr. Sid prep the quad troll.
I'll go to the tower and rotate the air track.
The city maybe lost.
But we are not.
Let's do this thing and get
the hell out of here.
Gray...
Be careful.
You too.
Oh yeah.
Neil, do you read me?
Loud and clear, captain.
This baby would fly itself.
Flight path is set.
Beginning rotation.
??? air track.
We have a problem.
I'm reading an impound
tracks is still attached ??? the ship.
Can you disengage it
from the cockpit?
No, sir.
Permission to go outside and detach the ???.
Do it!
There is the problem.
The controls are locked naturally.
Jane, let me ask you something.
You think we'll get out of here alive?
I mean I wonder if anybody else
is getting out
You think anyone's made it this far?
You think this 8th spirit stuff is really gonna
work against the phantoms?
I mean what if it is all a
bunch of mambo jumbo?
Jane, do you mind if we stop talking?
I'm trying to concentrate here.
What's happening out there?
Nothing we can't handle.
- What's your status?
- Almost there.
I want you two back inside!
-We're fine, sir.
Jane is negotiating with
extreme ??? .
Talk to me, Jane.
No problem here, Captain.
Yes! Captain, we are good to go.
No!
Jane, get out of there.
Get out now! Go!
Get the hell out of there!
Jane!
The shield is powered and ready.
Where are you going?
To the cockpit.
The ship is set on autopilot
We are in countdown to lift off.
Wait.
It's too dangerous.
Aki!
Over here. You son of a bitch.
Ryan!
Gray, do you read me?
What's happening?
You and Sid are getting out of here now.
No! We can't just leave everyone.
Everyone's dead.
-I'm not leaving without you.
I'm sorry.
But you don't have a choice.
Goodbye, Aki.
I just... I wish I could believe
they are in a better place.
I enlarge the scanning perimeter to include
an area that we had previously overlooked.
The impact crater.
That's a strange place
to find the 8th spirit.
Yes, really, quite astonishing.
But nothing could survive in there
except phantoms.
Precisely.
We have suggested that the 8th
spirit is a phantom spirit.
I can't explain it at the moment,
but once we get down there...
- Wait!
- You'll understand...
- Doctor...
That's the one way trip.
Yes. Yes, I expected that's how
you'll valuate our chances.
What, am I wrong?
No no no, I agree.
We'll probably won't
live long enough
to extract the 8th spirit
from the crater...
Then why should we even try it?
Because we don't need to
extract the 8th spirit.
If we can't bring the final spirit here,
we can go there and complete
the wave inside the crater.
Yes. Exactly.
And how do we do that... exactly?
I can construct the device
that would attach to Aki's chest plate
together the eight spirits and then...
-And then what?
...and then we wait
and see what happens.
That's it?
That's your plan?
We wait and see what happens?
Yes.
Oh good.
But I got my own plan.
We keep scanning the surface from orbit
and maybe we'll find a compatible
spirit somewhere else.
Aki?
I say we go in.
General Hein, you're clear for
docking to zero one alpha.
What caused the barrier to fail,
General Hein?
I'm afraid it was only a matter of time
before the phantoms develop
an immunity to our barriers.
But I'm ??? to see you
and the rest of the Council
were able to evacuate to Houston
without incident.
It was a terrible loss suffer this evening.
The Council had reconsidered your
proposal to fire the Zeus cannon.
I see.
We are transmitting the
access codes to you now.
And General,
best of luck to us all.
Prepare to fire the cannon.
The target, sir?
The phantom crater.
Prepare to drop in three, two, one.
Powering the shield.
Okay, we are __?__?__ .
Do you have it inside, Doctor?
There are so many of them!
Wait. Yes.
I'm tracking the 8th spirit
moving along the crater surface.
Alright.
Now let's take a closer look.
Ready to fire in 3 minutes.
Overpack set maximum.
Transferring plasma flow to off.
Counter thrusters are engaged.
??? Locks flow the couple. ???
Status is green.
We have something on the radar
over the impact site, sir.
It's her.
Sir.
Just a traitor on the influence
of the enemy.
Continue the countdown.
We'll take them all out at the
same time.
We're closing on the phantom.
Contact in 30 seconds.
Target locked.
Ready to fire on your command.
It's a match.
It's a perfect match.
Target scanner is ready, sir.
Fire!
What was that?
It's the Zeus.
They're firing on the crater.
Aki, Captain, are you alright?
A little shaking.
Stand by.
Sid,
the 8th spirit is not on our scanner.
Do you have it?
The 8th has been destroyed.
What are we going to do now?
Nothing. This mission is over.
We have to get out of here.
Incoming!
What is that?
If you gonna get us out of here,
you better do it now.
Hold on!
I can't hold on to you.
Unable to maintain altitude.
Emergency landing procedures.
Come in, come in, please
Aki, Gray, can you hear me?
Sid, I need to talk to the station.
Can you patch us through?
What is that thing?
I don't know, sir.
Incoming message, sir.
General Hein ,
you must cease fire immediately.
What are you looking at
in the crater is the living spirit
of an alien's home world.
The planet was destroyed and
part of it landed here.
This is not an invasion.
It never was.
Oh, I see.
And what we have been
fighting all this time, Doctor?
Ghosts?
Yes, spirits that are confused ,
lost and angry.
Oh right?
And these spirits
are coming out of this Gaia thing?
-General Hein, you have to listen!
-Alien Gaia, Earth Gaia...
Doctor,
even if I believe in such nonsense,
The fact remains. The Earth is
under attack
from aggressor who must
be destroyed at all cost.
The cost may be the entire planet, sir.
Firing on the alien Gaia
will only make it stronger.
Since you are under the
alien influence, Doctor,
I will take your protest to mean
that we are in fact pursuing
the correct course of action.
I suggest you take your last few moments
and prepare to meet your Gaia.
Continue to fire until the invaders
have been destroyed!
General, the system is overheated, sir.
We are going to hit again and again.
And keep on hitting it,
until it's dead.
But sir, we not even sure if it has
any affect on the creature.
No affect?
We've got them in a run,
soldier.
This is our moment of victory.
I order you to fire.
The system won't allow us to fire again.
We'll see about that.
The shield is out,
we're sitting ducks in here.
Come on.
This is not a good place to be.
What the hell is that?
- That's something what I think it is, is it?
- Yes! It's Gaia.
It is definitely not a good place to be.
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
I have to talk to Dr. Sid.
Sid, do you read me?
Go ahead. I'm still here.
We are looking at Gaia.
Do you hear me, sir? Gaia!
I think this explains why the 8th spirit
appeared here.
Yes. Yes, that's it.
A phantom must have changed
into the 8th spirit
when it touched a new life born
from our own Gaia.
If so, it would have been
given a different energy signature
that set it apart from the
other phantoms.
You two could not have hope
for a better location to find
a new compatible spirit.
Whatever you do,
don't move.
Stay right where you are.
Staying right where we are may
not be as easy as it sound.
Don't shoot any of them.
You could very well destroy our last hope.
And what do you suggest I do,
Doctor?
Ask them to play nice?
Combat strategy is your area of expertise,
captain, not mine.
I have a reading here in the ___?__?__.
Do you see it?
Yes, a compatible spirit.
It must be very near you.
Well, Which one is it?
Which one?
I'm having difficulties  __?__?__.
Just a moment, please.
Doctor, it's getting crowded in here.
Aki, we don't have much time.
Aki...Aki!
With the hope of new life,
has Gaia changed the phantom within?
I have it.
Gray, get in here. I need you.
Do you hear me, Sid?
The wave pattern is complete.
Yes, I read you.
This is wonderful.
I don't see how you could
have found the final spirit.
It found me, Doctor.
I see now. I understand.
Well, I don't understand.
What the hell is going on?
Give me your overpack.
I need to project the
completed wave.
But, we'll be defenseless.
- Just do it!
I hope you know what you are
doing, Aki.
We can use the shield
to project the wave.
Dr Sid's theory was right.
I have it, the 8th spirit.
I'm cured, Gray.
Are you sure you have
the final spirit?
Yes, yes. I'm sure.
But how?
How can you know that?
Don't worry,
the phantom told me.
Oh, great.
That's it. Shield on.
It's not working.
We have to do something
before it's too late.
If this doesn't work,
then it's already too late.
Gray... trust me.
No! No!
Get down!
Warning system overload.
I know.
I know!
But it must be done.
Fire! Fire! Damn it!
Fire!
Gray?
Gray!
Don't leave me, Gray.
Told Sid this was an one-way trip.
Looks like I was right.
No, Gray. Hang on, please.
I still have the wave.
We can get through this.
We are not gonna make it.
We are going to make it.
We both know that isn't true.
Gray...
Help me.
Listen to me.
You saved my life once.
Now I want you to save yourself.
Gray, no. Please.
Let me do this, Aki.
Trust me.
Don't leave me, Gray.
You have been trying to tell me
the death isn't the end.
Don't back out on me.
Now when I finally believe.
I love you.
Oh, it's warm. 