- German bandits at 2 o'clock!
- Increase throttle! Power dive!
Spell it right, Rafe.
"Rudder" is spelled with two D's.
- Thanks, wingman.
- Yeah, sure.
Whoa, bandits!
- Crack shootin', Danny.
- Crack shootin', Rafe.
- Land ofthe free.
- Home ofthe brave.
Great flyin', Dad!
Come on. I'm gonna
teach you how to fly.
- I get the front!
- No, you take the back.
I'm bigger,
and I should be in front.
I'm older and I'm teachin',
so no.
- Wow. It's like we're really flying.
- Yeah, I did it lots oftimes.
Come on. You man the guns.
I'll give her some throttle.
We gotta get those
dirty German bandits.
Oh, gosh!
- Hang on!
- Make it stop, Rafe!
I've seen my dad do this
lots oftimes. Don't worry!
Rafe!
- Oh, my gosh! We're flying!
- We're flying!
My dad's gonna kill me.
Come on.
Yes! Woo-hoo!
- We flew!
- We flew! Yes! I'm a pilot!
- I know!
- Yeah!
We flew.
- You no-account boy!
- Daddy!
I done told you, you spend time playing
with this stupid boy, can't read...
you ain't never gonna
amount to nothin'!
He ain't stupid, Daddy!
Daddy!
Come on!
Get on back home. Now!
Get on up.
You got work to do.
Come on!
Come on. Get on home!
You let him alone!
Daddy, no!
I will bust you open,
you dirty German!
What'd you call me?
I fought the Germans
in France.
And I fought 'em
in the trenches.
And I pray to God no one ever
has to see the things that I saw.
You're my best friend.
Daddy, wait!
Daddy, wait.
AdolfHitlerbuilds
the German militarymachine...
anddrags
allofEurope into war.
But even while France falls to Hitler...
America stillrefuses
tojoin the fighting.
- Where's McCawley and Walker?
- Still training, sir.
All right, Danny.
Now, let's show 'em how to fly.
We're gonna play chicken.
You ready?
This ain't the farm,
and these ain't no crop dusters.
- I'm not playing chicken with ya.
- Now don't be a baby.
I'll tell you what.
- I'm not doing it, Rafe.
- Well, I'm coming right at you.
You can turn oryou can hit me.
It's up to you.
- What the--
- Oh, boy.
Why you always
bustin' my ass, Rafe?
Which way you goin'?
I guess I'll go right.
No, left. I'll go left.
- Okay, we're goin' left, right?
- Uh. right. Right?
"Right" Iike we're going right
or "right" Iike we're going left?
Now you got me all mixed up!
I don't know. Make up your mind.
God, Rafe, we're going right!
Righty-tighty!
Those are some smooth aces.
Did you say something?
'Cause let me tell ya,
those farm boys are grounded!
Yes, sir, an entirely unacceptable use
of m-m-military aircraft, sir.
- Get my hat.
- Yes, sir.
Get those hedge-hoppers
in Doolittle's office.
After two years oftraining...
you believe that a $45,000 aeroplane
is there foryour amusement?
No, sir. I wasjust trying
to keep my edge, Major.
And when you did the outside loop
last week, what did you think that was?
Honing your skills?
That's not training, McCawley.
That's a stunt.
And I personally consider it
to be reckless and irresponsible.
Major.
How could that be when you're famous
for being the first man in the world
ever to do it?
- Don't get cute with me, son.
- No, sir. I--
I don't mean to be disrespectful.
I just think that-- Well, l--
It is reckless and irresponsible if
you'rejust doing it to be a show-off.
But I was doing it
to try to inspire the men, sir...
in the way that
you've inspired me.
I believe the French
even have a word for that...
when the men get together
to honour their leaders.
They call it an homage, sir.
- A what?
- An homage, sir.
That's bullshit, McCawley!
But it's very, very good bullshit.
Thankyou, sir.
McCawley, you remind me
of myself 1 5 years ago.
Which is why we need
to discuss this.
Have a seat, son.
The British have accepted you
into the Eagle Squadron.
You're on your way to England
tomorrow, ifyou still want to go.
Wow.
Just a few British pilots
are all that stand...
between Hitler
and total victory in Europe.
They're gonna need all the help
they can get.
Yes, sir.
Well, I'm on my way.
Just for the record, I'm supposed
to askyou to reconsider.
- Sir?
- Sooner or later...
we're gonna be in this war
whether we like it or not.
And I'm gonna need
all of my best pilots.
So it's my duty
to askyou to stay.
Major, what would you do?
If it was me...
I'd go.
God! Am I going bald
right back here?
Ooh!
Man, I am one good-lookin'
son ofa bitch.
Don't you ever die.
Die. That's exactly the concept
you gotta work tonight.
You put a drop ofthis clove oil
underyour eyes...
and you let 'em sting
and well up.
You get your nurse alone,
take a breath...
Iet her see your eyes glisten
and say...
"Baby, they're training me for war...
and I don't know
what'll happen...
but if I die tomorrow...
I want to know that we lived
all we could tonight."
Come on, guys!
We got nurses waitin'.
Come on, before the rest
of his hair falls out.
How could you do this?
Well, Doolittle assigned me.
He wanted me to get some real--
real combat training in.
Well, guess what?
It's not training over there.
It's war...
where the losers die
and there aren't any winners...
just guys who turn into
broken-down wrecks like my father.
Yeah, I understand that, Danny,
but I feel like I got a duty to go.
Don't preach to me about duty, damn it.
I wear the same uniform you do.
Now, iftrouble wants me, I'm ready
for it, but why go looking for it?
God, Danny, come on. I'm gonna be 25.
I might as well be an old man.
They're gonna have me bein'
a flight instructor.
I don't wanna teach
loops and barrel rolls.
- I wanna be a combat fighter.
- Hey, come on!
The nurses can't
d-d-dance by themselves.
Let's go.
Ifthe call to duty means seeing
1 50 men in their underwear every day...
we are here to serve.
I can't believe it.
Saturday night in New York City.
Do you know what they're doing
where I come from? Nothing.
Cow tipping.
That's why
you joined the navy, hon.
Get out ofthat dusty little town
and see the world.
May I remind you, Barbara,
we're navy nurses, not tourists.
I joined to do my patriotic duty
and to meet guys.
Me too.
Girls, we're gonna have so much fun
tonight in the city.
You gotta tell them
the story, Evelyn.
What?
Oh, come on. Tell us.
- Oh, it's such a long story.
- We got time.
I saw it happen.
Well, it was about four weeks ago.
What do you think
is b-better?
All in the one cheek
or spreading them out?
Okay.
Fusco, Anthony.
You all right, buddy?
Sweetie, do you really
have to do this?
I'm not gonna get yellow fever
in my barracks.
No? lfyou'd rather,
she can do it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
J-J-Just gimme a minute.
Honey, the government says
stick 'em, we stick 'em.
Hey, Red, you all right?
Eye exam number four?
Listen, Doc, I have passed
a dozen medical checks.
You write that,
they won't let me fly.
Sorry, son.
I'm gonna fail.
They're gonna take my wings away.
No, they won't.Just relax.
Read the bottom line, please.
Just keep practisin'
the bottom line.
And don't worry.
I'm right behind you.
J-L-M-K-P-O--
Thankyou.
- Next.
- Ma'am.
J-L-M-K-P-O-E-T-X.
Eyes like an eagle, ma'am.
Slow down, flyboy.
And instead ofthe bottom,
read the very top. Both eyes.
"C." Sorry. "J."
"C," "W," uh, "Q", uh, "Q"
Read the bottom line again, please,
but read it right to left...
and every other letter.
E-X--
- X-E.
X-E, ma'am.
Ma'am, I know how this looks.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant.
I really am...
but army and navy
requires 20/20 vision.
Oh, l-- It's not a problem
with my eyes. I mean, I can see.
I mean, I can hit a running rabbit
with a $3.00 pistol.
I got a problem with letters,
that's all.
Well, maybe after some schooling,
you could come back
and take the test again.
No, I had schooling.
I mean, the teachersjust
never knew what to make of it.
It'sjust letters.
I mix 'em up sometimes. That's all.
I mean, I just get 'em
backward sometimes.
Look here. My math and spacial reasoning
and my verbal scores are all excellent.
But you barely passed
the written exam.
Yeah, but he did pass it.
So is it my turn now?
- No, you'll wait your turn.
- Yes, ma'am.
Ma'am, I'm never gonna be
an English teacher.
But I know why I'm here:
to be a pilot.
And you don't dogfight with manuals.
You don't fly with gauges.
It is all about feeling and speed...
and lettin' that plane become
like a part ofyour body.
And that manual says that a guy who's
a slow reader can't be a good pilot.
That file says
I'm the best pilot in this room.
Ma'am, please,
don't take my wings.
Well, I felt so bad.
Evelyn, rotate to station three.
I had no choice.
I passed him.
So then this cocky pilot
comes back.
- Say, fella, are you enlisted?
- Yeah.
"Yeah"?
Boy, you're talking to an officer.
- Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
- Give me that file.
- Yes, sir.
- Parade rest.
Yes, sir.
Ma'am, I didn't get
a chance to thankyou.
Drop your skiwies.
Oh. Okay.
Just like this?
That's fine.
He did have a very cute butt.
You know, I know you didn't have
to pass me, and you did.
And I just-- I didn't think
you'd understand, and you did.
You know, you still
haven't said thankyou.
- Thankyou.
- You're welcome.
Why'd you do it?
I mean, I'm just curious.
You're like my hero now.
Actually, my father was a pilot...
and I've seen firsthand what happens
when a pilot loses his wings.
You know what?
Your father's my hero then too.
In fact, as an officer,
I think it'd be my duty...
to take my new hero's daughter out
tonightjust to--
- Gosh, did I poke too deep?
- I thinkyou hit the bone there.
You are so mean.
What, so is-- so is there any chance
that you might kind of, sort of...
you know, like me, or--
How did you guess?
They never taught us how
to deal with this feeling.
What feeling?
Well, it's kind of like this.
Well, he was getting fresh,
so I poked him again.
All right, Romeo.
I want to get this over with.
Hold on a second.
Miss, I really, really lickyou.
Ah! What did he mean?
Like you.
I didn't mean to say that.
And I just, um...
I just want to askyou, please,
if I can donate dinner.
He started to act very strange.
Or, well, buy you dinner.
- This isn't your chart.
- Whoa!
No. That's the, uh, this fellow
over here's. I think he left.
Have you already
had this shot?
Yeah, well, once already.
Well, I wanted-- I mean, I just--
can I askyou out?
No.
And hejust went wham!
Oh! What'd you do to him?
Poor guy.
Hey!
Oh, my God.
Are you okay?
Uh, yeah.
I'm fine. I feel great.
This isjust standard,
precautionary thing.
But, look, I got some, uh, genuine
French champagne from France.
And I thought, you know,
maybe we could celebrate.
Celebrate what?
Oh, I don't know.
You being my hero, for one.
Okay. Why not?
So I wanted to thankyou...
and I just wanted to put your mind
at ease about passing me...
because I really do think
you did this country a service.
I mean, I am a great flier.
And ifyou have a fault, which you
obviously don't, it's modesty.
No. If I have a fault,
it's candour.
You arejust so--
Corkjust got away from me.
God, it hurts!
It hurts something fierce.
I'm sorry.
- It's bleeding.
- God.
Oh.
- Lay still.
- I ruined everything. Oh, it hurts.
- It's cold!
- It'll stop the bleeding.
- I can't breathe.
- Lay still.
You are so beautiful,
it hurts.
It's your nose that hurts.
I think it's my heart.
And then I kissed him.
Evelyn, that's the most romantic story
I ever heard.
It's been the most romantic
four weeks and two days of my life.
I'm sojealous.
Hello, Lieutenant.
It's good to see you.
- You, too, Lieutenant.
- Pick a hand.
It's beautiful.
What's in your other hand?
Mine.
Well, it took me six hours
to fold these.
I want you to meet
my friends.
Rafe, this is Martha,
Barbara, Sandra.
- Hi. I'm Betty.
- Hi.
Would you happen
to have any friends?
Take your pick.
Hi.
We ever get in this war
and somethin' happens to me...
I can't tell you how good
it makes me feel to know...
that someone as sweet as you will
be there to nurse me back to health.
Good, but we're not
in the waryet.
Okay. That was a bad line.
Hi.
I'm-- I'm Red.
Red S-S-Strange.
- Your last name's Strange?
- Yeah, she's all yours, soldier.
No. It's-- It's Winkle.
Red is such a ladies' man.
- Do you always stutter?
- No. Only when I'm--
She's totally buying it.
- Nervous?
- Yeah.
Why can't I get
something like that?
- Hello.
- Hi.
Danny seems kind ofshy
around the girls.
It's not that he's shy.
He'sjust a little unsure
of himself, you know.
His old man used to
run him down a lot.
Get him in a plane,
he's sure of himself.
He's like my brother.
He's like my best friend.
You know, my right hand.
Which, at the moment,
is a long way south of my waist.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I guess I lost
a little altitude.
Yeah, I guess you did.
Excuse me.
You and me,
we got to talk.
So the rumour is the navy's
shipping us to Pearl Harbor.
Well, won't be so bad.
It's about as far from
the fighting as you can get.
You'll get a suntan.
So maybe the army
will post you guys there too.
You are
a super special woman.
And, and, well--
Well, they're training me
to be a big bad warrior...
and, well--
So I mean, you never know
what might happen tomorrow or--
or any day after that,
you know?
So...
God, we need to make tonight
super special.
Why are you crying?
I guess it's the thought that I might
not ever get to see you again.
Dry your eyes, toots.
Tonight you're mine.
I don't want to be
with a crowd tonight.
I just want to be
alone with you.
Well, how does New York Harbor
by moonlight sound?
Are you gonna be
a bad influence?
Ofcourse
I'm a bad influence.
Let's see ifwe can
commandeer this vessel...
'cause we're officers
ofthe U.S. government.
Not for long, we won't be.
One day, we'll take a trip
on a boat like that.
Would you like that?
We'll be dressing for cocktails
and walk into the Grand Salon.
No one's talking about war.
They'rejust dancing to Cole Porter.
- I'll have to get a tux.
- Yeah.
- Come on. There you go. All aboard.
- You're out ofyour mind.
Yeah. Careful now.
Here, sit down.
Now, let's see here.
There we go.
See, this is as close
as I could get you to your ship.
So at least I tried, right?
Actually, you know what?
This is better.
Yeah, it is.
God, you're pretty.
What's gonna become
of us all, Rafe?
Well, the future's not
exactly in our hands, is it?
No. I guess you're right.
Oh, my God!
Are you all right?
- Yeah, are you?
- That was not part ofthe date.
- Watch your step.
- Oh, thankyou.
- Evelyn!
- Guys, come up! Come on--
Come up!
We're in 32 1 .
There's something
I got to tell you.
Well, you got no secrets
from me, Lieutenant.
I've seen your medical chart.
This can't be good,
or it wouldn't be so hard to say.
Yeah. I got to go away.
We're all going away.
Yeah...
but I'm going to the war
tomorrow.
I'm flying with
the Eagle Squadron.
It's an outfit the British started
for American pilots.
I don't understand.
You're in the U.S. Army.
How could they orderyou to go?
They didn't order me.
I volunteered.
But I passed you.
I let you through.
And now you volunteer for the most
dangerous place you could go?
It's not your responsibility,
not your choice.
Flying's the only thing
I ever wanted to do.
I mean, everything in my life
has led me up to this point.
Meeting you.
I love you.
I love you so much.
Let's go inside.
All right. Wait a minute.
I just-- I can't do this.
Thisjust-- It's not right.
I'm sorry. I just--
See, I can't do this.
I mean, l--
I mean, I can.
I-- I want to.
I'm not trying
to be noble, you know.
Or not saying
I know what would happen.
Orjust--
I need to stop talking.
I just-- I just don't want it-- I just
don't want it to be like everybody else.
I don't want you to have anything
about tonight that you'll regret.
I mean, it's been
the most incredible night of my life...
and I don't want
to ruin that.
Oh, you couldn't ruin it.
If I had one more night to live,
I'd want to spend it with you.
See, that's what I want
to come home to.
That's what I want to have
to think about and dream about.
I want to know that the best part
of my life is still ahead of me.
Look.
Don't--
Could you
not come see me off?
Because saying goodbye to you
once is hard enough.
Here.
- Take this.
- You think it looks good on me?
I will come back.
I thought you said
you told her not to come.
- Yeah, I did.
- Why are you looking for her then?
It's my test.
If I tell her not to come,
and she comes anyway...
then l--
I know she loves me.
All aboard!
Track 57!
If, uh, anything
happens to me...
I want you to be
the one to tell her, all right?
You just make sure and come back
for the both of us, all right?
- See you when I get back.
- Yeah.
Good hunting, Rafe.
Evelyn! Evelyn!
Evelyn!
Evelyn! Evelyn! Hey!
She loves me.
The German Luftwaffe relentlessly
bombards downtown London...
while Churchill'sRoyaIAirForce
is in a deadlystruggle...
to maintain control
ofthe British skies.
This is a real mess.
Lieutenant McCawley
reporting for duty, sir.
Good. We'll get you settled
into your quarters...
and then introduce you
to the crate you'll be flying.
Yes, sir, well, ify'all are patching up
bullet holes right here on the runway...
maybe we ought to skip housekeeping
and get me right into an aeroplane.
Two didn't come back, sir.
We counted only eleven.
Are all Yanks as anxious as you
to get themselves killed, Pilot Officer?
Not anxious to die, sir.
Just anxious to matter.
This is yours.
Good chap.
Didn't die till he'd landed
and shut down his engine.
Please be seated,
gentlemen.
I'm afraid
I'm in a bad mood.
Churchill and Stalin are asking me
what I'm asking you.
How long is America going
to pretend the world is not at war?
We've increased food and oil supply
shipments to them, Mr President...
and as far as I know--
What they really need are tanks, planes,
bullets, bombs and men to fight.
But our people think Hitler and
his Nazi thugs are Europe's problem.
We have to do more.
Send the Brits and Russians more of
our ships and anti-aircraft weapons.
And keep cannibalizing
the Pacific Fleet?
What choice do we have?
We're building refrigerators
while our enemies build bombs.
This is so exciting.
You know, there's about
a hundred ships on Pearl.
And how many sailors per ship?
It depends. There's more
on a battleship than a sub.
But say, on average, 2,000?
Yeah, but then there's the fliers,
the marines, the base personnel.
I'm still working on the sailors.
Girls, I think the odds
are in your favour.
Yeah, like 4,000 to 1 .
It's paradise.
See you on the beach, boys!
We're in Hawaii!
Hey, you know, you're not
supposed to be paintin' titties
on the side of my aeroplanes.
And ifyou do,
don't make 'em lopsided.
- They were lopsided, Earl.
- Look, it says right here.
"Never ride waves amongst rocks
or submerged pilings."
See, it says
you shouldn't do that.
Well, how you gonna know they're
submerged ifthey're submerged?
Hey, Gooz, what in the hell
are you doing?
He's trying to fix
this surfboard thing of his.
He keeps taking chunks off his nose
on the rocks.
I thought I'd come in on my day off,
work on my new invention--
the Gooz cruise fin.
I'm gonna be a rich fella.
Every surfboard in the nation's
gonna need one.
Yeah?
You're gonna need a broom.
Oh. Check out
these new recruits.
- Hi.
- Aloha.
Y'all pilots?
We're working on it.
There's a lot ofswitches
and stuff.
- Pride ofthe Pacific.
- Who are you?
Terrors ofthe Skies.
- Welcome, ladies.
- Hi.
I have to deal with
Coastie's sunburnt rump...
before I can show you around.
Dear Evelyn...
it's different than I thought
it would be here.
It's cold.
So cold it goes deep
into your bones.
There is one place
I can go to find warmth.
That is to think ofyou.
I just wish I could be
back there with you.
It's not easy making friends.
Two days ago, I had a beer
with a couple ofthe RAF pilots.
Yesterday,
both ofthem got killed.
Dear Rafe...
I miss you so much.
It's so strange to be
halfa world away from you.
I'm right on his tail!
Got one!
Every night I look at the sunset...
and try to draw the last ounce
of heat from its long day...
and send it
from my heart to yours.
Family?
Girl, sir.
The girl.
A lot of people frown on the Yanks
for not being in this waryet.
I'd just like to say...
ifthere are many more
back home like you...
God help anyone who goes
to war with America.
Atten-hut!
Attention on deck!
Admiral Kimmel...
commander-in-chief,
Pacific Fleet, on deck.
Sharp presentation, Captain.
Thankyou, Admiral Kimmel.
For four months now,
Washington's been blowing pink smoke...
about the threat fromJapan.
Could make us lose our fighting edge.
I'm determined not to let that happen.
With your permission,
Captain.
Admiral, urgent,
from Washington.
I'm supposed to keep this fleet
battle-ready to take on theJapanese...
cover halfthe damn globe.
Now they want me to transfer
another 1 2 destroyers to the Atlantic.
Don't they know what
we're facing out here?
They feel Europe
is the greater danger, Admiral.
I'm assuming these risk assessments
include Hawaii.
Well, Pearl Harbor is too shallow
for an aerial torpedo attack...
and we're surrounded by sub nets.
All we have to worry about here
is sabotage...
so we bunched our planes together
to make them easier to protect.
Distance is our ally, Admiral.
You analysts got it
all figured out, don't you?
The smart enemy hits you exactly
where you thinkyou're safe.
I fixed the hydraulics
and electrical systems, sir...
but the oil hoses
still need attention.
-Just crank it, lan!
- God speed you, sir.
Red section, take the bombers.
Blue section, look out for fighters.
Bombers dead ahead.
Let's drop in on 'em
and give 'em a reception.
Red Two, follow my lead,
high side.
- Go right at the lead bomber.
- Following you, Red One.
Good hit! Good hit!
Red One, coming around,
reset for the kill.
I have the middle bomber.
Hammer down!
We got him.
Nice shot, Red Two.
I got two M.E.'s dead ahead.
I'm on him. I'm on his tail.
Hammer down.
I got one ofthem!
I got another one.
Red One, you got fighters
all overyour tail!
I'm under fire!
I'm taking fire!
Red One, get out ofthere.
Pull up! Pull up!
I got an oil leak!
Can't see a damn thing!
I can't bail!
My canopy's stuck!
I can't bail out!
He's on my tail, Red Two.
I'm hit! I'm hit!
Mayday! Mayday!
Oh, my God.
- I'm no good at church.
- What do you mean, sweetie?
Well, whenever I'm up there
getting my slate wiped clean...
I can't help but think of how
I'm gonna dirty it up again.
- This from a virgin.
- I've got to inventory supplies.
Oh! Kill me now.
Could you be any more boring?
Don't bother.
Sundays she writes Rafe.
Ten pages
instead ofthe usual five.
Gosh, I wish I was in love.
Hey, sweetheart.
She hates me.
- Good to see you, Red.
- Sure good to see you, too, Betty.
What are you doing?
You wanna come for a ride? Come on.
Yeah, I'll be your chauffeur.
That-a-boy! Be a mad dog!
You hit pretty hard
for a cook.
All right, Walker, who you got?
Come on. Fight's almost over.
- I'll take the cook.
- Why? You don't like money?
Come on!
Get out there now!
- I'll put five on it.
- Done.
Against the mechanic?
That guy craps rivets.
How's it feel up from that dark, oily
engine room? Sunlight botherin' you?
Ow.
Man, he's getting
all busted up in there!
Move! Move!
Come here. We gotta talk.
Get down here.
- He can't hurt us.
- He can hurt us.
- He cut us. We bleeding.
- Bleeding?
That's a scratch.
You see this here?
This here's the hard-earned greenbacks
ofevery pot-scrubbin', dish-washin'
chop in this here fleet.
Now, ifwe don't win, the Teeny here
has to find himselfanother battleship.
'Cause there's no way I'm going back
to the Arizona empty-handed.
Don't worry about the money.
I'm gonna send that smug
engine-fixin' snipe...
back below decks
where he belong.
Come on, man! We the man!
You the man!
He slapped your mama, remember?
Be a son ofa bitch!
Look at this!
All right, Dorie!
That's enough.
Oh! Where's my money?
Nah. Fight's rigged.
We're rich!
How'd you get this?
Boxing.
Did you win?
Yes, ma'am.
What do you get
for winning?
Respect.
So why do you have to fight
with your fists to get respect?
I left my mama in Texas and
joined the navy to see the world...
become a man.
They made me a cook.
Not even that. I, uh,
clean up after other sailors eat.
Two years, they never even
let me fire a weapon.
Well, let's hope
you never have to.
Yes, ma'am.
You take care,
Petty Officer Miller.
You, too, ma'am.
You know,
he taught me to fly.
I always knew that no matter
what kind oftrouble I got into...
I'd never be in it alone.
He'd be there with me.
Up there, he was always pushing me
to be better and faster.
He told me you were
a great flier.
It was the same night he told me
he volunteered to go to England.
Volunteered?
He--
He told me
he'd been assigned.
He was always
trying to protect me.
But you know what? I look at myself
in the mirror in this uniform...
and I still don't know
who I am.
I look like a hero...
but I don't feel like it.
Rafe...
he always looked the part,
didn't he?
He couldn't wait to be one.
To Rafe McCawley.
The best pilot...
and the best friend
I ever knew...
or ever will know.
To Rafe.
Look at this. Look at this.
TheJapanese are flooding
the Pacific with radio traffic.
Everywhere from the Panama Canal
to Southeast Asia.
There's no logical pattern
in it, Captain.
No, there's--
There's always logic.
They know we read their mail.
They're trying to make us think
their fleet is moving south.
I'm not buying it.
Something, something--
Something's up.
Otherwise, why would they take
the trouble to bullshit me?
Evelyn, um, I signed for
these letters foryou today.
They're from England.
They're from Rafe.
I'm sorry, Ev.
You know how long
it takes mail to get here.
- Hurry up!
- Show time, boys! Come on!
America stillawaitsJapan's response
topeaceproposals.
AmbassadorNomura
arrives in Washington...
in what couldhopefullyguarantee
continuedpeace in the Pacific.
On the British front.
Churchilldeclares...
"Give us the tools.
and we willfinish thejob. "
The RAFhasfought bravely...
against Hitler'sambition
to rule theskies overthe Channel.
Victorydoesnot come
withoutsacrifice.
- Evelyn!
- Danny.
- Hey.
- Some comedy, huh?
- Yeah.
- It's been awhile.
Yeah, I've been logging
a lot offlight hours.
I kinda been
avoiding you too.
Yeah.
- Look--
- Do you--
- Do you want to?
- Sure, yeah.
I remember this one time
when I was like seven years old.
I was always building
these gadgets and things.
He told me he wanted me
to build him some wings...
so that he could fly like
his daddy, dusting crops.
I told him you can't fly without
some kind ofengine, right?
But he wouldn't listen.
You know, he told me...
"Danny, never mind all that.
Just build 'em anyway."
So I did.
And I'm up there, strapping
these big ol' wings on his back...
that we made from paper and glue
and these massive silk bloomers
that we stole.
He looked so stupid, you know?
And I told him...
"You can'tjump off
the barn in these."
And bam!
He busted his leg
on the backhoe.
God, I miss him.
Yeah, but don't you think that Rafe
wasn't back up there the next day...
cast and everything...
telling me to make some
adjustments on those wings.
Wow. Check this out.
Crossroads to the Pacific.
Tahiti, 1 ,700 miles.
All right! Okay.
Say, Betty.
- No, Betty! Get up!
- What's going on, Red?
- You've gotta stand up, please.
- What do you mean, get up?
Just stand up.
Stand up here.
Oh!
- Betty--
- Red, come on!
We got a dinner reservation.
Can I get a minute?
What's the matter,
you sick?
Can a guy propose?
Oh! Thankyou!
Am I talking too much?
Sometimes I do that. I'm sorry.
Hold up. Look at this.
Hello.
- Okay, let's get out of here.
- Okay. Hey!
I guess I should go.
Don't let it be three months
before I see you again, all right?
- I had a good time.
- Yeah, me too.
- Do you want me to walkyou home?
- No, I'll be fine.
No. Ofcourse.
- Good night, Danny.
- Good night.
I wasjust wondering if maybe
I could come by some time...
get a cup ofcoffee
or a piece of pie.
What am I doing?
Okay.
Oh! You were asleep.
I'm sorry.
Danny?
Is something wrong?
No! There's nothing wrong.
There's no problem. Hi.
It'sjust Danny.
I just-- You--
You forgot this.
Oh.
Thanks. It was good ofyou to take
the trouble to drop it over now.
I-- I thought you might need it,
you know...
uh, maybe tomorrow morning.
If, uh-- I mean, not that
you wear this to work, but--
No. It's a hanky.
Right, right. Yeah.
Listen, I was thinking
maybe, uh, I could come by
some time or give you call--
If I gave you a call,
could I come by some time?
Once, maybe,
ifyou're not busy?
Yeah, maybe.
- Maybe?
- Maybe.
Okay, all right.
- Thanks. Good night.
- Goodbye. Good night. Good night.
You are such an idiot.
- Did you have fun last night?
- It wasn't how it looked.
And if it was, it'd be all right.
It's been months. It's time to move on.
- I am moving on.
- Ev, don't lie.
All I know is I hearyou crying
when you think I'm asleep.
When my dad left, I was too much
for my mom to handle...
so she sent me
to live with my aunt.
I thought my life was over, but you
don't know where it's all going to lead.
If I hadn't have run away and lied
about my age and enlisted in the navy...
I-- I wouldn't have met Red,
and-- now he's my fianc.
Oh, God, I can't
get used to that word.
- It's only been 1 2 hours.
- Oh, Betty.
Uh, Little Betty beat us all
to the post.
And this is ward three.
As you can see, no patients.
Welcome to Hawaii.
Come on. I'll show you the bar.
Sandra, new recruits to torture.
- Come on. Excuse me, ladies.
- Hi!
We're gonna wait two years until
I'm 1 9 and Red can buy me a ring.
Rafe sent his best friend to tell you
so you would be okay...
so you can move on.
You gotta go on living, Ev.
Red!
Oh! Sorry.
Bye, Rafe.
TheJapanese fleet is missing.
They're operating
under radio silence.
This footage was shot
four days ago on October 28.
Well, we're sending scout planes in
wider vectors all over the Pacific...
but they get nothing.
Now, they could be
anywhere in here.
I don't understand how two whole
carrier divisions can just disappear.
Clear!
Oh, we're all over the page.
We got one walleyed
and one pigeon-toed.
- Anthony, tap in number six.
- All right.
- Gooz?
- Yeah?
- Tap in number three.
- All right.
Hey, we got a visitor.
Oh, that ain't no
navy issue uniform, eh?
- Danny, it's Evelyn.
-Jesus.
- You all right?
- Yeah, yeah.
No.
I think I'm falling for her.
Wow. You know,
I saw this coming.
I didn't want this to happen.
Itjust kind ofdid. Can't help it.
Well, Danny, she's got to be
with somebody. It might as well be you.
You're telling me
ifyou were dead, and you saw
your best buddy doing your girl...
you wouldn't come back and
beat the livin' crap out of him?
- Tony, back off.
- I'd be back so fast.
Danny's being a better friend
taking care of her himself.
I got a girlfriend.
That's great.
Come on, fellas. Let's split.
Danny, whatever happens now is
just about you and her.
You got to try
and forget about Rafe.
Be careful, all right?
Ladies cloud the mind.
- Thanks, Gooz.
- You're welcome.
Hey, Danny.
Where's everybody going?
Just being discreet.
Does it seem like everybody's
acting a little strange?
No, no.
Right.
Well, maybe--
maybe a little, yeah.
Well, people in this outfit have way
too much time on their hands.
Oh, yeah.
I just hope they don't think
there's been something going on
between us. That's all.
Oh, no, I mean, no. I mean,
that would be embarrassing, right?
I forgot my wrenches.
- It'd definitely be embarrassing.
- Yeah.
- Hi. Forgot my wrenches.
- Hey. He really doesn't have to leave.
No.
I, uh-- I'm just going out
with the girls, so--
- Guess I'll see you later.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Yeah. All right. I'll see you around.
Shit.
Evelyn?
Have you ever seen
Pearl Harbor at sunset?
- Ofcourse.
- Well, from the air?
You know, I could get kicked out
ofthe military for this.
- Really?
- Yes. Stay down.
The Hawaiians call
this harbour WaiMomi.
- It means "water of pearls."
- It's so beautiful.
My dad took me up
a couple oftimes.
Just don't do what he did.
What do you call it? When you flip over?
- A barrel roll?
- Yeah.
Oh.
Oh!
Oh, my God.
- What do you think?
- I like that.
- Hey, that plane was supposed...
- Duck.
to be back here an hour ago.
Quick. Hide in
the parachute hangar.
My heart is pounding.
Danny, last night--
No, that's terrible.
Danny, we need
to talk about this.
- Sir. Evelyn!
- Danny!
Hey. Hi.
Hi.
I didn't sleep a wink
last night.
I had to see ya.
Last night was crazy, I know,
but I'm not sorry.
Are you?
I don't know.
Danny, I had a wonderful time
last night. I--
- It'sjust all too fast.
- Listen, Evelyn.
I wasjust down at the beach this
morning, and I watched the sun rise...
and I knew that everything
was gonna be different...
that this was the start
ofsomething new...
in this place,
in this moment...
and I don't care
what anybody else says, you know?
How can I not feel this way?
I kind of like ya.
Oh, you do?
You have your tie on crooked.
Everything's gonna
be all right, okay?
Everything's gonna be all right.
Do you have any air tours
going through the valley of Oahu?
You do?
Aloha. This is KGMB
in Honolulu...
on anotherbeautifulfallday
here inparadise.
We have enough information.
We are returning home.
Do you ever wonder if
this war's gonna catch up with us?
Not a whole lot.
Every moment we're not together,
you're up there training for it.
Yeah, well, I'm training
for moments like these.
'Cause I have no idea how I'm gonna
get this car out ofthe sand.
Evelyn, can you please
come out ofthe bathroom?
You've been there for an hour.
Evelyn!
What are you trying to do?
Look like me?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
What's the matter? No, you--
They call it the Vacant Sea.
None ofthe major sea lanes
go through it...
and you could bury the entire land mass
ofAsia there, and nobody would know.
From there,
they could attack anywhere.
Our last signals intercept indicate
that theJapanese task force...
is heading south, toward
the Philippines or Southeast Asia.
But Captain Thurman
of Naval lntelligence here...
has his own theory
about the missing ships.
Sir, I believe they'll try to hit us
where it'll hurt us the most--
Pearl Harbor.
That's over 4,000 nautical miles
fromJapan.
To Pearl, that's a long distance
to steam a navy, Captain.
Your theory--
It's based on what?
Well, it's what I would do.
It's not exactly hard evidence,
Captain Thurman.
Well, Admiral, if I had hard evidence,
we'd already be at war.
Sir, we can read their diplomatic
codes faster than they can type them.
But Captain Thurman's cryptology team is
still trying to crack the naval codes.
The intercepts have missing words
and garbled lines.
So to explain the decrypts...
we have to try to interpret
what we think they're trying to do.
Interpret? You mean, guess.
They use their
informed intuition, sir.
We guess. It's like
playing chess in the dark.
Any rumour, troop movement, ship
movement, spine tingle, goosebump...
we pay attention to it.
When I was in the Asiatic fleet,
the locals used to try to...
get outside ofa problem
to try to see the inside.
Well, I see a strike on Pearl.
It's the worst thing
that could happen.
A blow to Pearl would devastate the
Pacific Fleet's ability to make war.
So, sir, you would have us
mobilize the entire fleet...
at the cost
of millions ofdollars...
based on this spine-tingling
feeling ofyours?
No, sir. I understand myjob
is to gather and interpret material.
Making difficult decisions
based on incomplete information...
from my limited decoding ability
is yourjob, sir.
Then break the damn naval code, Captain,
so I can make a better decision.
Aye, sir. We are trying.
I wonder ifwe shouldn't put
the Pacific Fleet on full alert.
In case the optimism
ofthe HonoluluAdvertiser...
proves unfounded, gentlemen...
what are General Short and the army
going to do about protecting my ships?
Within a ten-mile radius
ofyour harbour...
we have fighter planes
here at Wheeler...
bombers at Hickam
and a training strip at Haleiwa.
We've recently established
a radar station here that
can detect planes 1 25 miles out.
Which is a month old, Admiral,
and untested.
I've seen these
new radar screens, Major.
There's no way oftelling
whether they're ours, theirs
or a flock ofdamn birds.
I'm intercepting a call from Tokyo
to somewhere close by Pearl.
There's a call from Tokyo.
They say they don't know you.
Hello?
It's a local dentist. He can see
Pearl Harbor from his office.
"Are there many sailors around?"
Uh, the dentist says that
the flat ships are not in port.
They're talking about the weather.
He doesn't seem to know
who he's talking to.
Hello?
That was a strange call.
Admiral, may I speak to you
in private?
Why would a spy use a phone?
They know we tap
all international lines.
Our listeners feel
it's probably not code talk.
It sounds like someone inJapan
is sneaking around...
asking a local citizen
the location ofour carriers.
Well, that makes me
feel all warm inside.
Get the FBI on it immediately.
Have we found
the goddamJapanese fleet yet?
No, Admiral, the bases
are looking all over the Pacific.
So the entire fleet could be
rounding Diamond Head right now.
We wouldn't know a thing about it.
Get on it.
I'm alive.
This is the first
I could get word out.
I told you I'd come back.
Here. Sit down.
Sit down. Come here.
It's okay.
It's all right.
- You're real.
- Yeah.
- I wished for this every day.
- I know. Me too.
Every second, so did l.
I thought you were dead. They--
They said you were shot down in the sea.
Yeah, I was.
I was in the ocean.
It was so cold.
I missed you.
I got picked up by a--
a French fishing boat, and l--
I was in Occupied France.
I couldn't get word out.
I'll tell you all about it.
I promise.
But I'm fine. I'm okay,
and I'm here now.
I just wanted to see you.
You're so beautiful.
I love you.
Hey, it's okay. It's okay.
Evelyn-- Evelyn, I'm back.
It's okay.
I won't leave you again. I promise.
Rafe, you died.
So did l.
I know, but I'm-- I'm--
It's fine now. I'm back.
We're together.
I mean, we are together, right?
I don't know where I am.
Rafe.
Rafe?
Stay away.
Rafe!
This isRadio Honolulu.
playing thesweetest music...
on thesweetest island
in the Pacific.
It'sa beautifuIDecember6
with beautifulmusic...
from the beautifulbeach
ofWaikiki.
- Rafe!
Oh! God damn it.
There you go.
A real live ace!
An ace is only five.
I shot down six M.E.'s.
- And I got two smokers too.
They don't count them.
- Oh, sorry.
Ofcourse, I got shot down myself
before they could pin me.
You got back from behind enemy lines,
huh? What was that combat like?
- Were you scared?
- Hey! One at a time.
Oh, fine.
Well, them Luftwaffe boys can
fly pretty good. It's not like,
you know, training. They're, uh--
- Danny.
- You know, they're all
about tactics is what it is.
You see, the Nazis, right?
They're faster than you are.
So they'll disappear,
and they get up in the soup.
They'll throw like
a roll or a hammerhead and
come around your high side, you know.
Shoot you from behind,
like some Americans will.
Hey, Gooz, you're
lookin' at a real live ace.
Well, let me give you
the shirt off my back.
- Aloha! There you go!
- I'll take it from you!
You all are having
a pretty good time out here.
Hey, Rafe,
we got to talk, all right?
Ain't got nothing
to talk about with you. Here.
Why don't you have a drink?
I'll make a toast.
To returnin' from the dead.
Wasn't all I expected,
but, well, that's life.
And to-- to my best friend
and loyal buddy Danny...
for keeping up the war effort
back here at home.
- Yeah.
- All right, here we go.
- That was good.
You know, where I come from,
somebody makes a toast to you...
and you don't drink,
that's sayin' somethin'.
All right, Rafe,
that's how it's gonna be.
- To you.
- Hey, you guys need to spend
some time alone, I think.
Oh, hell, no, Red. Come on.
What are you talking--
No, no, no. We're celebrating here.
Me over there fightin'.
Almost gettin' killed.
My friend Danny back here,
looking after my interests for me.
You all know Danny was
even good enough to look out for
my girl for me while I was gone.
We thought you were dead, Rafe,
and it gutted us both...
and we werejust trying
to get on with our lives.
Life is good, ain't it, Danny?
You know, you're a rotten drunk.
You always have been.
Yeah, well, you're a lousy friend.
That's a new development.
You left her to fight
somebody else's war.
And you made damn sure
that I didn't go with ya,
and we thought that you were dead!
I almost did die,
you little son ofa bitch.
Her face was the last thing
that went through my mind.
So don't stand there and tell me
to act like it's all right.
Yeah, Rafe, well, I stayed.
I stayed, and you made sure ofthat,
and some things changed.
- I hope you can get used to that.
- Oh, I have to get used to it.
- Yeah.
- All right.
We'll see how
I can get used to it.
- Get used to that, boy.
- Hey!
- And that's my left hand too.
- Hey, hey, hey!
Come on!
Melee at the Hula-la! Send MP's!
You called me a lousy friend?
Shit!
Come on!
- Let's go get 'em!
- Move out!
Oh, they're gonna throw us
in the brig. Let's go.
Oh, shit.
Rafe, you're
the only family I got.
When you were gone, it was
the loneliest I'd ever been.
The same for her too.
Oh, boy, now you're
really breaking my heart.
Ifyou hadn't gone,
none ofthis would have happened.
Oh, so it's my fault, I guess.
Damn it, Rafe.
I just know there's
got to be some way...
we can work
things out so that...
things can be right
between me and you.
I just don't see how
it could ever be the same.
Revered father...
I go now to fulfi I
my mission and my destiny.
I hope it is a destiny
that will bring honour to our family.
And if it requires my life...
I will sacrifice it gladly
to be a good servant ofour nation.
Hey, I got a large haze.
That's too big to be planes, right?
Is that what you want to do?
Knight to knight five?
Boom! Wrong move.
Lieutenant! Radar's picking up a large
return moving in from the northeast.
Hang on.
Relax. It's a flight of B-1 7's
coming in from the mainland.
Nothing to worry about.
Heck ofa lot of B-1 7's.
Good shot, Hot.
This better be good, Commander.
One ofour destroyers reports having
fired and sunk enemy submarine...
attempting to enter
Pearl Harbor at 0653.
- It's 7:20.
- We had decoder delays, Admiral.
Relay this to Washington.
Recall the staff.
"Failure--
Peace talks useless."
Thurman here. Tokyo transmitting
to their embassy in Washington.
"Discontinue use ofyour decoding
machine and dispose of immediately.
Special emphasis on destroying important
parts." Do you read that? Acknowledge.
Admiral, Naval lntel intercepted
a transmission from Tokyo...
to theJapanese embassy
in Washington...
instructing them to break apart
all decoder machines...
and burn all secret documents.
TheJapanese are expectin' a war.
Should we?
Warning of possibleJapanese
aggressive movement in any direction.
"Broken relationship.
Hostilities imminent." But where?
Did you ever
lose a fight, Miller?
I been lucky so far, Captain.
From what I hear, it ain't luck.
Ship's proud ofyou, son.
Come on.
Come on, come on, come on.
How do you like that?
Why the hell is the navy doing
practice this early on a Sunday?
- Heads up!
- Where's that coming from?
Get down!
Go! Go, go, go!
I'm with navy newsreel, and I can tell
you one thing! Them ain't navy planes!
-Allhands. manyourbattlestations!
-We're being bombed! We're being bombed!
Get up! Get up!
Allhands.
manyourbattlestations.
Jesus Christ!
- Manyourbattlestations!
Allhands. manyourbattlestations.
- Another dumb drill.
- Allhands. manyourbattlestations!
- What the heck was that?
- It's a bomb!
- Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Move! Move! Move! Move! Move!
Son ofa b--
Go! Go!
Get me the engine room!
My God.
Take cover!
Down! Down!
- Report battle stations!
Manned and ready!
- Man your battle stations.
Man your battle stations!
This isno shit!
Theyjustsunk the Arizona!
- Generalquarters! Generalquarters!
- Hustle! Hustle!
Allhands. manyourbattlestations!
This isno damn drill!
-Jap planes!
- Go! Go!
They look likeJaps.
I didn't even know
theJaps were sore at us.
Danny, you just get me
into a goddam aeroplane.
HolyJesus!
Oh, my God! This is good footage.
Did you see that?
Holy cow!
I hope there's still
an airfield left.
- Hurry up!
- What in the world?
Look. So many.
Everybody to the hospital!
Why is the navy always buzzin' us?
Shut up, Red!
- Hey, come on.
- Red, it's too early for this.
TheJaps are here!
- What the hell?
- Let's go! Let's go!
Get outta here!
Run! Run!
- It's theJaps!
- Take cover!
- Get down!
- Let's go! Hurry up!
- Generalquarters!
- Get corpsmen to the bridge.
- Aye, Captain.
Repair says third deck
is flooding port side.
Look out!
Get up! Get up, you cowards!
Get up there and fight! Move it!
- Incoming!
- Take cover!
Go, go, go!
Oh, my God!
- I got you, Captain.
- You radio for air cover!
Initiate damage control.
Find my XO!
Tell him to assume command!
- And you make sure the gunners--
- Everyone is where
they need to be, Captain.
You trained us well.
Captain?
Okay.
Get down now!
Oh, my God!
Go, go, go! Go!
Let's go! Let's go!
Everybody move! Let's move it!
Get to the guns!
Get the ammo for that 50 cal!
Get that 50 cal!
Let's get a fuel hook-up!
- Let's go! We're gotta get--
- Hey!
Come on, man!
We gotta get this thing loaded up!
Get to the planes!
Let's go! Let's go!
- Get the fuel.
- Help!
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on! Get down!
Down! Down!
Get to the planes!
Come on!
Get down!
Danny, get me into a damn plane.
Come on!
- Planes coming in!
- Get down!
Get some ammo up here!
We need to man these guns!
Sir! Captain says
you're in charge, sir!
We need more ammo! Now!
Send up ammunition
for the five-inch guns.
- Medic!
- All of'em! Now!
Send everything you got!
Come on!
Come on, you sum'bitch!
Oh, yeah!
I need a doctor!
Somebody help me!
Take a deep breath!
Come on! Breathe!
Get to the supply room!
Get everything out!
Planes incoming!
Cut 'em down!
Come on! Come on!
Get 'em away from the windows!
Get against the wall!
The mattresses!
Get 'em against the wall!
Take cover!
- Is everybody all right?
- Can you stand?
Come on! Help 'em out!
- Hold your fire!
- Get to the guns! Hurry up!
Get down, Danny!
- Earl!
- This is Walker.
We need to get those planes
fuelled and loaded right now!
- What's going on out there, huh?
- Danny, what the hell's that noise?
Youguys doing targetpractice
orsomething?
I think World War Il just hit us.
- Get down!
- Go, go, go!
- Billy!
- Run!
Bomb!
It's a dud.
- It's a bomb!
- It's a dud!
Get down!
- Danny! Danny, you all right?
- I'm all right!
Come on! Let's go! Come on! Let's go!
Gooz, come on, man!
We're sinking! We're sinking!
Stay together!
Close the hatches!
- I can't swim!
- You hang on!
Move it! Now!
Joe! Go! Go!
- Come on!
- We're gettin' out of here!
Get in the car!
Get in! Get in!
Let's go! Go! Go! Go!
Get out ofthe way!
- Where's this place we're goin'?
- We got a small mechanic runway
about 1 0 minutes away.
Hasn't been hit yet.
Zeros on our six!
Duck!
We're trapped.
Try-- Try the door!
Oh, my God! I'm gonna be under!
I'm gonna be under!
- It's sucking me back!
- The current's too strong!
Watch it!
They're still shootin' us!
I don't wanna die! I don't wanna die!
I don't wanna die!
- This is it.
- Help! There's no way out!
How bad?
It's still not over, sir.
An entire fleet at anchor.
My God. My God.
Barbara, fill every syringe
you can find with morphine!
Fill up the kitchen!
Fill up the ki--
Are you listening to me?
Fill up the kitchen!
Over there!
- Bad neck wound here!
We got a dire neck wound!
- Surgery!
Go! We've got to
get him to surgery!
Oh, God. In here.
Guy's still bleeding.
Give me another haemostat.
Hurry! Haemostat!
Give me a haemostat now!
Hurry!
Give me another haemostat.
Give me another suture.
- Oh, God! I'm so sorry!
- Hurry it up!
- Doctor!
- Here it is!
Am I gonna die?
Nurse!
- Don't leave me!
- Doctor, get over here!
My fingers
are plugging his artery.
Doctor, what do you need?
Doctor, focus. Look at me.
What do you need?
- H-H-H-Haemostat.
- Haemostat.
Here. All right.
Look at me.
It's gonna be all right.
I need more ammo!
I need more ammo, ladies!
- Earl! We good to go?
- Yeah, mostly, but--
- Get down! Get down!
- Shit! Take cover!
- Oh, jeez--
Oh, my God!
Earl, get in here!
Hey, Sergeant! They come back around,
we're gonna need more than a shotgun.
You got any other weapons and ammo
you can lay us some cover fire?
Yeah, inside that ammo locker!
Come on! Let's go! Move it!
Go! Go! Go!
Gimme a gun, goddam it!
You said the planes were
mostly ready "but." But what?
Well, she's down, she's broke,
she's shit. I got four left.
One's good to go,
two need ammo, one needs fuel.
Fall out.
Load up in the bunker.
- Let's go! Get down!
- Move!
- Come on!
- Get ready to roll.
- Get down! Down!
All right, Anthony, Red...
you two are gonna
stay here and man the 50-calibre.
Gooz, you get up to the next bunker
and you lay down some cover fire,
all right?
Planes!
Should we fire?
Stay down! Stay down!
No, goddam it, hold your fire!
- Stay still. Nobody fire.
- Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
- Hold your fire.
They don't know we're here.
- Stay down.
- We can fire.
- No, no, no, no, no, goddam it.
They don't know we're here.
Stay down. Stay still. Don't fire.
Oh, God.
I don't see any ordnance.
I think they're goin' home.
No, they'll be back. We still
got planes on the ground.
All right, you pilots, listen up.
Get all the airspeed you can
coming offthe runway.
Don't get on the stick
till you get to the very end.
When you get in the air,
stay low between the buildings.
You see any Zero on your tail,
try to wipe him off. Don't freeze.
All right?Just keep moving.
We're gonna try to break 'em up
and separate 'em.
- That way we can take 'em out
one by one.
- All right.
P-40s can't outrun Zeros,
so don't try.
We'rejust gonna
have to outfly 'em.
We got high-level bombers. They're
gonna bust this hangar wide open.
- Grab the 50s! Let's move!
- Okay!
- Let's go! Let's go!
- Move! Move! Move!
- Go, go, go!
- Let's go!
- Zeros!
Take cover! Take cover!
Go! Faster!
- Get down! Get down! Get down!
- Gooz, Danny, come on!
Get in there!
Danny!
Come on!
Come on, buddy!
Leave him! He's dead!
He's dead!
- All right, they're kickin' our butt.
Get to the aeroplanes! Let's go!
- Let's go!
- Come on. Go, go, go!
- Get up!
- Danny, let's run!
- Red, Anthony, let's go!
Hey! Come on! Help me!
Let's do it, Anthony!
Come on!
- Knock 'em dead.
- Here. Get in.
Here. Put these on.
They're coming around, boys!
Pick it up! Let's go, go, go, go, go!
Red, get outta here, goddam it!
I'm all right. Go! Go!
Come on, come on. Let's go.
-Joe, get out the way!
- I'm rollin'! I'm rollin'!
Clear, clear! Go!
Planes!
Help me, damn it!
Hey,Joe.Joe, you got three Zeros
right behind you! You got
three Zeros on your six!
Turn! Turn!
Oh, God!
- Oh, shit.
- What are you doing?
Get goin'! Get movin'!
Danny, start that thing up
and get in the air, now.
I'm not much good
without a wingman.
- Ineedyou.
- I got you.
Let's do it!
It's real tight, Rafe.
It's real tight.
Hey, Rafe, I'm not sure
we have enough runway!
Get your airspeed up
before you leave the dirt!
Don't freeze.
I don't think I'm gonna
make it up over this.
Get up! Get up!
We did it! I'm up!
We got Zeros behind us, Rafe!
How many you see back there?
We got five on our six!
Take it down
to the deck, Danny! Now!
We gotta split 'em up, Danny.
You take left,
I'll take right.
Earl, you better get some guns
in that goddam tower up there!
Okay, okay. Let's go!
Get to the truck! Let's go! Follow me!
Danny, I got three on my six!
Whoo!
Stop it! Stop it! Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go! Move it!
Move it, Red.
- Let's go. Move it!
- Gimme the 50!
Let's go! Let's go! Come on!
I still got two
behind me, Rafe.
Coming in! Take cover!
Son ofa bitch!
No!
Earl, do you hear me, goddam it?
Get some guns in that tower!
On the tower. Yeah.
Goin' ten storeys up.
It's a long son ofa bitch.
- Look! Look!
- Move it!
Rafe, they're all over me.
I can't get 'em off me!
Danny, I still got three on my tail.
- Keep jinkin' it.
Don't let 'em get a handle on you.
- I can't shake 'em, Rafe.
Damn it.
Danny, let's play some chicken
with theseJap suckers.
All right, I'm with you.
Jesus!
- I'm comin' right at you, Rafe.
- Don't break till I tell you. Hold on.
Not yet. Not yet!
Come on! Come on!
Go left, now!
- Whoo! We got 'em!
- Whoo! Ha-ha-ha!
Set up over there!
Come on. Load it.
Okay, we're at the top ofthe tower.
Earl, I got one on my tail.
I'm gonna bring him right by you.
He's comin' around! He's comin' around!
Let's get thisJap sucker!
Hold your fire. Hold your fire.
Here he comes.
You better be cocked
and locked when I come by there.
Hold your fire.
Fire!
Whoo!
Good shootin', boys!
Nicejob. Earl.
- Now, let's head over
to Battleship Row.
- I'm with you.
Let's go do some business.
I'm goin' after 'em.
Rafe, I got him!
- Oh, yeah!
- P-40s!
- Yeah!
They're pullin' out into the clouds,
Danny. We ain't gonna let
these sons of bitches get home.
How do you like it
when someone's shootin' back at you?
Oh, I'm on your ass now.
Danny, I got one!
Come on.
Ah! Come on!
Come on. Stay in there.
Stay in there!
Whoa!
I got you, son ofa bitch!
Who taught you
how to fly, Lieutenant?
He did.
All right, Bobby, don't kick.
I know it's hard, but--
- I have to amputate here!
I have to amputate!
- You're not gonna die!
I got you.
Can you hold on to this--
Sandra, we're running out
of morphine, so you gotta--
you gotta mark 'em,
you gotta find some way to mark 'em...
so we can keep track ofwho's got--
got the morphine already.
Tell me about your ship.
What ship are you from?
- It's not marking. It's not ma--
Ev, you got a marker?
- Uh, uh, no.
Use my lipstick.
Put M for morphine.
- Evelyn, we need a tourniquet!
- Tourniquet?
Where are the clamps?
Hurry.
There's nothing left.
- Evelyn.
- Here. Use this.
- I need you to go outside.
There's too many to help.
Okay? You gotta sort 'em out.
Only those that can be saved,
you bring in here. You got that?
- I can't.
- No, please, do it!
I need you to do it. Go! Go!
- Don't let in anyone without a mark.
- Stay back!
- I told you, stand back!
- Stay outside. Keep 'em outside.
Come on! Let's go!
Take this guy up!
- Wait here.
- Don't touch me, youJap!
Get your hands off me!
- He's critical. Get him into Critical!
- Keep him off me. Keep him off me!
Critical, front ward!
How bad am l?
- You're gonna bejust fine, sweetheart.
- I don't wanna die!
- You're gonna bejust fine.
You're not gonna die, sweetheart.
I got your hand.
Give him enough morphine
to make him comfortable.
He's not gonna make it.
Line the critical up in the ward.
Get him morphine. Take him over there.
- Take the burn victims by the trees.
- I just found her.
- I-l-l don't--
I don't think she's breathing.
- No, she's dead. Take her.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, God!
Oh, are you sure, Ev?
Could you check her one more time
to be sure?
She's dead, Sandra, she's dead.
Take her over there.
- You've got to be sure before you--
- She's dead. Get back to work.
- Oh, my God!
Go back to work, Sandra.
I don't know what to do.
- Over here!
- Admiral?
From Washington.
"Attack byJapan considered imminent."
They're only an hour late.
- How can we help?
- We need blood. Come on.
Remember, son,
hold on to your faith.
- 1 ,500 cartons over there.
- Remember whatJesus said:
"Today you will be with me
in paradise." So fear not.
Fear not, my son.
You are a man truly blessed.
Truly blessed.
You will die
in a state of grace.
Remember, pain is temporary,
but glory is forever.
Hold on to your faith, my son.
You will be with God and all
the saints, all the angels very soon.
I absolve you ofyour sins
in the name ofthe Father...
and ofthe Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Go with God, my son.
We've got men trapped
everywhere in the harbour.
We need help
from anybody who can move.
Don't lose us!
Keep swimming!
- Get us outta here!
- Help!
There's somebody in here!
Get somebody down here!
- They're cuttin' through!
- Yeah!
Get us outta here!
I hear somebody!
Let's get some guys over here!
Pull!
- Get us outta here!
- The room's filling up with water!
Get an air line in here!
- Help us! Hurry!
- The air hose!
What can we do?
It won't cut any faster!
Cut 'em out!
Yesterday...
December 7, 1 941 ...
a date which will live
in infamy...
the United States ofAmerica was
suddenly and deliberately attacked...
bynavalandairforces...
ofthe Empire ofJapan.
It is obvious
thatplanning the attack...
began many weeks ago.
During the intervening time...
theJapanesegovernment
hasdeliberatelysought...
to deceive the United States...
by false statements
and expressions of hope...
forcontinuedpeace.
The attackyesterday
on the Hawaiian lslands...
has causedsevere damage
toAmerican militaryforces.
Iregret to tellyou
that over3.000American lives...
have been lost.
No matter how long
it may take us...
to overcome
this premeditated invasion...
theAmericanpeople
in theirrighteousmight...
will win through...
to absolute victory.
Because ofthis...
unprovoked. dastardlyattack
byJapan...
I ask that the Congress
declare a state ofwar.
Is it true...
men are still trapped alive
inside the Arizona?
We can hear tapping
from inside the hull.
We're doing everything
we can to get to them,
but they're 40 feet below water.
We've been trained to think
that we're invincible...
and now our proudest ships
have been destroyed...
by an enemy
we considered inferior.
We're on the ropes, gentlemen.
That's exactly why
we have to strike back now.
We're preparing an attack against
the Marshall and Gilbert lslands, sir,
to keep our--
I'm talking about hitting the heart
ofJapan the way they have hit us.
Mr President,
Pearl Harbor caught us unawares...
because we didn't face facts.
This isn't a time
for ignoring them again.
The Army Air Corps has long-range
bombers but no place to launch them.
Midway is too far,
and Russia...
won't allow us
to launch a raid from there.
- Admiral?
- The navy's planes are small.
They carry light loads
and have a short range.
We'd have to get them within
a few hundred miles ofJapan...
and therefore risk our carriers,
and ifwe lose our carriers...
we'll have no shield
against invasion.
Does anyone in this room...
think that victory is possible
without facing danger?
We are at war.
Ofcourse there's a risk.
But consider the risk,
Mr President.
IftheJapanese
invade us right now...
they would penetrate as far
as Chicago before we could stop them.
Gentlemen...
most ofyou did not know me
when I had the use of my legs.
I was strong and proud
and arrogant.
Now I wonder
every hour of my life...
why God put me
into this chair.
But when I see defeat
in the eyes of my countrymen...
in your eyes right now, I start to think
that maybe he brought me down...
for times like these when we all need
to be reminded who we truly are--
that we will not give up
or give in.
Mr President,
with all respect, sir.
What you're asking can't be done.
- Mr President--
- Mr President!
- Get back, George. Get back.
Do not tell me...
it can't be done.
Japan continues itsmilitaryconquest
throughout the Pacific.
But. backhome.
millions ofAmerican workers...
bandtogether. bringing factories
to life to avenge PearIHarbor.
Mr President, I think we have an idea
about how to bomb theJapanese.
Sir, it's risky, but it's bold.
- Who are you?
- I, sir?
Captain Low, Mr President.
He's a submariner.
He came up with this idea, sir.
I like sub commanders.
They don't have time for bullshit,
and neither do l.
Fire away, gentlemen.
And where is God in all this?
Our enemies believe
that a divine wind protects them.
But we see our friends
laid out here before us--
Hey, Cap'n.
- Lieutenants Rafe McCawley,
Daniel Walker?
- Major.
You're both going stateside.
Fly out in two hours.
What for, sir?
Ask Colonel Doolittle.
Yes, sir.
Over there.
Packing.
Orders.
What kind oforders?
The top secret kind.
Dangerous kind.
I, uh, can't find Danny.
That why you're here?
Looking for Danny?
He's probably
saying goodbye to his squadron.
We've been assigned to Doolittle.
I wasn't looking for Danny.
I couldn't have you go away
without you understanding something.
Yeah, well, you don't have
to explain anything to me.
I do, because you're acting
like I didn't love you.
Evelyn, loving you
kept me alive.
I should've died over there.
When I was in that water,
I made a deal with God.
I told Him I was sorry.
I told Him I knew I'd been
a fool for leaving you...
trying to go over there
and be a hero...
and I promised I'd never
ask for anything again...
if I could just see you
one more time.
You know what?
It was worth it.
You kept me alive, Evelyn.
You brought me home.
So I'm gonna stand by
my end ofthe deal.
I'm gonna walk away,
and I won't askyou for anything.
But I just wanna know why.
Just tell me that, will you, please?
Just tell me why.
Rafe, I'm pregnant.
Oh, my God.
I didn't even know until the day
you turned up alive.
And then all this happened.
I haven't told Danny.
I don't want him to know.
All he needs to think about is how
to do this mission and get back alive.
Rafe, all I ever wanted
was for us to have a home...
and grow old together, but life
never asked me what I wanted.
Now I'm gonna give Danny
my whole heart...
but I don't think I'll ever look at
another sunset without thinking ofyou.
I'll love you my whole life.
I'll see you on board.
You know, the only thing
that scares me...
is that you might love him
more than you love me.
I love you, Danny...
and I'll be here
waiting foryou when you come back.
Follow me.
Colonel.
- Congratulations
on your promotion, sir.
- I heard what you did.
We can explain that, sir.
Explain what?
Whatever it is
you heard about us, sir.
You mean the hula shirts
you were flying in?
Or the seven planes
you shot down?
You're both being awarded
the Silver Star...
and promoted to captain.
Is that the good news, sir, or--
You'rejust about the only pilots
in the army with combat experience.
I need you for a mission
I've been ordered to put together.
- You know what top secret is?
- Yes, sir.
It's the kind of mission
where you get medals.
But they send them
to your relatives.
Top secret means
you train for something...
never done before
in aviation history...
and you go without knowing
where you're going.
You do it on that basis
or not at all.
I'll go, sir.
I'll go too, sir.
By the way, McCawley,
the Brits sent this over.
- It's your personal effects.
- Thankyou, sir.
There's only one more thing
I can tell you.
Leave your goddam hula shirts
at home.
Dear Rafe, it's so strange
to be this far from you...
but you should know this:
every night--
I've been looking
all over foryou.
Danny, this-- this--
this ain't no time
to leave things unsaid.
We gotta face facts here.
The fact is, wejust both
love the same woman.
You know, she's the first girl
I ever felt this way about, Rafe.
I couldn't help what happened
any more than you could.
This is different, though, Danny.
Evelyn already lost the man she loved
once. I just don't want to see
that happen to her again.
Guys like us got no choice.
This is war.
She knows that.
Danny, don't do this.
Don't go on this mission.
You got nothing to prove.
You've been trying to protect me
since we were kids.
Yeah, well, you do tend
to need it from time to time.
The mission I'm asking you to volunteer
for is exceptionally dangerous.
Take a look
at the man beside you.
It's a good bet
that in the next six weeks...
you or he...
will be dead.
Everyone brave enough
to accept this...
step forward.
Your grandmother could take a B-25 off
on a mile-long runway.
Well, I'm gonna train you
to do it in 467 feet.
Because at 468 feet...
you're dead.
And once you get it up, you're gonna
learn to fly it like a fighter...
thirty feet offthe ground.
I want you to say hello to Lieutenant
Jack Richards, Navy Aviation.
He's gonna help us lighten
these fat ladies here.
Dump that ashcan.
See that bombsight? Get rid of it.
- Colonel, he's crazy.
- The lady's fat!
- Listen to him.
She's a fat lady.
We want a skinny lady.
Max power!
Get up! Get up! Get up!
- Damn!
- How in the heckyou--
Theyjust keep rolling
past that line.
- Maybe this mission's a bad idea.
- No, they're too heavy. We got
to get drastic with these planes.
This armoured plating's
got to go.
- I'm sure. I'm sure.
Now, lose it like a skirt, son.
- Release brakes!
Come on! Come on!
- God!
- Put every man on the line now!
Let's show these boys
how this thing is done!
Come on! Max power!
Well, if he can do it--
Well, gentlemen, now I can tell you
that we're going to Tokyo.
And we're gonna bomb it.
That comes as a special request
directly from President Roosevelt.
The navy's gonna sneak us about
400 miles offtheJapanese coast,
and we'll launch from the carrier there.
Has that ever even been done before?
Taking army bombers offa navy carrier?
No.
Okay.
- Any other questions?
- Well, sir...
is it even possible to land a B-25
on an aircraft carrier deck?
That won't matter.
As soon as we're airborne, the carrier
will head straight back for Hawaii.
But ifthe carriers head home,
where do we land?
I have a phrase
I want you to memorize.
It means "I am an American."
In Chinese.
Ain't gonna be any easier. That's three
feet shorter than our practice runway.
- Fellas?
- Sir.
Sir.
- Secretary ofthe navy gave me these.
- What are they?
Friendship medals theJapanese gave us
when they were pretending
they wanted peace.
- What do they want you
to do with them, sir?
- We're gonna wire them
to the bombs and give them back.
- So what's going on?
- Well, sir, we only have 1 6 planes.
So?
When theJaps hit us,
they had more than 300.
I mean, how much difference
we really gonna make?
It's not that we're afraid, sir.
It'sjust that we might die doing this,
and we wanna know what it's for.
You know, at Pearl,
they hit us with a sledgehammer.
This raid,
even ifwe make it through...
it'll only be a pinprick.
But it'll be straight
through their hearts.
Victory belongs to those
that believe in it the most
and believe in it the longest.
We're gonna believe. We're gonna
make America believe too.
Colonel! I need a minute.
- Excuse me, MajorJackson.
- Yes.
- Do you remember me?
Oh, sure I do. I'm sorry.
I've been meaning to thankyou.
Maybe you can.
When the news starts coming in about
those boys in the Doolittle outfit...
- I wanna be in the command post.
- I'm sorry.
I-l don't know
what you're talking about.
How in the hell do you know
about this mission, Lieutenant?
Let's call it
an inadvertent disclosure.
You mean some fly boy
you're dating shot his mouth off.
Actually, It's about two pilots.
I know they're going
into great danger.
I just wanna be there
when the news comes in
to tell us ifthey've lived or died.
Most officers would have
thrown you in the brig.
Most nurses would have gone on
to someone else instead of keeping
their fingers plugged in your artery.
I can't promise you anything.
One, two, three, one!
One, two, three, two!
One, two, three--
Hey, Red, you think theyjust picked us
to do this 'cause we're young and dumb?
Come on, Gooz.
We're the tip ofthe sword.
All right,
in honour ofour trip toJapan,
I got us some, uh, victory cigars!
Yeah, victory cigars!
There you go.
Put that in your inside pocket
next to your heart.
You know,Jack, we may lose this battle,
but we're gonna win this war.
- You know how I know?
- No.
Them.
Because they're rare.
And in times like these,
you see them...
stepping forward.
There's nothing stronger
than the heart ofa volunteer,Jack.
My friends in the War Department
don't want me to lead this raid...
because they say I'm too valuable.
They don't want me up in the air
flying with the men that I've chosen...
that I've chewed out, cussed out,
pushed to the limit...
and that I've come to respect.
They want me to stand
in the flight deck and wave you off.
Well, I don't see it that way.
So I'm going with you.
We take offtomorrow afternoon,
drop our fire and head for China.
Our mission is to hit military targets,
aircraft and tank factories.
Colonel...
you've given us the homing beacons,
but you've also told us that China
is overrun withJapanese troops.
What do we do
ifthe beacons are switched off?
You bring her down any way you can
and do your best to avoid capture.
What do we do ifour planes are damaged
and we have to bail out overJapan?
Well, in that situation,
I can't tell you what you should do.
What would you do, Colonel?
I wasn't built to be a prisoner.
So I would have my crew bail out.
I'd find the sweetest
military target I could...
and drive my plane
right smack into the middle of it.
But that'sjust me.
I'm 45 years old.
I'm an old man.
You guys have
your whole lives ahead ofyou.
So what you do is up to you.
The mission will launch
in a couple of hours.
You'll stay right in here.
Here. Stay here. Don't talk to them.
They won't talk to you.
Pretend to type whatever information
we pass you. That's it.
This is OrphanAnnie
from Radio Tokyo...
to allthe lonelyboys
in theSouth Pacific.
- Watch out. The enemy willgetyou.
- Maybe she's right.
Japs transmitting!
Captain, Radar reportsJapanese
patrol boats range of400 yards.
- How many yards?
- 400 yards and closing, sir.
Richards!Japs! 400 yards.
Let's go!
Admiral Halsey's ordering
the cruisers to open fire!
We gotta sink theseJap boats
before they give away our position.
Go to general quarters!
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
Oh, my God.
This can't be good.
Allhands.
manyourbattlestations!
Japs one mile away!
They've reported our position!
We're supposed to launch 400 miles away.
How far are we now?
624 miles.
-Jesus!
- What do you wanna do?
624 miles--
I don't know. Colonel...
I don't know ifthe planes can carry
enough fuel to make it to China.
Now. We launch now!
Army pilots, man your planes!
Manyourplanes!
They're shooting at something.
Colonel,
we're too far out to make it.
These planes need more fuel,
but ifthey're too heavy,
they might not get offthe deck.
Listen. I want you to strip
everything out ofthis plane
you don't need, and I mean now.
Start preflight. Let's go!
Add ten more cans offuel
for each plane.
Every plane!
- Let's go! Let's go! Move!
- Come on, you guys. Get up there!
Lose those suitcases now!
- What's your favourite gun?
- What?
You wanna get offthis deck,
you give me one ofthose guns now.
It's still too heavy.
Yo. I want you to go to the kitchen,
get some broomsticks. Cut 'em down,
paint 'em black and bring 'em here.
- You're gonna put a broomstick
where this gun was.
- A broomstick.
Your plane's gonna be fine.
You tell your crew to take a piss
before they take off, or they're
not gonna clear the deck.
- We've got broomsticks for tail guns.
- Yeah, maybe it'll scare 'em.
- You take care ofyourself up there.
- Yeah. I will.
Danny, be careful.
You hear me?
- I will. I'll see you, Rafe.
- Rafe, we're the tip ofthe sword.
- Turning on one!
- Turning on two!
All right.
You ready for this?
- Superchargers low and latched.
- Superchargers are low and latched.
We're full into the wind.
More speed! More speed!
- Are you nervous?
- No-- Yes, sir. Yes.
- When did you find religion?
- When you assigned me
to this mission, sir.
- I want you to do me a favour.
- What's that, Colonel?
- Pray for both of us.
- It's gotta be right!
Let's go!
Max power!
Up, please!
Come on! Come on!
- Yeah!
- Way to go!
Jesus, that was short.
- Move 'em up!
- All right, full power!
Full power! Here we go!
Come on!
Come on! Here we go!
Here we go!
We made it!
From Berlin, Rome and Tokyo,
we have been described...
as a nation
ofweaklings and playboys...
who hire British orRussian
orChinesesoldiers...
to do ourfighting forus.
Let them repeat that now.
Let them tell that
to General MacArthur and his men.
Let them tellthat
to thesoldiers who today...
are fightinghard
in the far waters ofthe Pacific.
Let them tell that
to the boys in the Flying Fortresses.
to the marines.
That'sJapan right there, fellas.
Tighten up back there. Man your guns!
We're in the enemy's backyard.
All right,
look alive back there. I see coastline.
Heads up, boys! Heads up!
- Man your guns back there.
- I'm cocked and locked!
Get ready, you suckers.
Approaching targets for bombing raid.
Open bomb bay doors.
Ripley, you got
our target in sight?
37 degrees. Target in sight.
All right, boys,
let's knock their clocks off!
- Drop your ordnance.
- Bombs away.
One away!
- Bombs away!
Two away!
Three away! Four away!
- We caught 'em bysurprise.
- Dropping ordnance.
Bombsaway!Bombsaway!
Factories.Just factories.
- We got it!
We hit our targets.
Good job, Raiders.
We got flak everywhere.
- Go down there and get Gooz!
- I want everyone to separate!
- Clean that up.
- Yes, sir.
- Try and clean that up.
- They're shooting flakat us!
We gotta try
and get out ofthis shit, Gooz.
We got a fire!
It's an electric fi--
We got a fire back here!
I'm gonna short this out!
Get into the clouds. Danny.
right now! Get up--
Goddam it!
Red, go check it out.
- I'm getting peppered up here!
-Just hope they don't hit a prop.
- I'm hit!
- They're gonna tear this plane apart.
We gotta take it up. 800 feet.
I think Theo's dead!
Theo, wake up! Theo!
Get into the clouds, Danny,
right now. Get up in that soup!
All right, we're gonna pull out
ofthis, Gooz. Come on.
Thankyou, George.
What is it, General?
Colonel Doolittle had
to advance his execution order
by 1 2 hours, Mr President.
There'll be no homing beacons.
The plane carrying them
crashed en route to China.
And our bombers may lack the fuel
to reach the mainland anyway, sir.
So our boys are flying blind
on empty tanks.
God help them.
Still not getting a signal.
All ocean, no land.
Homing into nothing.
How many cans offuel
we got left?
These are all empty!
- Is this all you got?
- That's all we got, Red.
Rafe, you better pray for land.
Break radio silence.
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
You're all brave souls...
among the bravest I've everhad
theprivilege offlying with.
But we're on our own.
This really was
a suicide mission.
- Engine one's fluctuating.
- We're gonna lose it any minute.
- Rafe, you gotta prime it.
- I'm priming it. How about now?
I see the coastline.
I see the coast!
Copy that, Rafe.
- We're gonna make it.
- Yeah.
Danny, follow me now.
We can make this.
I can see the coast right now.
It's only a few miles out. Follow me.
We're following you, Rafe.
We gotta find a soft landing spot.
I'm pushing up on two.
Fellas, it's gonna be
a hard landing. Hold on.
I see rice paddies right there.
We'll bring it in right here.
Oh, God. Engine one's dead.
We're gonna lose
engine two any second.
We can make it in.
Easy. Pull it back.
We'll glide in,
go in on fumes.
Japs! We gotJap patrols
all over the place!
There'sJaps everywhere!
Danny. Iandsomewhere else!
Strap yourself in, boys!
We're coming in hard!
- We're a dead stick.
- Get out ofthe nose!
Hold on, boys!
We're going down!
Watch the trees!
Oh, God!
Everyone all right?
I'm okay. I'm okay.
Where's Ripley?
He's dead.
Watch forJaps.
Jap patrols! Take cover!
- Who's got extra magazines?
- I got 'em.
We got to get up into those hills
and find the Chinese.
They got us pinned down!
- Danny!
- Rafe!
- Rafe, no! Rafe!
- Danny!
You don't have a chance!
Rafe!
Oh, God. Dan-- Danny!
Come on!
- Gooz? You okay, man?
- Danny!
Oh, shit. Anthony.
Gooz!
- Can you hear me? Come on.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Danny. Easy, easy, easy.
- I've had better landings.
- You saved us back there.
- I got something in my neck.
- Let me try to pull this out foryou.
- Where's Gooz?
He's fine.
He's right over there.
Rafe!
Grenade!
Danny.
Danny!
Danny. Oh!
- Hold on.Just hold on one second.
- Rafe.
Hold on now. I got you.
You're all right.
You're all right. There you go.
I'm not--
I'm not gonna make it.
Oh, yes, you are.
Yes, you are. Danny, look at me.
Rafe.
I'm so cold. I'm so cold.
You're all right. Hey.
Hey, Rafe?
- Can you do me a favour?
- What?
Can you have someone else
write my name on the tombstone?
You're not gonna die. Look at me.
Listen to me. You ain't gonna die.
You hear me? Danny.
Danny, you can't die.
You can't die.
You know why? 'Cause
you're gonna be a father, Danny.
You're gonna be a daddy.
I was-- I wasn't supposed to tell you.
You're gonna be a father.
Please.
No, you are.
Danny.
Danny?
Please. Please. Please.
God.
Please, Danny.
Hold your fire. They're Chinese.
When the action is over
and we look back...
we understand both more and less.
This much is certain.
Before the Doolittle raid,
America knew nothing but defeat.
After it,
there was hope ofvictory.
Japan realized, for the first time, that
they could lose and began to pull back.
America realized that she would win
and surged forward.
It was a war that changed
America and the world.
Dorie Miller was the first black
American to be awarded the Navy Cross.
But he would not be the last.
Hejoined a brotherhood of heroes.
That's for all the Raiders.
World War ll, for us,
began at Pearl Harbor...
and 1 ,1 77 men still lie entombed
in the battleship Arizona.
America suffered,
but America grew stronger.
It was not inevitable.
The times tried our souls...
and through the trial,
we overcame.
Hey, Danny.
How'd you like to go flying?
Come here.
When lthinkback on these times
Andthe dreams we left behind
I'llbeglad
'cause I wasblessedtoget
To haveyou in my life
When llookback on these days
I'Illookandseeyourface
You were right there forme
In my dreams. I'llalwaysseeyou
Soarabove thesky
In myheart. there willalways
be aplace foryou
Forallmy life
I'llkeep apart ofyou with me
Andeverywhere lam
Thereyou'llbe
Well. youshowedme howit feels
To feelthesky within my reach
Andlalways willremember
Allthestrengthyougave to me
Yourlove made me make it through
Oh. Ioweso much toyou
You were right there forme
In my dreams. I'llalwaysseeyou
Soarabove thesky
In myheart. there willalwaysbe
A place foryou
Forallmy life
I'llkeep apart ofyou with me
Andeverywhere lam
Thereyou'llbe
'Cause lalways sawinyou my light
Mystrength
Andl wanna thankyou now
forallthe ways
- You were right there forme
You were right there forme
Foralways
In my dreams. I'llalwaysseeyou
Soarabove thesky
In myheart. there willalwaysbe
A place foryou forallmy life
I'llkeep apart ofyou with me
Andeverywhere lam
Thereyou'llbe
www.moviesubtitles.org