AVICI
CONTINUOUS HELL
UNINTERRUPTED TIME
UNLIMITED SPACE
BOUNDLESS SUFFERING
FOR THE FALLEN SOULS
UNINTERRUPTED TIME
TIME
I still remember my first arrest.
It was December 12, 1980.
My partner and I were walking the beat
on Hanoi Road.
Got the call that shit was going down
at New World Centre.
We rushed over.
It was a big knife fight
between two gangs.
Around 15 or so were already down.
Lots of blood on the ground.
I saw a severed hand,
still holding a knife.
My partner told me to draw my gun.
I was a rookie, so I did what he told me.
But before I could open the holster,
my partner was already down.
This kid stabbed him in his belly
with a pipe.
Blood gushed out of the sawed-off opening.
I didn't know what to think.
I simply emptied all six of my bullets
straight into that kid.
I don't remember how many years he got.
But when I saw him again two years ago,
he was boozing at the Regal,
looking sharp.
His drinking buddies
were all Kwun's goons.
Those who kill get golden belts,
while those who fix roads
perish with mangled corpses.
I can barely recall my partner's face now.
But, I really regret...
not putting those six bullets
into that kid's skull.
The world shouldn't be like this.
That's not the way it should be, Sam.
How long have you been around
Tsim Sha Tsui?
Almost two years now.
Do you know why I haven't messed with you?
'Cause I am handsome?
Maybe.
‘Cause I think you're a decent guy.
My life will be much easier
if you're in charge in Tsim Sha Tsui.
Forget about it.
You couldn't waste the kid
even with six bullets.
That makes you a decent guy too, right?
You didn't hear this from me,
but I'd rather not be one.
Kwun gave me everything, even my life.
If I killed him for you,
I'd be despicable
even in your eyes, right?
-I knew you'd say that!
-But it's true!
It takes more than chivalry
to work for the Ngai family.
My master often says to me,
"Retribution always takes its sweet time."
No can do. Guess we won't be
sharing meals for a while.
Time to work!
This early? What's the rush?
My boys've got to eat too!
Take the whole box.
That's okay. It's all yours.
Don't worry about it. Just go.
I'm going!
Hey.
Wanna use the back door?
Ain't no rules against
schmoozing with cops.
The front door's fine! Got used to it.
Prat Avenue!
Prat Avenue, please.
Is Uncle Kwun in?
Uncle Kwun! Someone's looking for you!
Bye, Mary.
They say this antique American amp's got
sweet high, crisp middle and deep bass.
I say it's bullshit!
180 grand! Who can afford it in Hong Kong?
Sit.
Around 10,000 people, maybe.
Sam asked you to be a mole in the force.
If you don't like it, I can talk to him.
After all, you're my boy.
It's fine.
Sure?
Positive.
Hand me that bag.
Mary.
You haven't talked much lately.
I thought you'd been dreading it.
Hide in Tuen Mun till things quiet down.
Stay fit for the Academy's new term.
The money I gave you, spend it wisely.
You like the song?
Yeah.
It's yours.
It won't sound as good
on another player though.
I'll pick out a good one for you
after you've earned a little money.
What? Don't like it?
Not at all.
Sam gave you this watch, didn't he?
None of your business.
Only you and I...
know about tonight.
I don't want Sam to know.
Why's that?
Women are simple.
I'd do anything as long as
a man treats me well.
Now go home. I'm very busy tonight.
I mean, that's the rules of the game.
It's either you or me.
Boss said I would see blood today.
The Mainlanders looked up to me.
They kept asking,
"Got a Mercedes today, Brother Keung?"
I said, "Of course." And here I am.
Otherwise, I wouldn't be here with you.
I would be hugging girls
at China City Club.
That's for sure!
Hey, got a smoke?
I don't smoke.
Let's forget about it. My car's fine.
See? She says it's all good.
I mean look at her, dressed all dandy.
Does she look like someone
who wants any trouble?
Look at me. All beaten up by you.
Who do you think the judge would believe?
Also, I bet you guys never hang out
at Tsim Sha Tsui East, huh?
Know who I am? I'm Keung.
Sam's top dog. Del Piero's boy.
I'll kick your ass every time I see you,
and you can count on that.
Hey, you.
How about calling an ambulance, sir?
Look at all the blood!
Have them bring 500 cc, Type O. It's rare.
Shut up!
Save it till we're back at the station.
Take him.
Why do I have to go to the station?
I only stole a piece of junk, sir!
What have I done to deserve the OCTB?
-Just shut up!
-Does that deserve an OCTB beating?
Don't you know you're just a cadet?
And you thought you were going to be
at the top of your class?
Don't ever let Yip know about this.
Happy birthday, Chief Yip!
What's there to be happy about?
Ten years in the Academy. A rustic hell.
Well, you even managed to get me out.
Your case is now ancient history.
Think of a way to get yourself out too.
So what if the commissioner
is Chinese now?
Still six more years
till all the Brits are out of here.
I'll be 48 by then.
Might as well train a few good cops
from there.
The world is yours after 1997.
27149! Cheers!
Yan.
It's been beeping all day.
How come you don't call back? Girlfriend?
-Cheers, sir!
-Cheers!
Just leave me alone!
It's none of my business.
I don't want to know a thing.
Go! Leave me alone!
Law!
What's all this?
My father just passed away.
It was his wish to inform his children
when something bad happened to him.
Sorry to have bothered you.
Stop watching TV, Negro! Eat first!
I wanna see what the news have
on Kwun's death.
Did you do it, Ching?
I've got a big mouth. Had I done it,
you would've heard about it.
Ask Wah and Gandhi.
I was in Macau when Kwun died.
Everybody knows!
But I bet his kids think I did it.
I ain't scared of nothing.
The eldest son's a doctor,
the youngest a brat.
The daughter's been married for ages.
Only the middle son's running the show.
I'll make sure they pay
if they go too far!
It's our fault for failing to protect
Uncle Kwun.
Uncle John! That's enough.
Dad used to say,
"What goes around comes around."
It came later than expected already.
Wah, Ching, Negro and Gandhi.
Guess what those four are thinking?
Thank you. Thank you very much.
How's Mom doing, Sis?
She's fine. Been sleeping.
She wants us to bring some cigs
to the morgue for Dad.
I'll go get them.
B Team, watch Tak Shing Street.
C Team, watch the Austin Road exit
of that financial building.
It has two exits:
one on Tak Shing Street, one on Austin...
Hello?
Why didn't you call me that Kwun was dead?
I called everybody the minute it happened.
Kwun's boys can't sit still. Shit will
hit the fan in Tsim Sha Tsui tonight.
It's the 14th already, you know?
Today's the 14th.
Time to pay the Ngai Family.
Well, since I'm the junior here,
I'll be the jackass.
I'm not paying the Ngais anymore.
What do you three think?
Inspector Wong! What's up?
What are your men doing
outside Wah's building?
-Not a good day for chitchat.
-Are you up to something?
Fine, fine. Next time.
Wow! What's the occasion?
Come on. Where's my seat?
We're cool if you're
only here for the food.
All other business will have to wait.
The food! It's all about the food!
Some big shit is going down tonight.
Let the Big Four do their thing.
We'll clean up the mess.
Can't let them start fighting,
or you'll see bodies.
So what? You're not satisfied?
You know the rule. Pick a card.
Okay. Higher card wins.
Come on!
I told him there's nothing left
to talk about! What does he want now?
What's up, Hau?
Wah.
Nothing much. Heard you're planning
a casino in Macau.
I've got their officials on my payroll.
How about a joint venture?
Uncle Kwun's dead. I'm not in the mood.
I see.
Your Macau trip wasn't all business.
I know you had fun with Gandhi's wife.
Sorry, but I can't let go of my casino
in Macau.
Gotta go.
What are Sam's people doing?
I know Wah paid up!
Don't change the subject.
Tell me something I don't know.
Call me when you get your shit straight!
Hau took care of Wah
in less than ten minutes.
The Big Four are having a tough time.
My mole said Hau took out
a million's worth of coke.
What's this?
A Mafia roadblock?
I don't know why Wah paid up, Mr. Ngai.
But I ain't gonna negotiate.
I don't plan to negotiate with you either.
Pass the phone to Negro.
Hey, Negro.
Don't know why he calls you from my turf.
What's up, Hau?
I'm with Gandhi all the way.
If he's not paying, then neither will I.
Heard you and Gandhi have been tight.
The heroin you two smuggled got robbed.
You both lost several million each, right?
Luckily,
I found the stuff in your warehouse.
Want me to hand it back to Gandhi now?
What's he talking about?
Among the Tsim Sha Tsui Big Fives,
Wah and Negro paid up.
Counting Sam, that's 3 to 2.
I'm the youngest here. Gotta pay!
See ya!
Don't think too much. Cheers!
Pay my share for me.
Mr. Ngai went to eat, Inspector Wong.
A bit late for chow, Mr. Ngai.
My dad always came here after work.
I have to keep up the ritual.
Want to join us?
It's your seat from now on. Must be tough.
Not at all.
You guys worked all night for nothing.
Now, that's tough.
You've really done well tonight, Hau.
Hope you can keep it up.
Don't let it turn into a tragedy.
Let's go.
What did you say?
We want to celebrate!
Kwun's dead! Time to pop the champagne!
Want me to pop one for you?
What?
Want to mess with cops?
Hey, officers!
The Ngais are in mourning.
What more do you want?
Let's go. Go!
Sam.
Thanks.
Dad used to operate street gambling here.
Started out as...
a nickel-and-dime business.
Now everyone knows him in Tsim Sha Tsui.
He often said...
"What goes around comes around."
And now he's...
I'll always remember this day.
Hi honey. It's all good now.
Want some snacks?
Glad to hear it. Just come home.
27149. An officer has to have
a clean background.
Though you cut your ties with the Ngai
and used your mother's last name,
you still share the same father with Hau.
That means you violated conduct
by concealing your background.
I have to let you go.
But before you leave,
go see "Mr. Wrong Socks" first.
Still want to be a cop?
Can I still?
As long as you can give me a good reason.
I want to be a good person.
If you want to be a cop, then help me out.
You have no other choice.
You picked me
cause I'm Hau's brother, right?
When the time comes,
will you arrest him yourself?
How do I start?
Squat.
You okay?
Hanging in there?
What's wrong?
Does it still hurt?
My dad passed away today.
He was so good to me!
I asked the officer
if I could go to his funeral.
The officer said,
"Know what it means to be a prisoner?
It means you're not allowed
to even attend your father's funeral.
Don't you know that?
Get out of here!"
Come on. Stop that.
TIME
Are you nuts?
You sent Yan to be a mole?
Don't you know Hau's his half-brother?
So what?
Bring me his file.
So you're playing the boss now, huh?
You know damn well
the files are classified.
I treat you like a brother
and this is what I get?
If I am a brother to you,
you'd stop asking.
It's okay.
Calm down.
Talk it over.
She had an abortion!
That's no big deal. It's just a baby!
You can always have another one.
That's how it works!
I've been with you for four years,
and I've bailed you out tons of times.
One minute we're dining with my folks and
the next you're in a gang fight!
I don't want our baby to grow up like you.
Don't you understand?
Why're you looking so uptight?
I'm not.
Uncle John says you're doing well.
Ever thought about helping the family out?
I know you don't want others to know
your relations with the Ngais.
But we're blood brothers,
and that's a fact.
Right?
It's my daughter's birthday this Sunday.
You're invited.
You really hate talking to me, huh?
No.
Promoted already?
Soon you'll be a superintendent.
Might as well become a full-time cop.
Sam's joking with you. Go ahead, smile.
Thanks for your intel
these couple of years.
When you were still a rookie,
I helped you catch some small potatoes.
It's about time for you to catch
some big shots.
How about catching me?
Why so dirty here?
Or you can catch hot chicks!
What are you doing?
What a hot hoochie mama
Your man must be one good-looking bastard.
That man is you!
-Gotta go.
-Already?
Gotta work! I'm meeting Mr. Ngai.
Sam's so good to you.
But he's not good to himself.
It's been four years.
He could be in charge by now.
But he gave everything to the Ngais.
Now the Ngais are untouchable.
Hau will go after his father's killer
for sure.
These past four years...
I haven't been sleeping well.
Hello, I'm Inspector Wong Chi Shing.
Don't worry, Mary.
I won't let anything happen to you.
You better mean it.
Yes.
Toss it up!
Two days ago, a real estate agent came.
Guess how much he offered?
One hundred sixty million!
What's wrong with Hong Kong? Tell me.
When my dad bought it,
it was nine million and... 280,000.
What has this world come to?
Trading houses, Mr. Ngai?
1997 is approaching. Time to emigrate.
No big deal.
Communication's easy nowadays.
We're just a phone call away.
I'm just worried about the phone bill.
You know how greedy the phone company is.
I've discussed it with Mom.
Our businesses are on the right track.
And you guys have helped out
so much in the past.
So I don't want to be ungrateful.
I want to split the business up
among you guys.
You can treat it as a gift
or a retirement fund.
Let's eat! Help yourself!
We should hang out like this more often.
Mr. Ngai.
Are you leaving for real?
All hell will break loose
after you're gone.
Sam, you're a Buddhist, right?
"Easy to start. Hard to let go."
I'm letting go today.
You should be happy for me.
I've thought about it.
Cocaine will definitely be the future.
Those four ship it in small bags
from South America.
They're just small-timers.
I've closed a deal with the Thais.
You'll have a monopoly.
You'll be the top dog, leader of the pack.
Go to Thailand and wrap up the logistics.
You thinking' about getting rid
of those four?
Move closer to the centre, please.
Yan.
Come join the family portrait.
Stand next to me here.
All right. One more shot.
One, two, three!
One more!
I haven't been around much
these past two years.
It's rare to spend time
with the whole family like this.
Your siblings are
in legitimate businesses.
It's time you helped out the family.
Everything Dad did was for the family.
I did the same.
I hope you will too.
A deal's coming up next week.
Come with me.
I'll call you.
I think he's taking the deal seriously.
He'll go in person next Wednesday.
The 14th... Kwun's death anniversary.
Hau wants to whack the Big Four.
Why does he send Sam away?
Don't know. Sam should be of help to him.
Unless he wants to kill Sam too!
I've been following you around for days.
After all, I'm your superior.
I want to know what your plan is.
The Ngais are your family.
Do you really know what you're doing?
I'm a cop.
Good. Give me a salute.
I've booked a table for dinner.
Care to join?
Do I look cool in my cap?
Sit.
Check this out.
What'll you do in Thailand
with this outfit?
Have some shark fin soup,
a massage,
and get two hookers for a threesome.
That's for sure.
-Honey!
-What?
Why didn't you tell me
you're going to Thailand?
It's a business trip! Not for pleasure!
Don't worry. I'll behave.
Hau plans to whack Wah and those guys.
I know.
But do you know he wants to whack you too?
Nonsense! How can that be?
Just wait for me at the airport!
Time to board, Sam.
KAI TAK AIRPORT, HONG KONG
That's all I can do for now.
Call Sam again when the plane lands.
I'm going to kill Hau tonight.
Don't do anything rash.
I'm not being rash.
I only remember you told me
to kill Kwun four years ago.
So what? Are you blackmailing me?
I'm not blackmailing you.
It's just that we've both passed
the point of no return.
I'll send everybody away.
Tonight's operation must be kept secret.
We'll divide into three teams.
Team A watches here.
Team B, here.
You will not take action
until you get my order.
Team C follows the target until...
Why didn't you tell me
about the date change?
I've said it before.
Hau changes his mind all the time.
You think Yan's the only mole?
My man's been undercover for seven years.
Where's the deck of cards?
We'll run the show together tonight.
Let's go!
-Don't move!
-Hold it right there!
Well, Hau?
Zipping it till your lawyer gets here?
Come on, cooperate with us!
In fact, I appreciate your cooperation.
Are you speaking Zen, Mr. Ngai?
I don't get it.
Dad used to say,
"The way things work in the streets,
what goes around always comes around."
He died four years ago. It's about time.
The stove's hot enough now, boss!
She's here, boss.
You're here now.
What more can you do?
Wait and see.
We checked, boss.
The two foreigners are private eyes.
Honey!
Where are you?
Thailand, of course!
-Come back right away!
-Are you nuts? Why should I come back?
Don't ask! Just come back!
Hau wants you dead!
I'm working for him, silly!
Listen to me.
I'm the one who killed Kwun.
You've got a VCR?
Is it good?
It's very good.
Play it by ear. Run if you have to.
What did Hau say?
-Sam.
-Sunny!
I only remember you fold me
to kill Kwun four years ago.
So what? Are you blackmailing me?
I'm not blackmailing you.
It's just that we've both passed
the point of no return.
I'll send everybody away.
I hired Alan and Johnson
to investigate my father's murder.
Who could've guessed a police officer
would knowingly break the law
and murder a law-abiding citizen
like my father?
Superintendent Luk.
Isn't that a police officer in the video?
Whether to nab him or not,
that's up to you.
What a good show.
You were so photogenic.
Four years ago...
How much did Sam's woman pay you?
Give us another chance, Mr. Ngai!
I gave them a chance four years ago.
They didn't take it.
If I give you a chance today,
are you going to take it?
You've been with us for seven years now.
You're a cop.
And we're the triads.
Time to accept our fates.
You can't blame me.
Your Inspector Wong killed my dad.
Any word from Sam?
Sam called me. He said he was fine.
He asked you to hide out here
and wait for him.
Where are your folks?
All emigrated.
You didn't go with them?
Let's go, Sam! We got rid of the Thais.
Let's go!
You know you're not going to make it.
I know.
My woman's in danger in Hong Kong.
Please help me.
Why should I?
‘Cause I helped you whack your boss.
I know you want to be in charge.
And...
I've always treated you as a good friend.
Don't believe him, Sam! Don't!
Get lost!
-Don't believe him!
-Get lost!
I'm sorry, Sam.
Are you here to arrest me?
If you're going to kill Hau,
then I will.
Then there's nothing to talk about.
I've spoken with the higher ups.
They're with you all the way this time.
How? I instigated murder.
Even the Brits agree that...
we can't let the triads break us.
The whole department's behind you.
Good enough?
Where's your deck of cards?
Same, the highest point wins.
I'm calling the shots.
Come back with me to the station.
The car key.
Forget it. I screwed up.
No need to drag everyone down with me.
We found this deck
on our first raid together.
You've been keeping it all this time.
I knew that all along.
I've let you have your way
all these years.
It's your turn to listen to me for once.
We're like brothers.
Think I'm just gonna be a spectator?
Law's my snitch in the Ngai Family.
He hasn't contacted me for days.
And neither has Yan.
The key.
Get outta there!!
Help! Somebody get help!
Why did you lie to me?
I didn't.
Something happened to Sam.
I told you I was a simple woman.
I have to do something for my husband.
I'm going to Thailand.
Can you not go?
Forget it! Just treat it
as if you've never followed us.
I mean, I don't want you to go.
You've been with Sam for years.
Has it occurred to you...
-That maybe Sam's dead?
-What did you say?
I can take care of you.
-What are you doing?
-I don't want you to go.
You're out of line!
I'm telling you.
I'm your boss's woman.
Don't let me see your face again.
She will go to the airport tonight...
Hello? Hello?
I'm the one who killed Kwun.
I'd do anything
as long as a man treats me well.
TIME
File number 103142.
About Inspector Wong conspiring in murder.
This is the 11th internal hearing.
Inspector Wong, do you have any questions?
No...
No.
On April 11, 1995,
the Complaints and Internal Investigations
Branch received this videotape
accusing you of conspiring with the triads
in a murder.
I plead guilty, sir.
What happened to you?
If I told you...
that all the so-called evidence
couldn't stand,
would you like to start over?
I'm sorry.
I broke the law.
I'm grateful to all of you.
But I've got no confidence left.
I lost.
What about Luk, then?
Can you face him if you give up now?
The war's not over, Wong.
We all want closure to this incident.
We need to send a message that Hong Kong
is not run by the Ngai Family.
Here's a file from Interpol.
Read it before you make up your mind.
Ever been to a funeral in Thailand?
A few months ago,
I had one there for my wife.
The monks chanted
for three full days and nights.
I didn't shed a single tear.
But, on the day of the burial,
the pallbearers moved the casket
to the living room.
I was furious.
I wanted to beat them up.
The head monk said...
it's a tradition in Thailand.
The deceased...
as long as we keep her company...
for a little while longer...
she can then rest in eternal peace.
But then I asked the monk...
"My wife's not in the coffin.
Could she still rest in eternal peace?"
Sorry about your wife.
The monk placed his hand here.
He said, "Not a problem.
As long as your wife's here."
And here's exactly...
where the Thai shot me.
So I said to myself...
I've passed the point of no return.
Testifying against Hau in Hong Kong
could be dangerous.
You're so handsome.
I have confidence in you.
Haven't heard that for ages. Thanks.
What's your plan?
Just trying to do my best.
No big deal. It's my job.
I'll leave Hong Kong
when this is all over.
Wong.
You've changed!
Baby!
You diluted the coke, didn't you?
Got anything to say?
It's all yours then!
Don't go too far, Yan.
It might break the boys' morale.
Mr. Ngai asked me to be in charge here.
Don't like it?
Then take him to the hospital.
No matter what, they're still elders.
You've got a lot to learn from them.
Uncle John will retire in a few years.
You know what I mean?
I don't need any hiccups now.
The Labor Athletic Association
is hosting a dinner reception
for all the Political Consultative
candidates.
If everything works out,
our family will no longer live
in the shadows.
CELEBRATE THE HANDOVER
Mr. Cheung.
Mr. Ngai.
How are you?
When Solicitor Hung mentioned you,
I could hardly believe him.
You're so young and promising, Mr. Ngai.
What's your Zodiac sign?
-Ox.
-The Year of the Ox.
Ox is good.
Director Chan likes talking
with young people.
-I'll introduce you later.
-Thanks.
Really?
Director Chan told me
he hated the triads the most.
That's right, Superintendent Leung.
Mr. Ngai's been invited
to consult with the police.
Is that so? Congratulations!
Where do you golf these days, Chan?
-Zhongshan.
-Zhongshan? What's your handicap now?
How are you? My name's Ngai...
Mr. Ngai Wing-hau!
I'm Mr. Ngai's attorney.
This is a LAA reception
celebrating the handover.
Can we discuss this afterwards?
What if I say no?
Got any problem with that?
Mr. Ngai, we suspect you're related to
several murder cases in 1995.
Here's a warrant.
You're under arrest.
Everything you say will be recorded
and could be used as evidence against you.
Do you have any questions?
No.
I've looked through their charges.
The murder ones won't stick.
But your being a triad "Dragon Head"...
I can't help you with that.
The unions
and the political parties called.
They want to withdraw their invitations.
That was the HK and Macau Affairs Office.
-They have revoked your candidacy.
-Call Beijing.
-Get some friends to help.
-Let me try.
Forget it.
They even found a dead man
to testify against you.
Everyone knows how loyal Sam was to you.
Now he's a prosecution witness. It's over.
Sorry. Can't help you.
You said everything would be fine!
Everyone's watching how we will react.
What are you going to do?
What can I do?
Threaten the Chinese government?
That's not what he meant.
-We're all in the same boat.
-Time for me to get off then.
I may be your lawyer,
but I'm not one of you.
I don't wish to sink with you. Sorry.
Yes.
Sam has a wife and daughter in Thailand.
It's your call.
Sis.
You and the brothers should take Mom
and go to Hawaii for a while.
-Okay.
-Sure. Haven't been there for a while.
-Are you going to be all right?
-I'll be fine.
Sorry I can't help the family.
-You being OK is all that matters.
-Don't be silly. We're a family.
Take care of Mom.
Don't worry. Leave it to us three.
I kept thinking that,
even with my testimony,
Hau will only get a couple years.
True.
He'll have to whack you to get life.
I have to thank you.
Without you, I could never have
come back to Hong Kong.
Save it. I'm busy these days.
Anything you need, ask them.
They're here to protect you.
Sam?
Thanks.
So, how's it going?
Good, now that
I've been transferred to CIB.
I'll be an Inspector-in-Training
next month.
Did Mary call you...
before she died?
My condolences, Sam.
Inspector Wong said to find you
if I needed anything.
Will you really help me?
I thought you wouldn't come.
Why wouldn't 1?
Well?
It's been two years.
You didn't dare to call me for two years
because of my father's death?
You couldn't face me?
Right.
All of Hau's criminal evidence
is in the safe deposit box.
I've organised the files
according to dates.
Why are you still helping me?
I'm not helping you.
I'm a cop.
I want to keep my promises to Officer Luk.
And I don't want to be a mole anymore.
Two more years, and I'll become
the top dog in Tsim Sha Tsui.
What for? To end up in prison?
I'll forget the past.
Just finish this case soon
and bring me back into the department.
And give me a nice desk.
Make sure it has an ocean view.
But don't let me see your face ever again.
Don't worry. You won't see me anymore.
One more thing.
I couldn't spell some of the words.
Come find me if you don't understand.
But don't mess up the order.
Took me forever.
I'll kill you if you do.
That'll be good. Put me out of misery.
You wish.
Thank you, Officer.
Sam? All set. The DOJ has scheduled
three days for the trial.
Mr. Hon...
Hello, OCTB.
Inspector Wong! Sam's disappeared.
He probably escaped through the kitchen.
Who was guarding the kitchen?
Sorry, sir.
Sir, Sam had made a call to Thailand
before he escaped.
Hello?
Mr. Ngai.
How can I help you?
You called me.
So you tell me how you can help me.
Am I right? Sit down.
Kill me.
Kill me, and everything's taken care of.
Why should 1?
Haven't done that kind of stuff for ages.
Everything can be negotiated, Sam.
Hong Kong's big enough for us both.
We can be partners if you want.
Let's forget about the past.
You will kill me.
You'll kill me tonight.
Then who's gonna take care of your family?
This just in.
Hau has Sam's wife and daughter
as hostages.
That woman is his Thai maid.
I managed to stay alive all these years.
It's all because...
I have some good buddies in Thailand.
You want to take this call.
It's from Hawaii.
Your whole family's there.
My Thai buddies too.
Daddy? Where are you?
Mr. Ngai!
Shut up.
I told you. You'll kill me tonight.
Ngai Wing-hau! Drop the gun!
Let him, Wong!
He tried to kill me once before.
Let him do it again!
Officers!
Once he shoots me...
It's up to you to shoot him or not!
"What goes around comes around."
Two questions.
Did you Kill his whole family?
Of course not.
My Thai friends and I were just bluffing.
Did you expect me to kill him for you?
If I said no, would you believe me?
I expected to die here!
It was my only way.
Sorry.
Did you know how much time I spent
collecting tons of evidence?
Enough to put him away for life?
Hello, who's this?
It's the Thai guy, Sam.
Paul?
Thank you.
It's all good.
From now on, we're partners.
The shipment will go
straight to Hong Kong.
The rest of the Ngai family...
Should I take care of them?
Paul...
Perhaps... we shouldn't go too far.
You're lucky to be alive
when you bumped into me.
We were destined to be partners
when my shot didn't kill you.
There's no such thing as going too far.
The handover ceremony of Hong Kong
at the new convention centre
officially commenced at 11.20.
Both countries' military bands played
the respective anthems,
as the British Union Jack flag
was gradually raised.
While the ceremony was solemn,
the atmosphere was harmonious
before it began.
During the playing of
the two military bands,
a few Chinese representatives
Started taking pictures.
Both Prince Charles and Governor Patten
were smiling as they entered the hall.
The ceremony now officially begins.
Three British soldiers
and three flag-holding
Chinese PLA soldiers
march slowly onto the podium.
The People's Liberation Army present
the People's Republic of China flag
of the MCs.
Following them are,
three HK Royal Police officers,
together with three HK SAR police officers
as they all approach the podium.
The three SAR officers present
the HKSAR flag to the MCs.
All the guests are now
rising from their seats.
July 1st has now arrived
as the clock strikes midnight.
The PRC flag slowly rises
together with the HKSAR flag...
This marks the end of the colonial rule.
It also raises the curtains to the
historic "One Country, Two Systems" era.
The Hong Kong
Special Administrative Region
of the People's Republic of China
is now officially established.
It's okay. It's a done deal.
Come join me.
You know what kind of boss is the worst?
The ugly kind!
Looks are important!
See how my greasy face glows?
What's your name, miss?
Name...?
I'm Ma... Mary.
I think so...
CONTINUOUS HELL EMBODIES
3 COMPONENTS:
UNINTERRUPTED TIME, UNLIMITED
SPACE, BOUNDLESS SUFFERING
TRANSGRESSORS OF THE FIVE DEADLY
SINS FALL INTO THIS HELL FOREVER
CONDEMNED TO THE ULTIMATE
INCESSANT SUFFERING